0	PERSON	0	0	NNP	Klein
0	O	1	0	,	,
0	O	2	0	NNP	A.M.
0	O	3	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
0	O	4	0	CD	1909-1972
0	O	5	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
0	O	6	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
0	O	7	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
0	PERSON	8	0	NNP	Abraham/Moses/KleinA.M
0	O	9	0	.	.

8 0 hasAlias

1	O	0	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
1	PERSON	1	0	NNP	Abraham/Moses/-RRB-/Klein
1	O	2	0	VBD	was
1	O	3	0	DT	a
1	MISC	4	0	JJ	Canadian
1	O	5	0	JJ	modernist
1	O	6	0	RB	best
1	O	7	0	VBN	known
1	O	8	0	IN	for
1	O	9	0	PRP$	his
1	O	10	0	NN	poetry
1	O	11	0	VBG	depicting
1	MISC	12	0	JJ	Jewish
1	O	13	0	CC	and
1	MISC	14	0	JJ	French/Canadian
1	O	15	0	NNS	experiences
1	O	16	0	IN	in
1	O	17	0	DT	the
1	O	18	0	JJ	first
1	O	19	0	NN	half
1	O	20	0	IN	of
1	O	21	0	DT	the
1	O	22	0	JJ	twentieth
1	O	23	0	NN	century
1	O	24	0	.	.

1 4 hasEthnicity

2	O	0	0	DT	A
2	O	1	0	JJ	central
2	O	2	0	NN	figure
2	O	3	0	IN	in
2	MISC	4	0	JJ	Jewish-Canadian
2	O	5	0	NN	culture
2	O	6	0	,	,
2	O	7	0	JJ	many
2	O	8	0	IN	of
2	O	9	0	PRP$	his
2	O	10	0	NNS	poems
2	O	11	0	VBP	represent
2	MISC	12	0	JJ	Jewish
2	O	13	0	NN	identity
2	O	14	0	CC	and
2	O	15	0	NN	heritage
2	O	16	0	,	,
2	O	17	0	NNS	themes
2	O	18	0	PRP	he
2	O	19	0	VBD	sought
2	O	20	0	TO	to
2	O	21	0	VB	reconcile
2	O	22	0	IN	with
2	O	23	0	DT	a
2	O	24	0	JJ	modernist
2	O	25	0	NN	desire
2	O	26	0	TO	to
2	O	27	0	VB	break
2	O	28	0	IN	from
2	O	29	0	NN	history
2	O	30	0	.	.

3	PERSON	0	0	NNP	Klein
3	O	1	0	RB	also
3	O	2	0	VBD	wrote
3	O	3	0	JJ	short
3	O	4	0	NNS	stories
3	O	5	0	,	,
3	O	6	0	NNS	novels
3	O	7	0	,	,
3	O	8	0	CC	and
3	O	9	0	JJ	literary
3	O	10	0	NNS	essays
3	O	11	0	,	,
3	O	12	0	VBG	including
3	O	13	0	JJ	several
3	O	14	0	IN	on
3	PERSON	15	0	NNP	James/Joyce
3	O	16	0	POS	's
3	PERSON	17	0	NNP	Ulysses
3	O	18	0	,	,
3	O	19	0	IN	besides
3	O	20	0	VBG	practicing
3	O	21	0	IN	as
3	O	22	0	DT	a
3	O	23	0	NN	lawyer.Klein
3	O	24	0	VBD	was
3	O	25	0	VBN	born
3	O	26	0	IN	on
3	O	27	0	NNP	February
3	O	28	0	CD	14
3	O	29	0	,	,
3	O	30	0	CD	1909
3	O	31	0	IN	in
3	LOCATION	32	0	NNP	Ratno
3	O	33	0	,	,
3	LOCATION	34	0	NNP	Ukraine
3	O	35	0	.	.

0 15 inspiredBy
0 17 inspiredBy


4	O	0	0	IN	As
4	O	1	0	DT	a
4	O	2	0	JJ	young
4	O	3	0	NN	child
4	O	4	0	PRP$	his
4	O	5	0	NN	family
4	O	6	0	VBD	immigrated
4	O	7	0	TO	to
4	ORGANIZATION	8	0	NNP	Montreal
4	O	9	0	POS	's
4	O	10	0	JJ	working-class
4	MISC	11	0	JJ	Jewish
4	O	12	0	NN	district
4	O	13	0	,	,
4	O	14	0	DT	a
4	O	15	0	NN	setting
4	O	16	0	WDT	that
4	O	17	0	VBD	inspired
4	O	18	0	JJ	much
4	O	19	0	IN	of
4	O	20	0	PRP$	his
4	O	21	0	JJ	later
4	O	22	0	NN	poetry
4	O	23	0	.	.

5	O	0	0	IN	From
5	O	1	0	CD	1926
5	O	2	0	TO	to
5	O	3	0	CD	1930
5	O	4	0	,	,
5	PERSON	5	0	NNP	Klein
5	O	6	0	VBD	studied
5	O	7	0	IN	at
5	ORGANIZATION	8	0	NNP	McGill/University
5	O	9	0	,	,
5	O	10	0	WRB	where
5	O	11	0	PRP	he
5	O	12	0	VBD	was
5	O	13	0	VBN	influenced
5	O	14	0	IN	by
5	O	15	0	DT	the
5	ORGANIZATION	16	0	NNP	McGill/Movement
5	O	17	0	,	,
5	O	18	0	DT	a
5	O	19	0	JJ	modernist
5	O	20	0	JJ	literary
5	O	21	0	NN	circle
5	O	22	0	VBN	founded
5	O	23	0	IN	by
5	PERSON	24	0	NNP	A.J.M/Smith
5	O	25	0	,	,
5	PERSON	26	0	NNP	F.R./Scott
5	O	27	0	,	,
5	O	28	0	CC	and
5	PERSON	29	0	NNP	Leo/Kennedy
5	O	30	0	.	.

6	O	0	0	IN	While
6	O	1	0	DT	a
6	O	2	0	NN	student
6	O	3	0	IN	at
6	ORGANIZATION	4	0	NNP	McGill
6	O	5	0	,	,
6	PERSON	6	0	NNP	Klein
6	O	7	0	VBD	published
6	O	8	0	NNS	works
6	O	9	0	IN	in
6	O	10	0	JJ	several
6	O	11	0	NNS	magazines
6	O	12	0	CC	and
6	O	13	0	VBD	co-founded
6	O	14	0	DT	the
6	O	15	0	JJ	literary
6	O	16	0	NN	magazine
6	ORGANIZATION	17	0	NNP	McGilliad
6	O	18	0	.	.

7	O	0	0	DT	A
7	O	1	0	NN	lawyer
7	O	2	0	IN	by
7	O	3	0	NN	profession
7	O	4	0	,	,
7	PERSON	5	0	NNP	Klein
7	O	6	0	VBD	went
7	O	7	0	IN	on
7	O	8	0	TO	to
7	O	9	0	VB	study
7	O	10	0	NN	law
7	O	11	0	IN	at
7	O	12	0	DT	the
7	ORGANIZATION	13	0	NNP	Université/de/Montréal
7	O	14	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
7	O	15	0	CD	1930-1933
7	O	16	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
7	O	17	0	IN	after
7	O	18	0	VBG	graduating
7	O	19	0	IN	from
7	ORGANIZATION	20	0	NNP	McGill
7	O	21	0	.	.

8	O	0	0	IN	In
8	O	1	0	CD	1928
8	PERSON	2	0	NNP	Klein
8	O	3	0	VBD	became
8	O	4	0	VBN	involved
8	O	5	0	IN	with
8	O	6	0	DT	the
8	MISC	7	0	NNP	Zionist
8	O	8	0	NN	organization
8	PERSON	9	0	NN	Canadian/Young/Judaea
8	O	10	0	IN	as
8	O	11	0	DT	an
8	O	12	0	NN	educator
8	O	13	0	CC	and
8	O	14	0	NN	writer
8	O	15	0	.	.

9	O	0	0	RB	Later
9	O	1	0	PRP	he
9	O	2	0	VBD	wrote
9	O	3	0	IN	for
9	O	4	0	CC	and
9	O	5	0	VBD	edited
9	O	6	0	DT	the
9	ORGANIZATION	7	0	NNP	Zionist/Organization/of/Canada
9	O	8	0	POS	's
9	O	9	0	NN	magazine
9	O	10	0	,	,
9	O	11	0	DT	The
9	MISC	12	0	NN	Canadian/Zionist
9	O	13	0	,	,
9	O	14	0	CC	and
9	O	15	0	DT	The
9	MISC	16	0	NNP	Canadian/Jewish/Chronicle
9	O	17	0	.	.

11	O	0	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
11	PERSON	1	0	NNP	Abraham/Moses/-RRB-/Klein
11	O	2	0	VBD	was
11	O	3	0	DT	a
11	MISC	4	0	JJ	Canadian
11	O	5	0	JJ	modernist
11	O	6	0	RB	best
11	O	7	0	VBN	known
11	O	8	0	IN	for
11	O	9	0	PRP$	his
11	O	10	0	NN	poetry
11	O	11	0	VBG	depicting
11	MISC	12	0	JJ	Jewish
11	O	13	0	CC	and
11	MISC	14	0	JJ	French/Canadian
11	O	15	0	NNS	experiences
11	O	16	0	IN	in
11	O	17	0	DT	the
11	O	18	0	JJ	first
11	O	19	0	NN	half
11	O	20	0	IN	of
11	O	21	0	DT	the
11	O	22	0	JJ	twentieth
11	O	23	0	NN	century
11	O	24	0	.	.

12	O	0	0	DT	A
12	O	1	0	JJ	central
12	O	2	0	NN	figure
12	O	3	0	IN	in
12	MISC	4	0	JJ	Jewish-Canadian
12	O	5	0	NN	culture
12	O	6	0	,	,
12	O	7	0	JJ	many
12	O	8	0	IN	of
12	O	9	0	PRP$	his
12	O	10	0	NNS	poems
12	O	11	0	VBP	represent
12	MISC	12	0	JJ	Jewish
12	O	13	0	NN	identity
12	O	14	0	CC	and
12	O	15	0	NN	heritage
12	O	16	0	,	,
12	O	17	0	NNS	themes
12	O	18	0	PRP	he
12	O	19	0	VBD	sought
12	O	20	0	TO	to
12	O	21	0	VB	reconcile
12	O	22	0	IN	with
12	O	23	0	DT	a
12	O	24	0	JJ	modernist
12	O	25	0	NN	desire
12	O	26	0	TO	to
12	O	27	0	VB	break
12	O	28	0	IN	from
12	O	29	0	NN	history
12	O	30	0	.	.

13	PERSON	0	0	NNP	Klein
13	O	1	0	RB	also
13	O	2	0	VBD	wrote
13	O	3	0	JJ	short
13	O	4	0	NNS	stories
13	O	5	0	,	,
13	O	6	0	NNS	novels
13	O	7	0	,	,
13	O	8	0	CC	and
13	O	9	0	JJ	literary
13	O	10	0	NNS	essays
13	O	11	0	,	,
13	O	12	0	VBG	including
13	O	13	0	JJ	several
13	O	14	0	IN	on
13	PERSON	15	0	NNP	James/Joyce
13	O	16	0	POS	's
13	PERSON	17	0	NNP	Ulysses
13	O	18	0	,	,
13	O	19	0	IN	besides
13	O	20	0	VBG	practicing
13	O	21	0	IN	as
13	O	22	0	DT	a
13	O	23	0	NN	lawyer.Klein
13	O	24	0	VBD	was
13	O	25	0	VBN	born
13	O	26	0	IN	on
13	O	27	0	NNP	February
13	O	28	0	CD	14
13	O	29	0	,	,
13	O	30	0	CD	1909
13	O	31	0	IN	in
13	LOCATION	32	0	NNP	Ratno
13	O	33	0	,	,
13	LOCATION	34	0	NNP	Ukraine
13	O	35	0	.	.

14	O	0	0	IN	As
14	O	1	0	DT	a
14	O	2	0	JJ	young
14	O	3	0	NN	child
14	O	4	0	PRP$	his
14	O	5	0	NN	family
14	O	6	0	VBD	immigrated
14	O	7	0	TO	to
14	ORGANIZATION	8	0	NNP	Montreal
14	O	9	0	POS	's
14	O	10	0	JJ	working-class
14	MISC	11	0	JJ	Jewish
14	O	12	0	NN	district
14	O	13	0	,	,
14	O	14	0	DT	a
14	O	15	0	NN	setting
14	O	16	0	WDT	that
14	O	17	0	VBD	inspired
14	O	18	0	JJ	much
14	O	19	0	IN	of
14	O	20	0	PRP$	his
14	O	21	0	JJ	later
14	O	22	0	NN	poetry
14	O	23	0	.	.

15	O	0	0	IN	From
15	O	1	0	CD	1926
15	O	2	0	TO	to
15	O	3	0	CD	1930
15	O	4	0	,	,
15	PERSON	5	0	NNP	Klein
15	O	6	0	VBD	studied
15	O	7	0	IN	at
15	ORGANIZATION	8	0	NNP	McGill/University
15	O	9	0	,	,
15	O	10	0	WRB	where
15	O	11	0	PRP	he
15	O	12	0	VBD	was
15	O	13	0	VBN	influenced
15	O	14	0	IN	by
15	O	15	0	DT	the
15	ORGANIZATION	16	0	NNP	McGill/Movement
15	O	17	0	,	,
15	O	18	0	DT	a
15	O	19	0	JJ	modernist
15	O	20	0	JJ	literary
15	O	21	0	NN	circle
15	O	22	0	VBN	founded
15	O	23	0	IN	by
15	PERSON	24	0	NNP	A.J.M/Smith
15	O	25	0	,	,
15	PERSON	26	0	NNP	F.R./Scott
15	O	27	0	,	,
15	O	28	0	CC	and
15	PERSON	29	0	NNP	Leo/Kennedy
15	O	30	0	.	.

16	O	0	0	IN	While
16	O	1	0	DT	a
16	O	2	0	NN	student
16	O	3	0	IN	at
16	ORGANIZATION	4	0	NNP	McGill
16	O	5	0	,	,
16	PERSON	6	0	NNP	Klein
16	O	7	0	VBD	published
16	O	8	0	NNS	works
16	O	9	0	IN	in
16	O	10	0	JJ	several
16	O	11	0	NNS	magazines
16	O	12	0	CC	and
16	O	13	0	VBD	co-founded
16	O	14	0	DT	the
16	O	15	0	JJ	literary
16	O	16	0	NN	magazine
16	ORGANIZATION	17	0	NNP	McGilliad
16	O	18	0	.	.

17	O	0	0	DT	A
17	O	1	0	NN	lawyer
17	O	2	0	IN	by
17	O	3	0	NN	profession
17	O	4	0	,	,
17	PERSON	5	0	NNP	Klein
17	O	6	0	VBD	went
17	O	7	0	IN	on
17	O	8	0	TO	to
17	O	9	0	VB	study
17	O	10	0	NN	law
17	O	11	0	IN	at
17	O	12	0	DT	the
17	ORGANIZATION	13	0	NNP	Université/de/Montréal
17	O	14	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
17	O	15	0	CD	1930-1933
17	O	16	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
17	O	17	0	IN	after
17	O	18	0	VBG	graduating
17	O	19	0	IN	from
17	ORGANIZATION	20	0	NNP	McGill
17	O	21	0	.	.

18	O	0	0	IN	In
18	O	1	0	CD	1928
18	PERSON	2	0	NNP	Klein
18	O	3	0	VBD	became
18	O	4	0	VBN	involved
18	O	5	0	IN	with
18	O	6	0	DT	the
18	MISC	7	0	NNP	Zionist
18	O	8	0	NN	organization
18	PERSON	9	0	NN	Canadian/Young/Judaea
18	O	10	0	IN	as
18	O	11	0	DT	an
18	O	12	0	NN	educator
18	O	13	0	CC	and
18	O	14	0	NN	writer
18	O	15	0	.	.

19	O	0	0	RB	Later
19	O	1	0	PRP	he
19	O	2	0	VBD	wrote
19	O	3	0	IN	for
19	O	4	0	CC	and
19	O	5	0	VBD	edited
19	O	6	0	DT	the
19	ORGANIZATION	7	0	NNP	Zionist/Organization/of/Canada
19	O	8	0	POS	's
19	O	9	0	NN	magazine
19	O	10	0	,	,
19	O	11	0	DT	The
19	MISC	12	0	NN	Canadian/Zionist
19	O	13	0	,	,
19	O	14	0	CC	and
19	O	15	0	DT	The
19	MISC	16	0	NNP	Canadian/Jewish/Chronicle
19	O	17	0	.	.

20	O	0	0	PRP	He
20	O	1	0	RB	also
20	O	2	0	VBD	worked
20	O	3	0	IN	as
20	O	4	0	DT	a
20	O	5	0	NN	speechwriter
20	O	6	0	IN	for
20	PERSON	7	0	NNP	Samuel/Bronfman
20	O	8	0	,	,
20	O	9	0	NNP	President
20	O	10	0	IN	of
20	O	11	0	DT	the
20	MISC	12	0	JJ	Canadian/Jewish
20	O	13	0	NN	Congress.Klein
20	O	14	0	POS	's
20	O	15	0	JJ	first
20	O	16	0	NN	book
20	O	17	0	IN	of
20	O	18	0	NN	poetry
20	O	19	0	,	,
20	O	20	0	NNP	Hath
20	O	21	0	RB	Not
20	O	22	0	DT	a
20	O	23	0	NN	Jew
20	O	24	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
20	O	25	0	CD	1940
20	O	26	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
20	O	27	0	,	,
20	O	28	0	VBZ	contains
20	O	29	0	NNS	poems
20	O	30	0	IN	from
20	O	31	0	DT	the
20	O	32	0	CD	1920s
20	O	33	0	CC	and
20	O	34	0	CD	1930s
20	O	35	0	VBG	addressing
20	O	36	0	PRP$	his
20	MISC	37	0	JJ	Jewish
20	O	38	0	NN	community
20	O	39	0	POS	's
20	O	40	0	NN	culture
20	O	41	0	CC	and
20	O	42	0	NN	experience
20	O	43	0	IN	of
20	MISC	44	0	NN	anti-Semitism
20	O	45	0	.	.

21	O	0	0	IN	In
21	O	1	0	DT	the
21	O	2	0	NNS	1940s
21	O	3	0	,	,
21	PERSON	4	0	NNP	Klein
21	O	5	0	VBN	associated
21	O	6	0	IN	with
21	O	7	0	NNS	poets
21	O	8	0	IN	in
21	O	9	0	DT	the
21	LOCATION	10	0	NNP	Montreal
21	O	11	0	VBN	based
21	O	12	0	NNP	Preview
21	O	13	0	NNP	Group
21	O	14	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
21	PERSON	15	0	NNP	F./R./Scott
21	O	16	0	,	,
21	PERSON	17	0	NNP	P.K./Page
21	O	18	0	,	,
21	O	19	0	CC	and
21	PERSON	20	0	NNP	Patrick/Anderson
21	O	21	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
21	O	22	0	CC	and
21	O	23	0	DT	the
21	ORGANIZATION	24	0	NNP	First/Statement/Group
21	O	25	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
21	O	26	0	VBG	including
21	PERSON	27	0	NNP	Irving/Layton
21	O	28	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
21	O	29	0	:	;
21	PERSON	30	0	NNP	Klein
21	O	31	0	RB	also
21	O	32	0	VBD	lectured
21	O	33	0	IN	in
21	O	34	0	NN	poetry
21	O	35	0	IN	at
21	ORGANIZATION	36	0	NNP	McGill/University
21	O	37	0	.	.

22	O	0	0	IN	In
22	O	1	0	CD	1944
22	O	2	0	,	,
22	LOCATION	3	0	NNP	The/Hitleriad
22	O	4	0	,	,
22	O	5	0	DT	a
22	O	6	0	JJ	satirical
22	O	7	0	NN	poem
22	O	8	0	IN	about
22	LOCATION	9	0	NNP	Nazi/Germany
22	O	10	0	POS	's
22	O	11	0	NN	threat
22	O	12	0	TO	to
22	MISC	13	0	NNPS	European/Jews
22	O	14	0	,	,
22	O	15	0	CC	and
22	O	16	0	NNS	Poems
22	O	17	0	VBD	were
22	O	18	0	VBN	published
22	O	19	0	.	.

23	O	0	0	VBG	Shifting
23	O	1	0	PRP$	his
23	O	2	0	NN	focus
23	O	3	0	IN	from
23	MISC	4	0	JJ	Jewish
23	O	5	0	NN	culture
23	O	6	0	,	,
23	PERSON	7	0	NNP	Klein
23	O	8	0	VBD	wrote
23	O	9	0	PRP$	his
23	O	10	0	JJ	first
23	O	11	0	JJ	unpublished
23	O	12	0	NN	novel
23	O	13	0	IN	in
23	O	14	0	CD	1946
23	O	15	0	,	,
23	ORGANIZATION	16	0	NN	Comes/the/Revolution
23	O	17	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	18	0	VBD	retitled
23	ORGANIZATION	19	0	IN	That/Walks/Like
23	O	20	0	DT	a
23	O	21	0	NN	Man
23	O	22	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	O	23	0	,	,
23	O	24	0	VBN	inspired
23	O	25	0	IN	by
23	O	26	0	DT	the
23	PERSON	27	0	NNP	Igor/Gouzenko
23	O	28	0	NN	affair
23	O	29	0	IN	of
23	MISC	30	0	JJ	Soviet
23	O	31	0	NN	espionage
23	O	32	0	IN	in
23	LOCATION	33	0	NNP	Canada
23	O	34	0	.	.

24	PERSON	0	0	NNP	Klein
24	O	1	0	POS	's
24	O	2	0	JJ	next
24	O	3	0	NN	volume
24	O	4	0	IN	of
24	O	5	0	NN	poetry
24	O	6	0	,	,
24	ORGANIZATION	7	0	NNS	The/Rocking/Chair/and/Other/Poems
24	O	8	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
24	O	9	0	CD	1948
24	O	10	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
24	O	11	0	,	,
24	O	12	0	VBN	depicted
24	LOCATION	13	0	NNP	Quebec
24	O	14	0	POS	's
24	MISC	15	0	JJ	French-Canadian
24	O	16	0	NN	community
24	O	17	0	CC	and
24	O	18	0	VBD	won
24	O	19	0	DT	the
24	O	20	0	NNP	Governor-General
24	O	21	0	POS	's
24	O	22	0	NN	Medal
24	O	23	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
24	O	24	0	CD	1949
24	O	25	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
24	O	26	0	.	.

25	O	0	0	VBN	Involved
25	O	1	0	IN	in
25	O	2	0	NNS	politics
25	O	3	0	,	,
25	PERSON	4	0	NNP	Klein
25	O	5	0	VBD	was
25	O	6	0	VBN	nominated
25	O	7	0	IN	in
25	O	8	0	CD	1944
25	O	9	0	IN	as
25	O	10	0	DT	the
25	O	11	0	JJ	Co-operative
25	ORGANIZATION	12	0	NNP	Commonwealth/Federation
25	O	13	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
25	ORGANIZATION	14	0	NNP	CCF
25	O	15	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
25	O	16	0	NN	candidate
25	O	17	0	IN	in
25	LOCATION	18	0	NNP	Montreal-Cartier
25	O	19	0	,	,
25	LOCATION	20	0	NNP	Quebec
25	O	21	0	.	.

26	O	0	0	PRP	He
26	O	1	0	VBD	withdrew
26	O	2	0	IN	from
26	O	3	0	DT	the
26	O	4	0	CD	1944
26	O	5	0	NN	race
26	O	6	0	,	,
26	O	7	0	CC	and
26	O	8	0	RB	later
26	O	9	0	VBD	ran
26	O	10	0	RB	unsuccessfully
26	O	11	0	IN	for
26	O	12	0	DT	the
26	O	13	0	NN	position
26	O	14	0	IN	in
26	O	15	0	CD	1949
26	O	16	0	.	.

27	O	0	0	DT	That
27	O	1	0	NN	year
27	O	2	0	,	,
27	O	3	0	RB	however
27	O	4	0	,	,
27	O	5	0	DT	the
27	ORGANIZATION	6	0	NNP	Canadian/Jewish/Congress
27	O	7	0	VBD	sponsored
27	PERSON	8	0	NNP	Klein
27	O	9	0	POS	's
27	O	10	0	NNS	travels
27	O	11	0	TO	to
27	LOCATION	12	0	NNP	Israel
27	O	13	0	,	,
27	LOCATION	14	0	NNP	Europe
27	O	15	0	,	,
27	O	16	0	CC	and
27	LOCATION	17	0	NNP	North/Africa
27	O	18	0	,	,
27	O	19	0	CC	and
27	O	20	0	IN	over
27	O	21	0	DT	the
27	O	22	0	JJ	next
27	O	23	0	CD	three
27	O	24	0	NNS	years
27	O	25	0	PRP	he
27	O	26	0	VBD	lectured
27	O	27	0	IN	on
27	O	28	0	DT	the
27	ORGANIZATION	29	0	NNP	State/of/Israel
27	O	30	0	IN	throughout
27	LOCATION	31	0	NNP	Canada
27	O	32	0	CC	and
27	LOCATION	33	0	NNP	America
27	O	34	0	.	.

28	O	0	0	PRP	He
28	O	1	0	VBD	described
28	O	2	0	PRP$	his
28	O	3	0	JJ	early
28	O	4	0	NNS	travels
28	O	5	0	IN	in
28	O	6	0	``	`
28	O	7	0	NNP	Notebook
28	O	8	0	IN	of
28	O	9	0	DT	a
28	O	10	0	NN	Journey
28	O	11	0	,	,
28	O	12	0	''	'
28	O	13	0	VBN	published
28	O	14	0	IN	in
28	O	15	0	DT	The
28	MISC	16	0	NNP	Canadian/Jewish/Chronicle
28	O	17	0	.	.

29	O	0	0	VBN	Inspired
29	O	1	0	IN	by
29	O	2	0	PRP$	his
29	O	3	0	NN	visit
29	LOCATION	4	0	NNP	Israel
29	O	5	0	CC	and
29	O	6	0	VBG	witnessing
29	MISC	7	0	JJ	European
29	O	8	0	CC	and
29	MISC	9	0	JJ	North/African
29	O	10	0	NN	refugee
29	O	11	0	NNS	camps
29	O	12	0	IN	at
29	O	13	0	DT	the
29	O	14	0	NN	end
29	O	15	0	IN	of
29	MISC	16	0	CD	World/War/Two
29	O	17	0	,	,
29	PERSON	18	0	NNP	Klein
29	O	19	0	POS	's
29	O	20	0	JJ	only
29	O	21	0	VBN	published
29	O	22	0	NN	novel
29	O	23	0	,	,
29	O	24	0	DT	The
29	PERSON	25	0	NN	Second/Scroll
29	O	26	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
29	O	27	0	CD	1951
29	O	28	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
29	O	29	0	,	,
29	O	30	0	VBZ	recounts
29	O	31	0	DT	a
29	O	32	0	JJ	contemporary
29	O	33	0	NN	search
29	O	34	0	IN	for
29	O	35	0	DT	a
29	ORGANIZATION	36	0	NNP	Messiah
29	O	37	0	TO	to
29	O	38	0	VB	guide
29	O	39	0	DT	the
29	MISC	40	0	NNPS	Jews
29	O	41	0	TO	to
29	O	42	0	DT	the
29	O	43	0	VBN	Promised
29	O	44	0	NN	Land.Klein
29	O	45	0	VBD	became
29	O	46	0	JJ	depressed
29	O	47	0	IN	while
29	O	48	0	VBG	writing
29	O	49	0	DT	The
29	MISC	50	0	NN	Second/Scroll
29	O	51	0	CC	and
29	O	52	0	VBD	attempted
29	O	53	0	NN	suicide
29	O	54	0	IN	in
29	O	55	0	CD	1954
29	O	56	0	.	.

30	O	0	0	PRP	He
30	O	1	0	RB	soon
30	O	2	0	VBD	ceased
30	O	3	0	NN	writing
30	O	4	0	CC	and
30	O	5	0	VBD	withdrew
30	O	6	0	IN	from
30	O	7	0	JJ	public
30	O	8	0	NN	life
30	O	9	0	,	,
30	O	10	0	VBG	including
30	O	11	0	VBG	resigning
30	O	12	0	IN	from
30	O	13	0	VBG	practicing
30	O	14	0	NN	law
30	O	15	0	IN	in
30	O	16	0	CD	1956
30	O	17	0	.	.

31	O	0	0	IN	On
31	O	1	0	NNP	August
31	O	2	0	CD	20
31	O	3	0	,	,
31	O	4	0	CD	1972
31	O	5	0	,	,
31	PERSON	6	0	NNP	Klein
31	O	7	0	VBD	died
31	O	8	0	IN	in
31	O	9	0	PRP$	his
31	O	10	0	NN	sleep
31	O	11	0	.	.

32	O	0	0	JJ	Several
32	O	1	0	IN	of
32	O	2	0	PRP$	his
32	O	3	0	JJ	short
32	O	4	0	NNS	stories
32	O	5	0	CC	and
32	O	6	0	NNS	poems
32	O	7	0	VBD	were
32	O	8	0	VBN	published
32	O	9	0	RB	posthumously
32	O	10	0	.	.

33	O	0	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
33	O	1	0	NN	File
33	O	2	0	:	:
33	O	3	0	NN	A.M.Klein.jpg
33	O	4	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
33	O	5	0	NN	Figure
33	O	6	0	CD	1
33	PERSON	7	0	NNP	A./M./KleinSource
33	O	8	0	:	:
33	O	9	0	NN	http://www.collectionscanada.gc.ca/pam_archives/public_mikan/index.php?fuseaction=genitem.displayItem&lang=eng&rec_nbr=3217809&rec_nbr_list=3217809[kleinscroll.jpg]Figure
33	O	10	0	CD	2
33	O	11	0	NNP	Group
33	O	12	0	NN	portrait
33	O	13	0	IN	of
33	O	14	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
33	O	15	0	NN	l
33	O	16	0	TO	to
33	O	17	0	NN	r
33	O	18	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
33	ORGANIZATION	19	0	NNP	Monroe/Abbey
33	O	20	0	,	,
33	PERSON	21	0	NNP	Saul/Hayes
33	O	22	0	,	,
33	O	23	0	CC	and
33	PERSON	24	0	NNP	A./M./Klein
33	O	25	0	,	,
33	O	26	0	NN	Publication
33	O	27	0	IN	of
33	PERSON	28	0	NNP	A./M./Klein
33	O	29	0	POS	's
33	O	30	0	``	`
33	O	31	0	DT	The
33	MISC	32	0	NN	Second/Scroll
33	O	33	0	,	,
33	O	34	0	''	'
33	LOCATION	35	0	NNP	Montreal
33	O	36	0	.	.

34	O	0	0	NNP	November
34	O	1	0	CD	1951
34	O	2	0	.	.

35	O	0	0	NN	Source
35	O	1	0	:	:
35	O	2	0	NNP	http://www.cjhn.ca/en/explore.aspx?q=A.+M.+KleinSelected
35	O	3	0	NN	List
35	O	4	0	IN	of
35	O	5	0	NNP	Works
35	O	6	0	:	:
35	O	7	0	NN	LettersA.M
35	O	8	0	.	.

36	PERSON	0	0	NNP	Klein
36	O	1	0	:	:
36	O	2	0	DT	The
36	O	3	0	NNS	Letters
36	O	4	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
36	O	5	0	IN	in
36	O	6	0	NN	progress
36	O	7	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
36	O	8	0	NNPS	NotebooksNotebooks
36	O	9	0	:	:
36	O	10	0	NNS	Selections
36	O	11	0	IN	from
36	O	12	0	DT	the
36	ORGANIZATION	13	0	NNP	A.M./Klein/Papers
36	O	14	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
36	O	15	0	CD	1994
36	O	16	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
36	ORGANIZATION	17	0	NNP	PoetryHath
36	O	18	0	RB	not
36	O	19	0	DT	a
36	O	20	0	NN	Jew
36	O	21	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
36	O	22	0	CD	1940
36	O	23	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
36	O	24	0	NNS	Poems
36	O	25	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
36	O	26	0	CD	1944
36	O	27	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
36	O	28	0	DT	The
36	PERSON	29	0	NNP	Hitleriad
36	O	30	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
36	O	31	0	CD	1944
36	O	32	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
36	O	33	0	CD	Seven
36	O	34	0	NNS	Poems
36	O	35	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
36	O	36	0	CD	1947
36	O	37	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
36	O	38	0	DT	The
36	MISC	39	0	NN	Rocking/Chair
36	O	40	0	:	:
36	O	41	0	CC	and
36	ORGANIZATION	42	0	NNS	Other/Poems
36	O	43	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
36	O	44	0	CD	1948
36	O	45	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
36	O	46	0	DT	The
36	PERSON	47	0	NNP	Collected/Poems/of/A./M./Klein
36	O	48	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
36	O	49	0	CD	1974
36	O	50	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
36	O	51	0	NNP	A.M.
36	PERSON	52	0	NNP	Klein
36	O	53	0	:	:
36	O	54	0	DT	The
36	ORGANIZATION	55	0	NNS	Complete/Poems
36	O	56	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
36	O	57	0	CD	1990
36	O	58	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
36	O	59	0	NNP	Doctor
36	PERSON	60	0	NN	Dwarf
36	O	61	0	CC	and
36	ORGANIZATION	62	0	NNP	Other/Poems/for/Children
36	O	63	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
36	O	64	0	CD	1990
36	O	65	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
36	O	66	0	NNP	EssaysBeyond
36	LOCATION	67	0	NNP	Sambation
36	O	68	0	:	:
36	ORGANIZATION	69	0	NNS	Selected/Essays/and/Editorials
36	O	70	0	,	,
36	O	71	0	CD	1928-1955
36	O	72	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
36	O	73	0	CD	1982
36	O	74	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
36	ORGANIZATION	75	0	NNS	Literary/Essays/and/Reviews
36	O	76	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
36	O	77	0	CD	1987
36	O	78	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
36	O	79	0	NNP	NovelsThe
36	O	80	0	NNP	Second
36	O	81	0	NNP	Scroll
36	O	82	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
36	O	83	0	CD	1954
36	O	84	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
36	O	85	0	JJ	Short
36	ORGANIZATION	86	0	NNP	StoriesThe/Short/Stories/of/A.M./Klein
36	O	87	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
36	O	88	0	CD	1983
36	O	89	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
36	ORGANIZATION	90	0	NNP	DramaHershel/of/Ostropol
36	O	91	0	IN	in
36	PERSON	92	0	NNP	Canadian/Jewish/Chronicle
36	O	93	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
36	O	94	0	CD	1939
36	O	95	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
36	ORGANIZATION	96	0	NNP	TranslationsFrom/Palestine
36	O	97	0	TO	to
36	LOCATION	98	0	NNP	Israel
36	O	99	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
36	O	100	0	CD	1951
36	O	101	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
36	O	102	0	IN	Of
36	MISC	103	0	NN	Jewish/Music
36	O	104	0	,	,
36	O	105	0	JJ	Ancient
36	O	106	0	CC	and
36	MISC	107	0	NNP	Modern
36	O	108	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
36	O	109	0	CD	1952
36	O	110	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
36	ORGANIZATION	111	0	NN	AdaptationsConscience
36	O	112	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
36	O	113	0	CD	1952
36	O	114	0	-RRB-	-RRB-

0	LOCATION	0	0	NNP	Henein
0	O	1	0	,	,
0	PERSON	2	0	NNP	Adam
0	O	3	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
0	O	4	0	CD	1929
0	O	5	0	:	--
0	O	6	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
0	O	7	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
0	O	8	0	VB	Enter
0	O	9	0	DT	any
0	O	10	0	JJ	variant
0	O	11	0	NNS	forms
0	O	12	0	IN	of
0	O	13	0	PRP$	your
0	O	14	0	NN	headword
0	O	15	0	:	--
0	O	16	0	NN	OPTIONAL
0	O	17	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
0	LOCATION	18	0	VBN	Born
0	O	19	0	IN	in
0	LOCATION	20	0	NNP	Cairo
0	O	21	0	,	,
0	LOCATION	22	0	NNP	Egypt
0	O	23	0	,	,
0	PERSON	24	0	NNP	Adam/Henein
0	O	25	0	VBZ	is
0	O	26	0	CD	one
0	O	27	0	IN	of
0	O	28	0	DT	the
0	O	29	0	VBG	leading
0	O	30	0	JJ	contemporary
0	O	31	0	NNS	sculptors
0	O	32	0	IN	of
0	O	33	0	DT	the
0	MISC	34	0	NNP	Arab/World
0	O	35	0	.	.

1	O	0	0	IN	Throughout
1	O	1	0	PRP$	his
1	O	2	0	NN	career
1	O	3	0	,	,
1	O	4	0	PRP	he
1	O	5	0	VBD	produced
1	O	6	0	JJ	large
1	O	7	0	CC	and
1	O	8	0	JJ	small-scale
1	O	9	0	NNS	pieces
1	O	10	0	VBG	incorporating
1	O	11	0	NN	granite
1	O	12	0	,	,
1	O	13	0	NN	bronze
1	O	14	0	,	,
1	O	15	0	NN	plaster
1	O	16	0	,	,
1	O	17	0	NN	limestone
1	O	18	0	CC	and
1	O	19	0	NN	terracotta
1	O	20	0	.	.

2	O	0	0	PRP$	His
2	O	1	0	NN	work
2	O	2	0	VBZ	is
2	O	3	0	VBN	inspired
2	O	4	0	IN	by
2	O	5	0	DT	the
2	O	6	0	JJ	graceful
2	O	7	0	NN	solidity
2	O	8	0	IN	of
2	O	9	0	JJ	ancient
2	MISC	10	0	JJ	Egyptian
2	O	11	0	NN	statuary
2	O	12	0	CC	and
2	O	13	0	VBZ	expresses
2	O	14	0	DT	a
2	O	15	0	NN	sense
2	O	16	0	IN	of
2	O	17	0	NN	simplicity
2	O	18	0	IN	in
2	O	19	0	DT	the
2	O	20	0	NN	treatment
2	O	21	0	IN	of
2	O	22	0	NN	mass
2	O	23	0	CC	and
2	O	24	0	NNS	volumes
2	O	25	0	.	.

3	PERSON	0	0	NN	Henein
3	O	1	0	VBZ	is
3	O	2	0	RB	also
3	O	3	0	DT	a
3	O	4	0	JJ	talented
3	O	5	0	NN	painter
3	O	6	0	WP	who
3	O	7	0	VBD	worked
3	O	8	0	TO	to
3	O	9	0	VB	revive
3	O	10	0	JJ	ancient
3	O	11	0	NNS	techniques
3	O	12	0	,	,
3	O	13	0	JJ	such
3	O	14	0	IN	as
3	O	15	0	VBG	working
3	O	16	0	IN	with
3	O	17	0	JJ	natural
3	O	18	0	NNS	pigments
3	O	19	0	IN	on
3	O	20	0	NN	papyrus
3	O	21	0	NNS	sheets
3	O	22	0	.	.

4	O	0	0	VBG	Graduating
4	O	1	0	IN	from
4	O	2	0	DT	the
4	ORGANIZATION	3	0	NNS	School/of/Fine/Arts
4	O	4	0	IN	in
4	LOCATION	5	0	NNP	Cairo
4	O	6	0	IN	in
4	O	7	0	CD	1953
4	O	8	0	,	,
4	O	9	0	PRP	he
4	O	10	0	VBD	received
4	O	11	0	DT	a
4	O	12	0	NN	scholarship
4	O	13	0	IN	in
4	O	14	0	CD	1957
4	O	15	0	TO	to
4	O	16	0	VB	pursue
4	O	17	0	PRP$	his
4	O	18	0	NNS	studies
4	O	19	0	IN	at
4	O	20	0	DT	the
4	ORGANIZATION	21	0	NNS	Academy/of/Fine/Arts
4	O	22	0	IN	in
4	LOCATION	23	0	NNP	Munich
4	O	24	0	.	.

5	O	0	0	IN	In
5	O	1	0	CD	1971
5	O	2	0	,	,
5	O	3	0	PRP	he
5	O	4	0	VBD	moved
5	O	5	0	TO	to
5	LOCATION	6	0	NNP	Paris
5	O	7	0	,	,
5	O	8	0	WRB	where
5	O	9	0	PRP	he
5	O	10	0	VBD	stayed
5	O	11	0	IN	for
5	O	12	0	CD	twenty-five
5	O	13	0	NNS	years
5	O	14	0	.	.

6	O	0	0	IN	By
6	O	1	0	DT	the
6	O	2	0	NN	time
6	O	3	0	PRP	he
6	O	4	0	VBD	returned
6	O	5	0	TO	to
6	LOCATION	6	0	NNP	Egypt
6	O	7	0	IN	in
6	O	8	0	CD	1996
6	O	9	0	,	,
6	O	10	0	PRP	he
6	O	11	0	VBD	enjoyed
6	O	12	0	JJ	international
6	O	13	0	NN	recognition
6	O	14	0	.	.

7	O	0	0	PRP	He
7	O	1	0	VBD	was
7	O	2	0	VBN	appointed
7	O	3	0	IN	by
7	O	4	0	DT	the
7	ORGANIZATION	5	0	NNP	Ministry/of/Culture
7	O	6	0	TO	to
7	O	7	0	VB	participate
7	O	8	0	IN	in
7	O	9	0	DT	the
7	O	10	0	NN	restoration
7	O	11	0	IN	of
7	O	12	0	DT	the
7	ORGANIZATION	13	0	NN	Sphinx
7	O	14	0	IN	in
7	LOCATION	15	0	NNP	Giza
7	O	16	0	IN	from
7	O	17	0	CD	1989
7	O	18	0	TO	to
7	O	19	0	CD	1998
7	O	20	0	.	.

8	O	0	0	IN	In
8	O	1	0	CD	1996
8	O	2	0	,	,
8	O	3	0	PRP	he
8	O	4	0	VBD	founded
8	O	5	0	DT	the
8	ORGANIZATION	6	0	NNP	Aswan/International/Sculpture/Symposium
8	O	7	0	.	.

9	LOCATION	0	0	VBN	Born
9	O	1	0	IN	in
9	LOCATION	2	0	NNP	Cairo
9	O	3	0	,	,
9	LOCATION	4	0	NNP	Egypt
9	O	5	0	,	,
9	PERSON	6	0	NNP	Adam/Henein
9	O	7	0	VBZ	is
9	O	8	0	CD	one
9	O	9	0	IN	of
9	O	10	0	DT	the
9	O	11	0	VBG	leading
9	O	12	0	JJ	contemporary
9	O	13	0	NNS	sculptors
9	O	14	0	IN	of
9	O	15	0	DT	the
9	MISC	16	0	NNP	Arab/World
9	O	17	0	.	.

10	O	0	0	IN	Throughout
10	O	1	0	PRP$	his
10	O	2	0	NN	career
10	O	3	0	,	,
10	O	4	0	PRP	he
10	O	5	0	VBD	produced
10	O	6	0	JJ	large
10	O	7	0	CC	and
10	O	8	0	JJ	small-scale
10	O	9	0	NNS	pieces
10	O	10	0	VBG	incorporating
10	O	11	0	NN	granite
10	O	12	0	,	,
10	O	13	0	NN	bronze
10	O	14	0	,	,
10	O	15	0	NN	plaster
10	O	16	0	,	,
10	O	17	0	NN	limestone
10	O	18	0	CC	and
10	O	19	0	NN	terracotta
10	O	20	0	.	.

11	O	0	0	PRP$	His
11	O	1	0	NN	work
11	O	2	0	VBZ	is
11	O	3	0	VBN	inspired
11	O	4	0	IN	by
11	O	5	0	DT	the
11	O	6	0	JJ	graceful
11	O	7	0	NN	solidity
11	O	8	0	IN	of
11	O	9	0	JJ	ancient
11	MISC	10	0	JJ	Egyptian
11	O	11	0	NN	statuary
11	O	12	0	CC	and
11	O	13	0	VBZ	expresses
11	O	14	0	DT	a
11	O	15	0	NN	sense
11	O	16	0	IN	of
11	O	17	0	NN	simplicity
11	O	18	0	IN	in
11	O	19	0	DT	the
11	O	20	0	NN	treatment
11	O	21	0	IN	of
11	O	22	0	NN	mass
11	O	23	0	CC	and
11	O	24	0	NNS	volumes
11	O	25	0	.	.

12	PERSON	0	0	NN	Henein
12	O	1	0	VBZ	is
12	O	2	0	RB	also
12	O	3	0	DT	a
12	O	4	0	JJ	talented
12	O	5	0	NN	painter
12	O	6	0	WP	who
12	O	7	0	VBD	worked
12	O	8	0	TO	to
12	O	9	0	VB	revive
12	O	10	0	JJ	ancient
12	O	11	0	NNS	techniques
12	O	12	0	,	,
12	O	13	0	JJ	such
12	O	14	0	IN	as
12	O	15	0	VBG	working
12	O	16	0	IN	with
12	O	17	0	JJ	natural
12	O	18	0	NNS	pigments
12	O	19	0	IN	on
12	O	20	0	NN	papyrus
12	O	21	0	NNS	sheets
12	O	22	0	.	.

13	O	0	0	VBG	Graduating
13	O	1	0	IN	from
13	O	2	0	DT	the
13	ORGANIZATION	3	0	NNS	School/of/Fine/Arts
13	O	4	0	IN	in
13	LOCATION	5	0	NNP	Cairo
13	O	6	0	IN	in
13	O	7	0	CD	1953
13	O	8	0	,	,
13	O	9	0	PRP	he
13	O	10	0	VBD	received
13	O	11	0	DT	a
13	O	12	0	NN	scholarship
13	O	13	0	IN	in
13	O	14	0	CD	1957
13	O	15	0	TO	to
13	O	16	0	VB	pursue
13	O	17	0	PRP$	his
13	O	18	0	NNS	studies
13	O	19	0	IN	at
13	O	20	0	DT	the
13	ORGANIZATION	21	0	NNS	Academy/of/Fine/Arts
13	O	22	0	IN	in
13	LOCATION	23	0	NNP	Munich
13	O	24	0	.	.

14	O	0	0	IN	In
14	O	1	0	CD	1971
14	O	2	0	,	,
14	O	3	0	PRP	he
14	O	4	0	VBD	moved
14	O	5	0	TO	to
14	LOCATION	6	0	NNP	Paris
14	O	7	0	,	,
14	O	8	0	WRB	where
14	O	9	0	PRP	he
14	O	10	0	VBD	stayed
14	O	11	0	IN	for
14	O	12	0	CD	twenty-five
14	O	13	0	NNS	years
14	O	14	0	.	.

15	O	0	0	IN	By
15	O	1	0	DT	the
15	O	2	0	NN	time
15	O	3	0	PRP	he
15	O	4	0	VBD	returned
15	O	5	0	TO	to
15	LOCATION	6	0	NNP	Egypt
15	O	7	0	IN	in
15	O	8	0	CD	1996
15	O	9	0	,	,
15	O	10	0	PRP	he
15	O	11	0	VBD	enjoyed
15	O	12	0	JJ	international
15	O	13	0	NN	recognition
15	O	14	0	.	.

16	O	0	0	PRP	He
16	O	1	0	VBD	was
16	O	2	0	VBN	appointed
16	O	3	0	IN	by
16	O	4	0	DT	the
16	ORGANIZATION	5	0	NNP	Ministry/of/Culture
16	O	6	0	TO	to
16	O	7	0	VB	participate
16	O	8	0	IN	in
16	O	9	0	DT	the
16	O	10	0	NN	restoration
16	O	11	0	IN	of
16	O	12	0	DT	the
16	ORGANIZATION	13	0	NN	Sphinx
16	O	14	0	IN	in
16	LOCATION	15	0	NNP	Giza
16	O	16	0	IN	from
16	O	17	0	CD	1989
16	O	18	0	TO	to
16	O	19	0	CD	1998
16	O	20	0	.	.

17	O	0	0	IN	In
17	O	1	0	CD	1996
17	O	2	0	,	,
17	O	3	0	PRP	he
17	O	4	0	VBD	founded
17	O	5	0	DT	the
17	ORGANIZATION	6	0	NNP	Aswan/International/Sculpture/Symposium
17	O	7	0	.	.

0	PERSON	0	0	NNP	Varda
0	O	1	0	,	,
0	PERSON	2	0	NNP	Agnès
0	O	3	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
0	O	4	0	NNP	May
0	O	5	0	CD	30
0	O	6	0	,	,
0	O	7	0	CD	1928
0	O	8	0	:	--
0	O	9	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
0	O	10	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
0	O	11	0	VB	Enter
0	O	12	0	DT	any
0	O	13	0	JJ	variant
0	O	14	0	NNS	forms
0	O	15	0	IN	of
0	O	16	0	PRP$	your
0	O	17	0	NN	headword
0	O	18	0	:	--
0	O	19	0	NN	OPTIONAL
0	O	20	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
0	PERSON	21	0	NNP	Agnès/Varda
0	O	22	0	VBZ	is
0	O	23	0	DT	a
0	MISC	24	0	JJ	French
0	O	25	0	NN	filmmaker
0	O	26	0	CC	and
0	O	27	0	JJ	visual
0	O	28	0	NN	artist
0	O	29	0	.	.

1	O	0	0	PRP	She
1	O	1	0	VBZ	is
1	O	2	0	RB	best
1	O	3	0	VBN	known
1	O	4	0	IN	as
1	O	5	0	DT	the
1	O	6	0	JJ	key
1	O	7	0	JJ	female
1	O	8	0	NN	figure
1	O	9	0	IN	of
1	O	10	0	DT	the
1	MISC	11	0	NNP	French/New/Wave
1	O	12	0	.	.

2	O	0	0	RBR	More
2	O	1	0	RB	recently
2	O	2	0	,	,
2	O	3	0	PRP	she
2	O	4	0	VBZ	has
2	O	5	0	VBN	been
2	O	6	0	DT	a
2	O	7	0	NN	pioneer
2	O	8	0	IN	of
2	O	9	0	DT	the
2	O	10	0	NN	documentary
2	O	11	0	NN	genre
2	O	12	0	VBN	known
2	O	13	0	IN	as
2	O	14	0	DT	the
2	O	15	0	NN	essay
2	O	16	0	NN	film
2	O	17	0	.	.

3	LOCATION	0	0	VBN	Born
3	O	1	0	IN	in
3	LOCATION	2	0	NNP	Brussels
3	O	3	0	,	,
3	PERSON	4	0	NNP	Varda
3	O	5	0	VBD	began
3	O	6	0	PRP$	her
3	O	7	0	NN	career
3	O	8	0	IN	as
3	O	9	0	DT	a
3	O	10	0	RB	still
3	O	11	0	NNP	photographer
3	O	12	0	.	.

4	O	0	0	PRP$	Her
4	O	1	0	JJ	first
4	O	2	0	NN	feature-film
4	O	3	0	,	,
4	ORGANIZATION	4	0	NNP	La/Pointe/Courte
4	O	5	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
4	O	6	0	CD	1955
4	O	7	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
4	O	8	0	,	,
4	O	9	0	VBN	shot
4	O	10	0	IN	on
4	O	11	0	DT	a
4	O	12	0	JJ	small
4	O	13	0	NN	budget
4	O	14	0	IN	in
4	O	15	0	DT	a
4	MISC	16	0	JJ	French
4	O	17	0	NN	fishing
4	O	18	0	NN	village
4	O	19	0	,	,
4	O	20	0	MD	can
4	O	21	0	VB	be
4	O	22	0	VBN	understood
4	O	23	0	IN	as
4	O	24	0	DT	a
4	O	25	0	JJ	stylistic
4	O	26	0	NN	bridge
4	O	27	0	IN	between
4	MISC	28	0	JJ	Italian
4	O	29	0	NN	Neo-Realism
4	O	30	0	CC	and
4	O	31	0	DT	the
4	MISC	32	0	NNP	French/New/Wave
4	O	33	0	.	.

5	O	0	0	PRP$	Her
5	O	1	0	RBS	most
5	O	2	0	JJ	important
5	O	3	0	NN	film
5	O	4	0	,	,
5	PERSON	5	0	NNP	Cléo
5	O	6	0	IN	de
5	O	7	0	CD	5
5	O	8	0	NN	à
5	O	9	0	CD	7
5	O	10	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
5	PERSON	11	0	NN	Cléo
5	O	12	0	IN	from
5	O	13	0	CD	5
5	O	14	0	TO	to
5	O	15	0	CD	7
5	O	16	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
5	O	17	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
5	O	18	0	CD	1962
5	O	19	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
5	O	20	0	,	,
5	O	21	0	VBZ	captures
5	O	22	0	CD	two
5	O	23	0	NNS	hours
5	O	24	0	IN	in
5	O	25	0	DT	the
5	O	26	0	NN	life
5	O	27	0	IN	of
5	O	28	0	DT	a
5	MISC	29	0	JJ	Parisian
5	O	30	0	NN	starlet
5	O	31	0	IN	as
5	O	32	0	PRP	she
5	O	33	0	VBZ	awaits
5	O	34	0	DT	the
5	O	35	0	NNS	results
5	O	36	0	IN	from
5	O	37	0	DT	a
5	O	38	0	NN	cancer
5	O	39	0	NN	biopsy
5	O	40	0	.	.

6	O	0	0	DT	The
6	O	1	0	NN	film
6	O	2	0	VBZ	is
6	O	3	0	JJ	notable
6	O	4	0	IN	for
6	O	5	0	PRP$	its
6	O	6	0	JJ	innovative
6	O	7	0	JJ	narrative
6	O	8	0	NN	structure
6	O	9	0	,	,
6	O	10	0	PRP$	its
6	O	11	0	NN	treatment
6	O	12	0	IN	of
6	O	13	0	NN	existentialist
6	O	14	0	NNS	themes
6	O	15	0	,	,
6	O	16	0	CC	and
6	O	17	0	PRP$	its
6	O	18	0	JJ	ground-breaking
6	O	19	0	NN	study
6	O	20	0	IN	of
6	O	21	0	JJ	modern
6	O	22	0	JJ	feminine
6	O	23	0	NN	identity
6	O	24	0	.	.

7	O	0	0	IN	In
7	O	1	0	DT	the
7	O	2	0	JJ	late
7	O	3	0	NNS	1960s
7	O	4	0	,	,
7	PERSON	5	0	NNP	Varda
7	O	6	0	CC	and
7	O	7	0	PRP$	her
7	O	8	0	NN	husband
7	O	9	0	,	,
7	O	10	0	DT	the
7	O	11	0	NN	director
7	PERSON	12	0	NNP	Jacques/Demy
7	O	13	0	,	,
7	O	14	0	VBD	lived
7	O	15	0	IN	in
7	LOCATION	16	0	NNP	Los/Angeles
7	O	17	0	,	,
7	O	18	0	WRB	where
7	O	19	0	PRP	she
7	O	20	0	VBD	befriended
7	O	21	0	JJ	key
7	O	22	0	NNS	figures
7	O	23	0	IN	of
7	O	24	0	DT	the
7	LOCATION	25	0	NNP	California
7	O	26	0	NN	counterculture
7	O	27	0	.	.

8	O	0	0	PRP$	Her
8	O	1	0	CD	1985
8	O	2	0	NN	film
8	MISC	3	0	NNS	Sans
8	O	4	0	VBP	toit
8	O	5	0	NNS	ni
8	O	6	0	JJ	loi
8	O	7	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
8	O	8	0	NN	Vagabond
8	O	9	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
8	O	10	0	VBN	employed
8	O	11	0	DT	a
8	O	12	0	JJ	Rashomon-like
8	O	13	0	JJ	multi-perspectival
8	O	14	0	NN	structure
8	O	15	0	TO	to
8	O	16	0	VB	explore
8	O	17	0	DT	the
8	O	18	0	JJ	final
8	O	19	0	NNS	weeks
8	O	20	0	IN	of
8	O	21	0	DT	an
8	O	22	0	JJ	enigmatic
8	O	23	0	CC	and
8	O	24	0	JJ	rebellious
8	O	25	0	NN	drifter
8	O	26	0	VBN	played
8	O	27	0	IN	by
8	PERSON	28	0	NNP	Sandrine/Bonnaire
8	O	29	0	.	.

9	PERSON	0	0	NNP	Varda
9	O	1	0	POS	's
9	O	2	0	RBS	most
9	O	3	0	JJ	important
9	O	4	0	JJ	recent
9	O	5	0	NN	film
9	O	6	0	VBZ	is
9	O	7	0	DT	the
9	O	8	0	JJ	documentary-essay
9	O	9	0	DT	The
9	MISC	10	0	NNPS	Gleaners
9	O	11	0	CC	and
9	O	12	0	PRP	I
9	O	13	0	,	,
9	O	14	0	VBN	shot
9	O	15	0	IN	on
9	O	16	0	DT	an
9	O	17	0	JJ	inexpensive
9	O	18	0	NN	camcorder
9	O	19	0	,	,
9	O	20	0	IN	about
9	O	21	0	DT	the
9	O	22	0	NN	practice
9	O	23	0	IN	of
9	O	24	0	NN	scavenging
9	O	25	0	.	.

10	PERSON	0	0	NNP	Varda
10	O	1	0	POS	's
10	O	2	0	NN	voice-over
10	O	3	0	VBZ	suggests
10	O	4	0	DT	the
10	O	5	0	NN	film
10	O	6	0	PRP	itself
10	O	7	0	MD	can
10	O	8	0	VB	be
10	O	9	0	VBN	understood
10	O	10	0	IN	as
10	O	11	0	DT	an
10	O	12	0	JJ	affectionate
10	O	13	0	NN	collection
10	O	14	0	IN	of
10	O	15	0	VBN	gathered
10	O	16	0	NNS	scraps
10	O	17	0	.	.

11	O	0	0	IN	Throughout
11	O	1	0	PRP$	her
11	O	2	0	NN	work
11	PERSON	3	0	NNP	Varda
11	O	4	0	VBZ	has
11	O	5	0	VBN	explored
11	O	6	0	DT	the
11	O	7	0	NN	relationship
11	O	8	0	IN	of
11	O	9	0	DT	the
11	O	10	0	JJ	individual
11	O	11	0	TO	to
11	O	12	0	NN	society
11	O	13	0	CC	and
11	O	14	0	DT	the
11	O	15	0	NN	place
11	O	16	0	IN	of
11	O	17	0	NN	intimacy
11	O	18	0	,	,
11	O	19	0	NN	happiness
11	O	20	0	,	,
11	O	21	0	NN	death
11	O	22	0	,	,
11	O	23	0	CC	and
11	O	24	0	NN	chance
11	O	25	0	NNS	encounters
11	O	26	0	IN	in
11	O	27	0	JJ	contemporary
11	O	28	0	NN	culture
11	O	29	0	.	.

12	PERSON	0	0	NNP	Agnès/Varda
12	O	1	0	VBZ	is
12	O	2	0	DT	a
12	MISC	3	0	JJ	French
12	O	4	0	NN	filmmaker
12	O	5	0	CC	and
12	O	6	0	JJ	visual
12	O	7	0	NN	artist
12	O	8	0	.	.

13	O	0	0	PRP	She
13	O	1	0	VBZ	is
13	O	2	0	RB	best
13	O	3	0	VBN	known
13	O	4	0	IN	as
13	O	5	0	DT	the
13	O	6	0	JJ	key
13	O	7	0	JJ	female
13	O	8	0	NN	figure
13	O	9	0	IN	of
13	O	10	0	DT	the
13	MISC	11	0	NNP	French/New/Wave
13	O	12	0	.	.

14	O	0	0	RBR	More
14	O	1	0	RB	recently
14	O	2	0	,	,
14	O	3	0	PRP	she
14	O	4	0	VBZ	has
14	O	5	0	VBN	been
14	O	6	0	DT	a
14	O	7	0	NN	pioneer
14	O	8	0	IN	of
14	O	9	0	DT	the
14	O	10	0	NN	documentary
14	O	11	0	NN	genre
14	O	12	0	VBN	known
14	O	13	0	IN	as
14	O	14	0	DT	the
14	O	15	0	NN	essay
14	O	16	0	NN	film
14	O	17	0	.	.

15	LOCATION	0	0	VBN	Born
15	O	1	0	IN	in
15	LOCATION	2	0	NNP	Brussels
15	O	3	0	,	,
15	PERSON	4	0	NNP	Varda
15	O	5	0	VBD	began
15	O	6	0	PRP$	her
15	O	7	0	NN	career
15	O	8	0	IN	as
15	O	9	0	DT	a
15	O	10	0	RB	still
15	O	11	0	NNP	photographer
15	O	12	0	.	.

16	O	0	0	PRP$	Her
16	O	1	0	JJ	first
16	O	2	0	NN	feature-film
16	O	3	0	,	,
16	ORGANIZATION	4	0	NNP	La/Pointe/Courte
16	O	5	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
16	O	6	0	CD	1955
16	O	7	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
16	O	8	0	,	,
16	O	9	0	VBN	shot
16	O	10	0	IN	on
16	O	11	0	DT	a
16	O	12	0	JJ	small
16	O	13	0	NN	budget
16	O	14	0	IN	in
16	O	15	0	DT	a
16	MISC	16	0	JJ	French
16	O	17	0	NN	fishing
16	O	18	0	NN	village
16	O	19	0	,	,
16	O	20	0	MD	can
16	O	21	0	VB	be
16	O	22	0	VBN	understood
16	O	23	0	IN	as
16	O	24	0	DT	a
16	O	25	0	JJ	stylistic
16	O	26	0	NN	bridge
16	O	27	0	IN	between
16	MISC	28	0	JJ	Italian
16	O	29	0	NN	Neo-Realism
16	O	30	0	CC	and
16	O	31	0	DT	the
16	MISC	32	0	NNP	French/New/Wave
16	O	33	0	.	.

17	O	0	0	PRP$	Her
17	O	1	0	RBS	most
17	O	2	0	JJ	important
17	O	3	0	NN	film
17	O	4	0	,	,
17	PERSON	5	0	NNP	Cléo
17	O	6	0	IN	de
17	O	7	0	CD	5
17	O	8	0	NN	à
17	O	9	0	CD	7
17	O	10	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
17	PERSON	11	0	NN	Cléo
17	O	12	0	IN	from
17	O	13	0	CD	5
17	O	14	0	TO	to
17	O	15	0	CD	7
17	O	16	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
17	O	17	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
17	O	18	0	CD	1962
17	O	19	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
17	O	20	0	,	,
17	O	21	0	VBZ	captures
17	O	22	0	CD	two
17	O	23	0	NNS	hours
17	O	24	0	IN	in
17	O	25	0	DT	the
17	O	26	0	NN	life
17	O	27	0	IN	of
17	O	28	0	DT	a
17	MISC	29	0	JJ	Parisian
17	O	30	0	NN	starlet
17	O	31	0	IN	as
17	O	32	0	PRP	she
17	O	33	0	VBZ	awaits
17	O	34	0	DT	the
17	O	35	0	NNS	results
17	O	36	0	IN	from
17	O	37	0	DT	a
17	O	38	0	NN	cancer
17	O	39	0	NN	biopsy
17	O	40	0	.	.

18	O	0	0	DT	The
18	O	1	0	NN	film
18	O	2	0	VBZ	is
18	O	3	0	JJ	notable
18	O	4	0	IN	for
18	O	5	0	PRP$	its
18	O	6	0	JJ	innovative
18	O	7	0	JJ	narrative
18	O	8	0	NN	structure
18	O	9	0	,	,
18	O	10	0	PRP$	its
18	O	11	0	NN	treatment
18	O	12	0	IN	of
18	O	13	0	NN	existentialist
18	O	14	0	NNS	themes
18	O	15	0	,	,
18	O	16	0	CC	and
18	O	17	0	PRP$	its
18	O	18	0	JJ	ground-breaking
18	O	19	0	NN	study
18	O	20	0	IN	of
18	O	21	0	JJ	modern
18	O	22	0	JJ	feminine
18	O	23	0	NN	identity.File
18	O	24	0	:	:
18	O	25	0	NN	varda1.jpgSource
18	O	26	0	:	:
18	O	27	0	NN	http://25.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_kvygejskIZ1qzdvhio1_r1_500.jpg
18	O	28	0	IN	In
18	O	29	0	DT	the
18	O	30	0	JJ	late
18	O	31	0	NNS	1960s
18	O	32	0	,	,
18	PERSON	33	0	NNP	Varda
18	O	34	0	CC	and
18	O	35	0	PRP$	her
18	O	36	0	NN	husband
18	O	37	0	,	,
18	O	38	0	DT	the
18	O	39	0	NN	director
18	PERSON	40	0	NNP	Jacques/Demy
18	O	41	0	,	,
18	O	42	0	VBD	lived
18	O	43	0	IN	in
18	LOCATION	44	0	NNP	Los/Angeles
18	O	45	0	,	,
18	O	46	0	WRB	where
18	O	47	0	PRP	she
18	O	48	0	VBD	befriended
18	O	49	0	JJ	key
18	O	50	0	NNS	figures
18	O	51	0	IN	of
18	O	52	0	DT	the
18	LOCATION	53	0	NNP	California
18	O	54	0	NN	counterculture
18	O	55	0	.	.

19	O	0	0	PRP$	Her
19	O	1	0	CD	1985
19	O	2	0	NN	film
19	MISC	3	0	NNS	Sans
19	O	4	0	VBP	toit
19	O	5	0	NNS	ni
19	O	6	0	JJ	loi
19	O	7	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
19	O	8	0	NN	Vagabond
19	O	9	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
19	O	10	0	VBN	employed
19	O	11	0	DT	a
19	O	12	0	JJ	Rashomon-like
19	O	13	0	JJ	multi-perspectival
19	O	14	0	NN	structure
19	O	15	0	TO	to
19	O	16	0	VB	explore
19	O	17	0	DT	the
19	O	18	0	JJ	final
19	O	19	0	NNS	weeks
19	O	20	0	IN	of
19	O	21	0	DT	an
19	O	22	0	JJ	enigmatic
19	O	23	0	CC	and
19	O	24	0	JJ	rebellious
19	O	25	0	NN	drifter
19	O	26	0	VBN	played
19	O	27	0	IN	by
19	PERSON	28	0	NNP	Sandrine/Bonnaire.Varda
19	O	29	0	POS	's
19	O	30	0	RBS	most
19	O	31	0	JJ	important
19	O	32	0	JJ	recent
19	O	33	0	NN	film
19	O	34	0	VBZ	is
19	O	35	0	DT	the
19	O	36	0	JJ	documentary-essay
19	O	37	0	DT	The
19	MISC	38	0	NNPS	Gleaners
19	O	39	0	CC	and
19	O	40	0	PRP	I
19	O	41	0	,	,
19	O	42	0	VBN	shot
19	O	43	0	IN	on
19	O	44	0	DT	an
19	O	45	0	JJ	inexpensive
19	O	46	0	NN	camcorder
19	O	47	0	,	,
19	O	48	0	IN	about
19	O	49	0	DT	the
19	O	50	0	NN	practice
19	O	51	0	IN	of
19	O	52	0	NN	scavenging
19	O	53	0	.	.

20	PERSON	0	0	NNP	Varda
20	O	1	0	POS	's
20	O	2	0	NN	voice-over
20	O	3	0	VBZ	suggests
20	O	4	0	DT	the
20	O	5	0	NN	film
20	O	6	0	PRP	itself
20	O	7	0	MD	can
20	O	8	0	VB	be
20	O	9	0	VBN	understood
20	O	10	0	IN	as
20	O	11	0	DT	an
20	O	12	0	JJ	affectionate
20	O	13	0	NN	collection
20	O	14	0	IN	of
20	O	15	0	VBN	gathered
20	O	16	0	NNP	scraps.Throughout
20	O	17	0	PRP$	her
20	O	18	0	NN	work
20	PERSON	19	0	NNP	Varda
20	O	20	0	VBZ	has
20	O	21	0	VBN	explored
20	O	22	0	DT	the
20	O	23	0	NN	relationship
20	O	24	0	IN	of
20	O	25	0	DT	the
20	O	26	0	JJ	individual
20	O	27	0	TO	to
20	O	28	0	NN	society
20	O	29	0	CC	and
20	O	30	0	DT	the
20	O	31	0	NN	place
20	O	32	0	IN	of
20	O	33	0	NN	intimacy
20	O	34	0	,	,
20	O	35	0	NN	happiness
20	O	36	0	,	,
20	O	37	0	NN	death
20	O	38	0	,	,
20	O	39	0	CC	and
20	O	40	0	NN	chance
20	O	41	0	NNS	encounters
20	O	42	0	IN	in
20	O	43	0	JJ	contemporary
20	O	44	0	NN	culture
20	O	45	0	.	.

21	O	0	0	NN	List
21	O	1	0	IN	of
21	O	2	0	NNP	Works
21	O	3	0	:	:
21	ORGANIZATION	4	0	NNP	La/Pointe/Courte
21	O	5	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
21	O	6	0	CD	1955
21	O	7	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
21	PERSON	8	0	NNP	Cléo
21	O	9	0	IN	de
21	O	10	0	CD	5
21	O	11	0	NN	à
21	O	12	0	CD	7
21	O	13	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
21	PERSON	14	0	NN	Cléo
21	O	15	0	IN	from
21	O	16	0	CD	5
21	O	17	0	TO	to
21	O	18	0	CD	7
21	O	19	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
21	O	20	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
21	O	21	0	CD	1962
21	O	22	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
21	ORGANIZATION	23	0	NNP	Le/Bonheur
21	O	24	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
21	O	25	0	NNP	Happiness
21	O	26	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
21	O	27	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
21	O	28	0	CD	1965
21	O	29	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
21	MISC	30	0	NNP	Sans
21	O	31	0	NN	toit
21	O	32	0	NN	ni
21	O	33	0	NN	loi
21	O	34	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
21	O	35	0	NN	Vagabond
21	O	36	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
21	O	37	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
21	O	38	0	CD	1985
21	O	39	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
21	O	40	0	NNP	Les
21	O	41	0	VBZ	glaneurs
21	O	42	0	FW	et
21	O	43	0	FW	la
21	O	44	0	NN	glaneuse
21	O	45	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
21	O	46	0	DT	The
21	MISC	47	0	NNPS	Gleaners
21	O	48	0	CC	and
21	O	49	0	PRP	I
21	O	50	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
21	O	51	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
21	O	52	0	CD	2000
21	O	53	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
21	O	54	0	NNP	Les
21	O	55	0	VBZ	plages
21	O	56	0	NN	d'Agnès
21	O	57	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
21	O	58	0	DT	The
21	ORGANIZATION	59	0	NNP	Beaches/of/Agnès
21	O	60	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
21	O	61	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
21	O	62	0	CD	2008
21	O	63	0	-RRB-	-RRB-

0	PERSON	0	0	NNP	Kurosawa
0	O	1	0	,	,
0	PERSON	2	0	NNP	Akira
0	O	3	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
0	O	4	0	CD	1910-1998
0	O	5	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
0	O	6	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
0	O	7	0	VB	Enter
0	O	8	0	DT	any
0	O	9	0	JJ	variant
0	O	10	0	NNS	forms
0	O	11	0	IN	of
0	O	12	0	PRP$	your
0	O	13	0	NN	headword
0	O	14	0	:	--
0	O	15	0	NN	OPTIONAL
0	O	16	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
0	O	17	0	DT	The
0	MISC	18	0	JJ	Japanese
0	O	19	0	NN	director
0	PERSON	20	0	NNP	Kurosawa/Akira
0	O	21	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
0	O	22	0	CD	23
0	O	23	0	NNP	March
0	O	24	0	CD	1910-6
0	O	25	0	NNP	September
0	O	26	0	CD	1998
0	O	27	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
0	O	28	0	VBZ	has
0	O	29	0	VBN	been
0	O	30	0	RB	internationally
0	O	31	0	VBN	celebrated
0	O	32	0	IN	as
0	O	33	0	CD	one
0	O	34	0	IN	of
0	O	35	0	DT	the
0	O	36	0	RBS	most
0	O	37	0	JJ	important
0	O	38	0	NNS	filmmakers
0	O	39	0	IN	in
0	O	40	0	DT	the
0	O	41	0	NN	history
0	O	42	0	IN	of
0	O	43	0	NN	cinema
0	O	44	0	.	.

1	O	0	0	CD	One
1	O	1	0	IN	of
1	O	2	0	PRP$	his
1	O	3	0	RB	highly
1	O	4	0	JJ	acclaimed
1	O	5	0	NNS	works
1	O	6	0	VBZ	is
1	O	7	0	NNP	Rashomon
1	O	8	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
1	O	9	0	CD	1950
1	O	10	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
1	O	11	0	,	,
1	O	12	0	DT	the
1	O	13	0	NN	jidaigeki
1	O	14	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
1	O	15	0	NN	period
1	O	16	0	NN	drama
1	O	17	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
1	O	18	0	NN	film
1	O	19	0	RB	best
1	O	20	0	VBN	known
1	O	21	0	IN	for
1	O	22	0	DT	the
1	O	23	0	NN	complex
1	O	24	0	NN	portrayal
1	O	25	0	IN	of
1	O	26	0	JJ	several
1	O	27	0	NNS	characters
1	O	28	0	VBG	recounting
1	O	29	0	JJ	contradictory
1	O	30	0	NNS	interpretations
1	O	31	0	IN	of
1	O	32	0	DT	the
1	O	33	0	JJ	same
1	O	34	0	NN	event
1	O	35	0	.	.

2	O	0	0	DT	The
2	O	1	0	NN	film
2	O	2	0	VBD	won
2	O	3	0	DT	an
2	O	4	0	JJ	unanticipated
2	MISC	5	0	NNP	Grand/Prix
2	O	6	0	IN	at
2	O	7	0	DT	the
2	LOCATION	8	0	NNP	Venice/Film/Festival
2	O	9	0	IN	in
2	O	10	0	CD	1951
2	O	11	0	.	.

3	O	0	0	IN	For
3	O	1	0	DT	the
3	LOCATION	2	0	NNP	West
3	O	3	0	,	,
3	O	4	0	PRP$	its
3	O	5	0	NN	encounter
3	O	6	0	IN	with
3	MISC	7	0	JJ	Japanese
3	O	8	0	NN	cinema
3	O	9	0	VBD	started
3	O	10	0	IN	with
3	O	11	0	DT	this
3	O	12	0	NN	discovery
3	O	13	0	IN	of
3	PERSON	14	0	NNP	Rashomon
3	O	15	0	,	,
3	O	16	0	CC	and
3	O	17	0	IN	for
3	LOCATION	18	0	NNP	Japan
3	O	19	0	,	,
3	O	20	0	DT	the
3	O	21	0	JJ	sensational
3	O	22	0	NN	triumph
3	O	23	0	IN	of
3	O	24	0	DT	the
3	O	25	0	NN	film
3	O	26	0	RB	abroad
3	O	27	0	VBD	opened
3	O	28	0	DT	the
3	O	29	0	NN	door
3	O	30	0	TO	to
3	O	31	0	DT	the
3	LOCATION	32	0	NNP	West
3	O	33	0	IN	for
3	O	34	0	PRP$	its
3	O	35	0	NN	cinema
3	O	36	0	.	.

4	O	0	0	IN	At
4	O	1	0	DT	the
4	O	2	0	JJ	same
4	O	3	0	NN	time
4	O	4	0	,	,
4	PERSON	5	0	NNP	Rashomon
4	O	6	0	POS	's
4	O	7	0	JJ	worldwide
4	O	8	0	NN	success
4	O	9	0	VBD	gave
4	LOCATION	10	0	NNP	Japan
4	O	11	0	DT	an
4	O	12	0	``	`
4	O	13	0	NN	opportunity
4	O	14	0	TO	to
4	O	15	0	VB	rearticulate
4	O	16	0	RB	consciously
4	O	17	0	WP	what
4	O	18	0	VBD	constituted
4	O	19	0	DT	the
4	O	20	0	JJ	national
4	O	21	0	CC	and
4	O	22	0	JJ	cultural
4	O	23	0	NN	specificity
4	O	24	0	IN	of
4	MISC	25	0	JJ	Japanese
4	O	26	0	NN	cinema
4	O	27	0	,	,
4	O	28	0	''	'
4	O	29	0	IN	as
4	PERSON	30	0	NNP	Yoshimoto/Mitsuhiro
4	O	31	0	VBZ	argues
4	O	32	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
4	O	33	0	LS	1
4	O	34	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
4	O	35	0	.	.

5	PERSON	0	0	NNP	Kurosawa
5	O	1	0	POS	's
5	O	2	0	JJ	international
5	O	3	0	NN	fame
5	O	4	0	CC	and
5	O	5	0	NN	popularity
5	O	6	0	VBP	have
5	O	7	0	RB	always
5	O	8	0	VBN	gone
5	O	9	0	NN	side
5	O	10	0	IN	by
5	O	11	0	NN	side
5	O	12	0	IN	with
5	LOCATION	13	0	NNP	Japan
5	O	14	0	POS	's
5	O	15	0	NN	self-image
5	O	16	0	IN	toward
5	O	17	0	DT	the
5	LOCATION	18	0	NNP	West
5	O	19	0	CC	and
5	O	20	0	DT	the
5	LOCATION	21	0	NNP	West
5	O	22	0	POS	's
5	O	23	0	NN	use
5	O	24	0	IN	of
5	LOCATION	25	0	NNP	Japan
5	O	26	0	IN	as
5	O	27	0	DT	a
5	O	28	0	JJ	geo-political/geo-cultural
5	O	29	0	JJ	imaginary
5	O	30	0	NN	site.The
5	MISC	31	0	JJ	Japanese
5	O	32	0	NN	director
5	PERSON	33	0	NNP	Kurosawa/Akira
5	O	34	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
5	O	35	0	CD	23
5	O	36	0	NNP	March
5	O	37	0	CD	1910-6
5	O	38	0	NNP	September
5	O	39	0	CD	1998
5	O	40	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
5	O	41	0	VBZ	has
5	O	42	0	VBN	been
5	O	43	0	RB	internationally
5	O	44	0	VBN	celebrated
5	O	45	0	IN	as
5	O	46	0	CD	one
5	O	47	0	IN	of
5	O	48	0	DT	the
5	O	49	0	RBS	most
5	O	50	0	JJ	important
5	O	51	0	NNS	filmmakers
5	O	52	0	IN	in
5	O	53	0	DT	the
5	O	54	0	NN	history
5	O	55	0	IN	of
5	O	56	0	NN	cinema
5	O	57	0	.	.

6	O	0	0	CD	One
6	O	1	0	IN	of
6	O	2	0	PRP$	his
6	O	3	0	RB	highly
6	O	4	0	JJ	acclaimed
6	O	5	0	NNS	works
6	O	6	0	VBZ	is
6	O	7	0	NNP	Rashomon
6	O	8	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
6	O	9	0	CD	1950
6	O	10	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
6	O	11	0	,	,
6	O	12	0	DT	the
6	O	13	0	NN	jidaigeki
6	O	14	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
6	O	15	0	NN	period
6	O	16	0	NN	drama
6	O	17	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
6	O	18	0	NN	film
6	O	19	0	RB	best
6	O	20	0	VBN	known
6	O	21	0	IN	for
6	O	22	0	DT	the
6	O	23	0	NN	complex
6	O	24	0	NN	portrayal
6	O	25	0	IN	of
6	O	26	0	JJ	several
6	O	27	0	NNS	characters
6	O	28	0	VBG	recounting
6	O	29	0	JJ	contradictory
6	O	30	0	NNS	interpretations
6	O	31	0	IN	of
6	O	32	0	DT	the
6	O	33	0	JJ	same
6	O	34	0	NN	event
6	O	35	0	.	.

7	O	0	0	DT	The
7	O	1	0	NN	film
7	O	2	0	VBD	won
7	O	3	0	DT	an
7	O	4	0	JJ	unanticipated
7	MISC	5	0	NNP	Grand/Prix
7	O	6	0	IN	at
7	O	7	0	DT	the
7	LOCATION	8	0	NNP	Venice/Film/Festival
7	O	9	0	IN	in
7	O	10	0	CD	1951
7	O	11	0	.	.

8	O	0	0	IN	For
8	O	1	0	DT	the
8	LOCATION	2	0	NNP	West
8	O	3	0	,	,
8	O	4	0	PRP$	its
8	O	5	0	NN	encounter
8	O	6	0	IN	with
8	MISC	7	0	JJ	Japanese
8	O	8	0	NN	cinema
8	O	9	0	VBD	started
8	O	10	0	IN	with
8	O	11	0	DT	this
8	O	12	0	NN	discovery
8	O	13	0	IN	of
8	PERSON	14	0	NNP	Rashomon
8	O	15	0	,	,
8	O	16	0	CC	and
8	O	17	0	IN	for
8	LOCATION	18	0	NNP	Japan
8	O	19	0	,	,
8	O	20	0	DT	the
8	O	21	0	JJ	sensational
8	O	22	0	NN	triumph
8	O	23	0	IN	of
8	O	24	0	DT	the
8	O	25	0	NN	film
8	O	26	0	RB	abroad
8	O	27	0	VBD	opened
8	O	28	0	DT	the
8	O	29	0	NN	door
8	O	30	0	TO	to
8	O	31	0	DT	the
8	LOCATION	32	0	NNP	West
8	O	33	0	IN	for
8	O	34	0	PRP$	its
8	O	35	0	NN	cinema
8	O	36	0	.	.

9	O	0	0	IN	At
9	O	1	0	DT	the
9	O	2	0	JJ	same
9	O	3	0	NN	time
9	O	4	0	,	,
9	PERSON	5	0	NNP	Rashomon
9	O	6	0	POS	's
9	O	7	0	JJ	worldwide
9	O	8	0	NN	success
9	O	9	0	VBD	gave
9	LOCATION	10	0	NNP	Japan
9	O	11	0	DT	an
9	O	12	0	``	`
9	O	13	0	NN	opportunity
9	O	14	0	TO	to
9	O	15	0	VB	rearticulate
9	O	16	0	RB	consciously
9	O	17	0	WP	what
9	O	18	0	VBD	constituted
9	O	19	0	DT	the
9	O	20	0	JJ	national
9	O	21	0	CC	and
9	O	22	0	JJ	cultural
9	O	23	0	NN	specificity
9	O	24	0	IN	of
9	MISC	25	0	JJ	Japanese
9	O	26	0	NN	cinema
9	O	27	0	,	,
9	O	28	0	''	'
9	O	29	0	IN	as
9	PERSON	30	0	NNP	Yoshimoto/Mitsuhiro
9	O	31	0	VBZ	argues
9	O	32	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
9	O	33	0	LS	1
9	O	34	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
9	O	35	0	.	.

10	PERSON	0	0	NNP	Kurosawa
10	O	1	0	POS	's
10	O	2	0	JJ	international
10	O	3	0	NN	fame
10	O	4	0	CC	and
10	O	5	0	NN	popularity
10	O	6	0	VBP	have
10	O	7	0	RB	always
10	O	8	0	VBN	gone
10	O	9	0	NN	side
10	O	10	0	IN	by
10	O	11	0	NN	side
10	O	12	0	IN	with
10	LOCATION	13	0	NNP	Japan
10	O	14	0	POS	's
10	O	15	0	NN	self-image
10	O	16	0	IN	toward
10	O	17	0	DT	the
10	LOCATION	18	0	NNP	West
10	O	19	0	CC	and
10	O	20	0	DT	the
10	LOCATION	21	0	NNP	West
10	O	22	0	POS	's
10	O	23	0	NN	use
10	O	24	0	IN	of
10	LOCATION	25	0	NNP	Japan
10	O	26	0	IN	as
10	O	27	0	DT	a
10	O	28	0	JJ	geo-political/geo-cultural
10	O	29	0	JJ	imaginary
10	O	30	0	NN	site.Trailer
10	O	31	0	:	:
10	PERSON	32	0	NN	Rashomon
10	O	33	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
10	O	34	0	CD	1950
10	O	35	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
10	O	36	0	.	.

11	O	0	0	DT	The
11	MISC	1	0	NNP	Criterion
11	O	2	0	NNP	Collection.Figure
11	O	3	0	CD	1
11	O	4	0	:	:
11	O	5	0	NNS	Permissions
11	O	6	0	RB	still
11	O	7	0	VBP	need
11	O	8	0	TO	to
11	O	9	0	VB	be
11	O	10	0	VBN	obtained
11	O	11	0	IN	for
11	O	12	0	DT	the
11	O	13	0	NN	use
11	O	14	0	IN	of
11	O	15	0	DT	this
11	O	16	0	NN	video.Born
11	O	17	0	IN	in
11	LOCATION	18	0	NNP	Tokyo
11	O	19	0	,	,
11	PERSON	20	0	NNP	Kurosawa
11	O	21	0	VBD	spent
11	O	22	0	PRP$	his
11	O	23	0	NN	youth
11	O	24	0	VBG	devouring
11	O	25	0	JJ	foreign
11	O	26	0	NN	literature
11	O	27	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
11	O	28	0	RB	especially
11	PERSON	29	0	NNP	Dostoyevsky
11	O	30	0	CC	and
11	PERSON	31	0	NNP	Tolstoy
11	O	32	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
11	O	33	0	CC	and
11	O	34	0	RB	also
11	O	35	0	VBG	attempting
11	O	36	0	TO	to
11	O	37	0	VB	train
11	O	38	0	PRP	himself
11	O	39	0	IN	as
11	O	40	0	DT	a
11	O	41	0	NN	painter
11	O	42	0	,	,
11	O	43	0	IN	although
11	O	44	0	PRP	he
11	O	45	0	RB	never
11	O	46	0	VBD	made
11	O	47	0	PRP	it
11	O	48	0	PRP$	his
11	O	49	0	NN	vocation
11	O	50	0	.	.

12	O	0	0	PRP$	His
12	O	1	0	NN	career
12	O	2	0	IN	as
12	O	3	0	DT	a
12	O	4	0	NN	filmmaker
12	O	5	0	VBD	started
12	O	6	0	WRB	when
12	O	7	0	PRP	he
12	O	8	0	VBD	joined
12	O	9	0	DT	the
12	ORGANIZATION	10	0	NNP	Photo/Chemical/Laboratories
12	O	11	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
12	O	12	0	NNP	P.C.L.
12	O	13	0	,	,
12	O	14	0	WDT	which
12	O	15	0	RB	later
12	O	16	0	VBD	became
12	O	17	0	DT	the
12	ORGANIZATION	18	0	NNP	Toho
12	O	19	0	NN	studio
12	O	20	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
12	O	21	0	IN	in
12	O	22	0	CD	1936
12	O	23	0	CC	and
12	O	24	0	VBD	worked
12	O	25	0	IN	under
12	PERSON	26	0	NNP	Yamamoto/Kajiro
12	O	27	0	IN	among
12	O	28	0	JJ	other
12	O	29	0	JJ	senior
12	O	30	0	NNS	directors
12	O	31	0	.	.

13	PERSON	0	0	NNP	Kurosawa
13	O	1	0	POS	's
13	O	2	0	JJ	theatrical
13	O	3	0	NN	debut
13	O	4	0	,	,
13	PERSON	5	0	NNP	Sugata/Sanshiro
13	O	6	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
13	PERSON	7	0	NNP	Sanshiro/Sugata
13	O	8	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
13	O	9	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
13	O	10	0	CD	1943
13	O	11	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
13	O	12	0	,	,
13	O	13	0	VBD	offered
13	O	14	0	JJ	action-packed
13	O	15	0	NNS	spectacles
13	O	16	0	VBG	featuring
13	O	17	0	DT	a
13	O	18	0	JJ	stubborn
13	O	19	0	RB	yet
13	O	20	0	JJ	honest
13	O	21	0	NN	youth
13	O	22	0	VBG	disciplining
13	O	23	0	PRP	himself
13	O	24	0	IN	through
13	PERSON	25	0	NNP	Judo
13	O	26	0	.	.

14	O	0	0	IN	While
14	O	1	0	DT	the
14	O	2	0	NN	narrative
14	O	3	0	VBZ	is
14	O	4	0	RB	quite
14	O	5	0	JJ	conventional
14	O	6	0	,	,
14	O	7	0	VBG	following
14	O	8	0	DT	the
14	O	9	0	JJ	popular
14	O	10	0	NN	swordfight
14	O	11	0	NN	genre
14	O	12	0	NN	formula
14	O	13	0	,	,
14	O	14	0	DT	the
14	O	15	0	NN	film
14	O	16	0	VBZ	exhibits
14	PERSON	17	0	NNP	Kurosawa
14	O	18	0	POS	's
14	O	19	0	NN	signature
14	O	20	0	JJ	filmic
14	O	21	0	NNS	forms
14	O	22	0	CC	and
14	O	23	0	NNS	techniques
14	O	24	0	,	,
14	O	25	0	VBG	including
14	O	26	0	JJ	stylised
14	O	27	0	NN	frame
14	O	28	0	NN	composition
14	O	29	0	CC	and
14	O	30	0	DT	the
14	O	31	0	NN	use
14	O	32	0	IN	of
14	O	33	0	DT	the
14	O	34	0	VBP	wipe
14	O	35	0	.	.

15	O	0	0	DT	The
15	O	1	0	JJ	on-going
15	O	2	0	NN	war
15	O	3	0	RB	greatly
15	O	4	0	VBD	affected
15	O	5	0	PRP$	his
15	O	6	0	NN	production
15	O	7	0	RB	as
15	O	8	0	RB	well
15	O	9	0	,	,
15	O	10	0	CC	and
15	O	11	0	PRP$	his
15	O	12	0	VBG	following
15	O	13	0	NN	feature
15	O	14	0	,	,
15	PERSON	15	0	NNP	Ichiban/Utsukushiku
15	O	16	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
15	O	17	0	DT	The
15	ORGANIZATION	18	0	JJ	Most/Beautiful
15	O	19	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
15	O	20	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
15	O	21	0	CD	1944
15	O	22	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
15	O	23	0	,	,
15	O	24	0	VBD	was
15	O	25	0	DT	a
15	O	26	0	JJ	national
15	O	27	0	NN	propaganda
15	O	28	0	NN	film
15	O	29	0	VBG	stressing
15	O	30	0	DT	the
15	O	31	0	NN	war
15	O	32	0	NN	effort
15	O	33	0	IN	by
15	O	34	0	DT	the
15	MISC	35	0	JJ	Japanese
15	O	36	0	.	.

16	O	0	0	IN	In
16	O	1	0	NN	contrast
16	O	2	0	,	,
16	O	3	0	PRP$	his
16	O	4	0	JJ	first
16	O	5	0	JJ	post-war
16	O	6	0	NN	film
16	O	7	0	,	,
16	PERSON	8	0	NNP	Waga
16	O	9	0	NN	seishun
16	O	10	0	NN	ni
16	O	11	0	NN	kuinashi
16	O	12	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
16	O	13	0	DT	No
16	O	14	0	NNS	Regrets
16	O	15	0	IN	for
16	O	16	0	PRP$	Our
16	O	17	0	NN	Youth
16	O	18	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
16	O	19	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
16	O	20	0	CD	1946
16	O	21	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
16	O	22	0	,	,
16	O	23	0	VBD	was
16	O	24	0	VBN	developed
16	O	25	0	IN	out
16	O	26	0	IN	of
16	O	27	0	DT	an
16	O	28	0	JJ	actual
16	O	29	0	NN	wartime
16	O	30	0	NN	incident
16	O	31	0	IN	as
16	O	32	0	DT	an
16	O	33	0	RB	explicitly
16	O	34	0	JJ	political
16	O	35	0	JJ	anti-militarist
16	O	36	0	NN	work
16	O	37	0	VBG	promoting
16	O	38	0	DT	a
16	O	39	0	JJ	democratic
16	O	40	0	NN	ethos
16	O	41	0	.	.

17	PERSON	0	0	NNP	Kurosawa
17	O	1	0	VBZ	has
17	O	2	0	VBN	been
17	O	3	0	RB	often
17	O	4	0	VBN	labelled
17	O	5	0	IN	as
17	O	6	0	DT	a
17	O	7	0	NN	director
17	O	8	0	IN	of
17	O	9	0	NN	jidaigeki
17	O	10	0	IN	in
17	O	11	0	JJ	large
17	O	12	0	NN	part
17	O	13	0	JJ	due
17	O	14	0	TO	to
17	O	15	0	DT	the
17	O	16	0	NN	legacy
17	O	17	0	IN	of
17	PERSON	18	0	NNP	Rashomon
17	O	19	0	CC	and
17	O	20	0	PRP$	his
17	O	21	0	JJ	other
17	O	22	0	NN	trademark
17	O	23	0	NN	samurai
17	O	24	0	NNS	films
17	O	25	0	,	,
17	O	26	0	RB	notably
17	PERSON	27	0	NNP	Shichinin
17	O	28	0	DT	no
17	O	29	0	NN	samurai
17	O	30	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
17	O	31	0	CD	Seven
17	O	32	0	NN	Samurai
17	O	33	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
17	O	34	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
17	O	35	0	CD	1954
17	O	36	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
17	O	37	0	:	--
17	O	38	0	RB	arguably
17	O	39	0	DT	the
17	O	40	0	RBS	most
17	O	41	0	JJ	popular
17	MISC	42	0	JJ	Japanese
17	O	43	0	NN	film
17	O	44	0	IN	of
17	O	45	0	DT	all
17	O	46	0	NN	time
17	O	47	0	:	--
17	O	48	0	RB	as
17	O	49	0	RB	well
17	O	50	0	IN	as
17	O	51	0	DT	the
17	O	52	0	NN	smash
17	O	53	0	VBZ	hits
17	PERSON	54	0	NNP	Yojinbo
17	O	55	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
17	O	56	0	NNP	Yojimbo
17	O	57	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
17	O	58	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
17	O	59	0	CD	1961
17	O	60	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
17	O	61	0	CC	and
17	PERSON	62	0	NNP	Tsubaki/Sanjuro/-LSB-/Sanjuro
17	O	63	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
17	O	64	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
17	O	65	0	CD	1962
17	O	66	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
17	O	67	0	.	.

18	O	0	0	RB	However
18	O	1	0	,	,
18	O	2	0	PRP	he
18	O	3	0	RB	also
18	O	4	0	VBD	directed
18	O	5	0	DT	a
18	O	6	0	NN	number
18	O	7	0	IN	of
18	O	8	0	NN	gendaigeki
18	O	9	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
18	O	10	0	JJ	contemporary
18	O	11	0	NN	drama
18	O	12	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
18	O	13	0	NNS	films
18	O	14	0	WDT	that
18	O	15	0	VBP	are
18	O	16	0	VBN	concerned
18	O	17	0	IN	with
18	O	18	0	DT	the
18	O	19	0	NNS	predicaments
18	O	20	0	IN	of
18	O	21	0	JJ	immediate
18	O	22	0	JJ	post-war
18	LOCATION	23	0	NNP	Japan
18	O	24	0	,	,
18	O	25	0	RB	especially
18	O	26	0	IN	in
18	LOCATION	27	0	NNP	Subarashiki
18	O	28	0	NN	nichiyobi
18	O	29	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
18	O	30	0	CD	One
18	O	31	0	JJ	Wonderful
18	O	32	0	NNP	Sunday
18	O	33	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
18	O	34	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
18	O	35	0	CD	1947
18	O	36	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
18	O	37	0	,	,
18	PERSON	38	0	NN	Yoidore
18	O	39	0	NN	tenshi
18	O	40	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
18	PERSON	41	0	NNP	Drunken/Angel
18	O	42	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
18	O	43	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
18	O	44	0	CD	1948
18	O	45	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
18	O	46	0	,	,
18	PERSON	47	0	NN	Shizukanaru
18	O	48	0	NN	ketto
18	O	49	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
18	O	50	0	JJ	Quiet
18	O	51	0	NN	Duel
18	O	52	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
18	O	53	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
18	O	54	0	CD	1949
18	O	55	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
18	O	56	0	,	,
18	O	57	0	CC	and
18	PERSON	58	0	NNP	Ikiru/-LSB-/Ikiru
18	O	59	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
18	O	60	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
18	O	61	0	CD	1952
18	O	62	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
18	O	63	0	,	,
18	O	64	0	WDT	which
18	O	65	0	VBD	brought
18	O	66	0	PRP	him
18	O	67	0	DT	another
18	O	68	0	NN	prize
18	O	69	0	IN	at
18	O	70	0	DT	the
18	LOCATION	71	0	NNP	Berlin/International/Film/Festival
18	O	72	0	IN	in
18	O	73	0	CD	1954
18	O	74	0	.	.

19	O	0	0	RB	Aesthetically
19	O	1	0	,	,
19	O	2	0	DT	the
19	O	3	0	JJ	filmic
19	O	4	0	NN	form
19	O	5	0	CC	and
19	O	6	0	NN	technique
19	O	7	0	IN	in
19	O	8	0	DT	these
19	O	9	0	NNS	films
19	O	10	0	VBZ	is
19	O	11	0	RB	highly
19	O	12	0	JJ	modern
19	O	13	0	,	,
19	O	14	0	JJ	stylised
19	O	15	0	IN	with
19	O	16	0	DT	the
19	O	17	0	NN	use
19	O	18	0	IN	of
19	O	19	0	NN	conflict
19	O	20	0	NN	montage
19	O	21	0	CC	and
19	O	22	0	JJ	contrapuntal
19	O	23	0	NN	insertion
19	O	24	0	IN	of
19	O	25	0	NN	music
19	O	26	0	.	.

20	O	0	0	RB	Thematically
20	O	1	0	,	,
20	O	2	0	VBD	underscored
20	O	3	0	IN	in
20	O	4	0	DT	those
20	O	5	0	NNS	films
20	O	6	0	VBZ	is
20	O	7	0	DT	a
20	O	8	0	RB	universally
20	O	9	0	JJ	appealing
20	O	10	0	JJ	humanist
20	O	11	0	NN	sensibility
20	O	12	0	WDT	that
20	O	13	0	VBZ	is
20	O	14	0	JJ	sympathetic
20	O	15	0	IN	toward
20	O	16	0	VBG	struggling
20	O	17	0	NNS	individuals
20	O	18	0	,	,
20	O	19	0	CD	one
20	O	20	0	WDT	that
20	O	21	0	NNS	echoes
20	MISC	22	0	NN	Italian/Neorealism
20	O	23	0	,	,
20	O	24	0	DT	a
20	O	25	0	JJ	contemporaneous
20	O	26	0	NN	movement
20	O	27	0	WDT	that
20	O	28	0	RB	cinematically
20	O	29	0	VBD	evoked
20	O	30	0	DT	the
20	O	31	0	NN	plight
20	O	32	0	CC	and
20	O	33	0	NN	frailty
20	O	34	0	IN	of
20	O	35	0	DT	the
20	O	36	0	JJ	human
20	O	37	0	NN	condition
20	O	38	0	IN	in
20	O	39	0	JJ	post-war
20	LOCATION	40	0	NNP	Italy
20	O	41	0	.	.

21	O	0	0	NNP	Trailer
21	O	1	0	:	:
21	MISC	2	0	NN	Seven/Samurai
21	O	3	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
21	O	4	0	CD	1954
21	O	5	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
21	O	6	0	.	.

22	O	0	0	DT	The
22	O	1	0	NNP	Criterion
22	O	2	0	NN	Collection.Figure
22	O	3	0	CD	2
22	O	4	0	:	:
22	O	5	0	NNS	Permissions
22	O	6	0	RB	still
22	O	7	0	VBP	need
22	O	8	0	TO	to
22	O	9	0	VB	be
22	O	10	0	VBN	obtained
22	O	11	0	IN	for
22	O	12	0	DT	the
22	O	13	0	NN	use
22	O	14	0	IN	of
22	O	15	0	DT	this
22	O	16	0	NN	video.In
22	O	17	0	PRP$	his
22	O	18	0	JJ	later
22	O	19	0	NNS	years
22	O	20	0	,	,
22	PERSON	21	0	NNP	Kurosawa
22	O	22	0	VBD	remained
22	O	23	0	RB	extremely
22	O	24	0	JJ	influential
22	O	25	0	CC	and
22	O	26	0	JJ	uncompromising
22	O	27	0	IN	with
22	O	28	0	JJ	such
22	O	29	0	JJ	ambitious
22	O	30	0	JJ	international
22	O	31	0	NNS	projects
22	O	32	0	IN	as
22	ORGANIZATION	33	0	NN	Kagemusha
22	O	34	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
22	ORGANIZATION	35	0	NN	Kagemusha
22	O	36	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
22	O	37	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
22	O	38	0	CD	1980
22	O	39	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
22	O	40	0	,	,
22	O	41	0	DT	a
22	O	42	0	JJ	historical
22	O	43	0	NN	epic
22	O	44	0	NN	film
22	O	45	0	WDT	that
22	O	46	0	VBD	claimed
22	O	47	0	DT	the
22	LOCATION	48	0	NNP	Palme
22	O	49	0	NN	d’Or
22	O	50	0	IN	at
22	LOCATION	51	0	NNP	Cannes
22	O	52	0	,	,
22	O	53	0	CC	and
22	O	54	0	NN	Ran
22	O	55	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
22	O	56	0	NN	Ran
22	O	57	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
22	O	58	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
22	O	59	0	CD	1985
22	O	60	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
22	O	61	0	,	,
22	O	62	0	DT	another
22	O	63	0	JJ	grand
22	O	64	0	NN	epic
22	O	65	0	VBG	revolving
22	O	66	0	IN	around
22	O	67	0	DT	a
22	O	68	0	NN	warlord
22	O	69	0	NN	character
22	O	70	0	RB	roughly
22	O	71	0	VBD	developed
22	O	72	0	IN	out
22	O	73	0	IN	of
22	PERSON	74	0	NNP	Shakespeare
22	O	75	0	POS	's
22	O	76	0	NNP	King
22	PERSON	77	0	NNP	Lear
22	O	78	0	.	.

23	O	0	0	IN	In
23	O	1	0	CD	1990
23	O	2	0	,	,
23	O	3	0	PRP	he
23	O	4	0	VBD	received
23	O	5	0	DT	a
23	O	6	0	NN	lifetime
23	O	7	0	NN	achievement
23	PERSON	8	0	NNP	Oscar
23	O	9	0	IN	at
23	O	10	0	DT	the
23	LOCATION	11	0	NNP	Academy
23	O	12	0	NN	Awards.List
23	O	13	0	IN	of
23	O	14	0	NNP	Works
23	O	15	0	:	:
23	PERSON	16	0	NNP	Sugata/Sanshiro
23	O	17	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
23	PERSON	18	0	NNP	Sanshiro/Sugata
23	O	19	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
23	O	20	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
23	O	21	0	CD	1943
23	O	22	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
23	LOCATION	23	0	NNP	Ichiban/Utsukushiku
23	O	24	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
23	O	25	0	DT	The
23	ORGANIZATION	26	0	JJ	Most/Beautiful
23	O	27	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
23	O	28	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	29	0	CD	1944
23	O	30	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	PERSON	31	0	NNP	Waga
23	O	32	0	NN	seishun
23	O	33	0	NN	ni
23	O	34	0	NN	kuinashi
23	O	35	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
23	O	36	0	DT	No
23	O	37	0	NNS	Regrets
23	O	38	0	IN	for
23	O	39	0	PRP$	Our
23	O	40	0	NN	Youth
23	O	41	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
23	O	42	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	43	0	CD	1946
23	O	44	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	ORGANIZATION	45	0	NN	Subarashiki
23	O	46	0	NN	nichiyobi
23	O	47	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
23	O	48	0	CD	One
23	O	49	0	JJ	Wonderful
23	O	50	0	NNP	Sunday
23	O	51	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
23	O	52	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	53	0	CD	1947
23	O	54	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	ORGANIZATION	55	0	NN	Yoidore
23	O	56	0	NN	tenshi
23	O	57	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
23	PERSON	58	0	NNP	Drunken/Angel
23	O	59	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
23	O	60	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	61	0	CD	1948
23	O	62	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	ORGANIZATION	63	0	NN	Shizukanaru
23	O	64	0	NN	ketto
23	O	65	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
23	O	66	0	JJ	Quiet
23	O	67	0	NN	Duel
23	O	68	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
23	O	69	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	70	0	CD	1949
23	O	71	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	ORGANIZATION	72	0	NN	Rashomon
23	O	73	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	74	0	CD	1950
23	O	75	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	ORGANIZATION	76	0	NNP	Ikiru
23	O	77	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
23	O	78	0	NNP	Ikiru
23	O	79	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
23	O	80	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	81	0	CD	1952
23	O	82	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	ORGANIZATION	83	0	NNP	Shichinin
23	O	84	0	DT	no
23	O	85	0	NN	samurai
23	O	86	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
23	O	87	0	CD	Seven
23	O	88	0	NN	Samurai
23	O	89	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
23	O	90	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	91	0	CD	1954
23	O	92	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	ORGANIZATION	93	0	NNP	Yojinbo
23	O	94	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
23	O	95	0	NNP	Yojimbo
23	O	96	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
23	O	97	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	98	0	CD	1961
23	O	99	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	PERSON	100	0	NNP	Tsubaki/Sanjuro
23	O	101	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
23	PERSON	102	0	NNP	Sanjuro
23	O	103	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
23	O	104	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	105	0	CD	1962
23	O	106	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	ORGANIZATION	107	0	NNP	Kagemusha
23	O	108	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
23	PERSON	109	0	NNP	Kagemusha
23	O	110	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
23	O	111	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	112	0	CD	1980
23	O	113	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	O	114	0	NN	Ran
23	O	115	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
23	O	116	0	NN	Ran
23	O	117	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
23	O	118	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	119	0	CD	1985
23	O	120	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	O	121	0	CD	-----------
23	PERSON	122	0	NNP	Zoku/Sanshiro/Sugata
23	O	123	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
23	ORGANIZATION	124	0	NNP	Sanshiro/Sugata/Part/II
23	O	125	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
23	O	126	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	127	0	CD	1945
23	O	128	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	O	129	0	NNP	Tora
23	O	130	0	DT	no
23	O	131	0	NN	o
23	O	132	0	MD	wo
23	O	133	0	VB	fumu
23	O	134	0	NN	otokotachi
23	O	135	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
23	O	136	0	DT	The
23	MISC	137	0	VB	Man/Who/Tread
23	O	138	0	IN	on
23	O	139	0	DT	the
23	ORGANIZATION	140	0	NNP	Tiger
23	O	141	0	POS	's
23	MISC	142	0	NN	Tail
23	O	143	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
23	O	144	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	145	0	CD	1945
23	O	146	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	PERSON	147	0	NNP	Nora
23	O	148	0	NN	inu
23	O	149	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
23	O	150	0	JJ	Stray
23	O	151	0	NN	Dog
23	O	152	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
23	O	153	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	154	0	CD	1949
23	O	155	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	ORGANIZATION	156	0	NNP	Skyandaru
23	O	157	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
23	O	158	0	NNP	Scandal
23	O	159	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
23	O	160	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	161	0	CD	1950
23	O	162	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	ORGANIZATION	163	0	NNP	Hakuchi
23	O	164	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
23	O	165	0	DT	The
23	O	166	0	NN	Idiot
23	O	167	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
23	O	168	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	169	0	CD	1951
23	O	170	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	ORGANIZATION	171	0	NNP	Ikimono
23	O	172	0	DT	no
23	O	173	0	NN	kiroku
23	O	174	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
23	O	175	0	NNP	Record
23	O	176	0	IN	of
23	O	177	0	DT	a
23	O	178	0	VBG	Living
23	O	179	0	VBG	Being
23	O	180	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
23	O	181	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	182	0	CD	1995
23	O	183	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	O	184	0	JJ	Kumonosu-jo
23	O	185	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
23	O	186	0	NN	Throne
23	O	187	0	IN	of
23	O	188	0	NN	Blood
23	O	189	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
23	O	190	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	191	0	CD	1957
23	O	192	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	ORGANIZATION	193	0	NNP	Donzoko
23	O	194	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
23	O	195	0	DT	The
23	O	196	0	JJR	Lower
23	O	197	0	NNS	Depths
23	O	198	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
23	O	199	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	200	0	CD	1957
23	O	201	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	LOCATION	202	0	NNP	Kakushi
23	O	203	0	IN	toride
23	O	204	0	DT	no
23	O	205	0	NN	san
23	O	206	0	NN	akunin
23	O	207	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
23	O	208	0	DT	The
23	ORGANIZATION	209	0	NNP	Hidden/Fortress
23	O	210	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
23	O	211	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	212	0	CD	1958
23	O	213	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	ORGANIZATION	214	0	NNP	Warui
23	O	215	0	NN	yatsu
23	O	216	0	NN	hodo
23	O	217	0	NN	yoku
23	O	218	0	NN	nemuru
23	O	219	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
23	O	220	0	DT	The
23	ORGANIZATION	221	0	NNP	Bad/Sleep/Well
23	O	222	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
23	O	223	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	224	0	CD	1960
23	O	225	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	ORGANIZATION	226	0	NNP	Tengoku
23	O	227	0	TO	to
23	O	228	0	VB	jigoku
23	O	229	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
23	O	230	0	JJ	High
23	O	231	0	CC	and
23	O	232	0	JJ	Low
23	O	233	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
23	O	234	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	235	0	CD	1963
23	O	236	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	ORGANIZATION	237	0	NNP	Akahige
23	O	238	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
23	ORGANIZATION	239	0	NNP	Red/Beard
23	O	240	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
23	O	241	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	242	0	CD	1965
23	O	243	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	ORGANIZATION	244	0	NN	Dodesukaden
23	O	245	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
23	PERSON	246	0	NN	Dodesukaden
23	O	247	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
23	O	248	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	249	0	CD	1970
23	O	250	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	PERSON	251	0	NNP	Derusu/Uzara
23	O	252	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
23	PERSON	253	0	NNP	Dersu/Uzala
23	O	254	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
23	O	255	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	256	0	CD	1975
23	O	257	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	LOCATION	258	0	NNP	Yume
23	O	259	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
23	O	260	0	NNS	Dreams
23	O	261	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
23	O	262	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	263	0	CD	1990
23	O	264	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	ORGANIZATION	265	0	NNP	Hachigatsu
23	O	266	0	DT	no
23	O	267	0	NN	rapusodi
23	O	268	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
23	PERSON	269	0	NNP	Rhapsody
23	O	270	0	IN	in
23	O	271	0	NNP	August
23	O	272	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
23	O	273	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	274	0	CD	1991
23	O	275	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	ORGANIZATION	276	0	NNP	Mādadayo
23	O	277	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
23	PERSON	278	0	NNP	Madadayo
23	O	279	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
23	O	280	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	281	0	CD	1993
23	O	282	0	-RRB-	-RRB-

0	LOCATION	0	0	NNP	Huxley
0	O	1	0	,	,
0	PERSON	2	0	NNP	Aldous
0	O	3	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
0	O	4	0	CD	1894-1963
0	O	5	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
0	O	6	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
0	O	7	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
0	LOCATION	8	0	NNP	Huxley
0	O	9	0	,	,
0	PERSON	10	0	NNP	Leonard/AldousAldous/Huxley
0	O	11	0	VBZ	is
0	O	12	0	RB	best
0	O	13	0	VBN	known
0	O	14	0	IN	for
0	O	15	0	PRP$	his
0	O	16	0	JJ	dystopian
0	O	17	0	JJ	novel
0	ORGANIZATION	18	0	NNP	Brave/New/World
0	O	19	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
0	O	20	0	CD	1932
0	O	21	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
0	O	22	0	,	,
0	O	23	0	CC	and
0	O	24	0	PRP$	his
0	O	25	0	NN	disquisition
0	O	26	0	IN	on
0	O	27	0	JJ	psychedelic
0	O	28	0	NNS	substances
0	O	29	0	,	,
0	ORGANIZATION	30	0	NN	The/Doors/of/Perception
0	O	31	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
0	O	32	0	CD	1954
0	O	33	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
0	O	34	0	.	.

1	O	0	0	IN	In
1	O	1	0	DT	the
1	O	2	0	JJ	inter-war
1	O	3	0	NNS	years
1	O	4	0	,	,
1	PERSON	5	0	NNP	Huxley
1	O	6	0	VBD	commanded
1	O	7	0	DT	a
1	O	8	0	JJ	formidable
1	O	9	0	NN	reputation
1	O	10	0	,	,
1	O	11	0	CC	and
1	O	12	0	PRP$	his
1	O	13	0	NN	work
1	O	14	0	VBD	was
1	O	15	0	VBN	considered
1	O	16	0	IN	alongside
1	O	17	0	DT	the
1	O	18	0	VBG	leading
1	O	19	0	NNS	modernists
1	O	20	0	.	.

2	O	0	0	PRP	He
2	O	1	0	VBD	was
2	O	2	0	RB	impressively
2	O	3	0	JJ	prolific
2	O	4	0	CC	and
2	O	5	0	VBD	wrote
2	O	6	0	IN	in
2	O	7	0	DT	a
2	O	8	0	NN	variety
2	O	9	0	IN	of
2	O	10	0	NNS	genres
2	O	11	0	,	,
2	O	12	0	VBG	producing
2	O	13	0	NN	poetry
2	O	14	0	,	,
2	O	15	0	JJ	short
2	O	16	0	NNS	stories
2	O	17	0	,	,
2	O	18	0	NNS	essays
2	O	19	0	,	,
2	O	20	0	NNS	novels
2	O	21	0	,	,
2	O	22	0	VBZ	plays
2	O	23	0	,	,
2	O	24	0	NN	biography
2	O	25	0	CC	and
2	O	26	0	NN	travel
2	O	27	0	NN	writing
2	O	28	0	.	.

3	O	0	0	PRP$	His
3	O	1	0	NN	work
3	O	2	0	VBD	appeared
3	O	3	0	IN	in
3	O	4	0	JJ	many
3	O	5	0	IN	of
3	O	6	0	DT	the
3	O	7	0	JJ	modernist
3	ORGANIZATION	8	0	NNS	Little/Magazines
3	O	9	0	,	,
3	O	10	0	JJ	such
3	O	11	0	IN	as
3	O	12	0	NNP	Coterie
3	O	13	0	,	,
3	ORGANIZATION	14	0	NNP	The/Egoist/and/Wheels
3	O	15	0	.	.

4	LOCATION	0	0	NNP	Huxley
4	O	1	0	VBD	was
4	O	2	0	DT	a
4	O	3	0	JJ	zealous
4	O	4	0	NN	individualist
4	O	5	0	:	:
4	O	6	0	IN	while
4	O	7	0	PRP	he
4	O	8	0	VBD	socialised
4	O	9	0	IN	with
4	PERSON	10	0	NNP	Virginia/Woolf
4	O	11	0	,	,
4	PERSON	12	0	NNP	Roger/Fry
4	O	13	0	CC	and
4	PERSON	14	0	NNP	Clive/Bell
4	O	15	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
4	O	16	0	IN	among
4	O	17	0	NNS	others
4	O	18	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
4	O	19	0	,	,
4	O	20	0	PRP	he
4	O	21	0	VBD	was
4	O	22	0	RB	never
4	O	23	0	NN	part
4	O	24	0	IN	of
4	O	25	0	DT	the
4	ORGANIZATION	26	0	NNP	Bloomsbury/Group
4	O	27	0	.	.

5	O	0	0	RB	Likewise
5	O	1	0	,	,
5	O	2	0	IN	though
5	O	3	0	DT	a
5	O	4	0	JJ	regular
5	O	5	0	NN	guest
5	O	6	0	IN	at
5	LOCATION	7	0	NNP	Garsington/Manor
5	O	8	0	,	,
5	O	9	0	DT	the
5	O	10	0	NN	home
5	O	11	0	IN	of
5	O	12	0	NN	society
5	O	13	0	NN	hostess
5	O	14	0	NNP	Lady
5	PERSON	15	0	NNP	Ottoline/Morrell
5	O	16	0	,	,
5	O	17	0	PRP	he
5	O	18	0	VBD	was
5	O	19	0	RB	not
5	O	20	0	VBN	regarded
5	O	21	0	IN	as
5	O	22	0	DT	a
5	O	23	0	NN	member
5	O	24	0	IN	of
5	O	25	0	PRP$	her
5	O	26	0	NN	pacifist
5	O	27	0	NN	coterie
5	O	28	0	WDT	that
5	O	29	0	VBD	included
5	PERSON	30	0	NNP	Lytton/Strachey
5	O	31	0	CC	and
5	PERSON	32	0	NNP	Bertrand/Russell
5	O	33	0	.	.

6	O	0	0	IN	After
6	O	1	0	VBG	moving
6	O	2	0	TO	to
6	LOCATION	3	0	NNP	America
6	O	4	0	,	,
6	PERSON	5	0	NNP	Huxley
6	O	6	0	VBD	became
6	O	7	0	RB	increasingly
6	O	8	0	VBN	concerned
6	O	9	0	IN	with
6	O	10	0	NN	mysticism
6	O	11	0	,	,
6	O	12	0	CC	and
6	O	13	0	PRP$	his
6	O	14	0	NN	reputation
6	O	15	0	VBD	declined
6	O	16	0	:	;
6	O	17	0	RB	however
6	O	18	0	,	,
6	O	19	0	DT	the
6	O	20	0	NN	work
6	O	21	0	PRP	he
6	O	22	0	VBD	produced
6	O	23	0	IN	during
6	O	24	0	DT	this
6	O	25	0	NN	period
6	O	26	0	VBD	was
6	O	27	0	VBN	championed
6	O	28	0	IN	by
6	O	29	0	JJ	key
6	O	30	0	NNS	figures
6	O	31	0	IN	in
6	O	32	0	DT	the
6	MISC	33	0	NNP	New/Age
6	O	34	0	CC	and
6	O	35	0	JJ	counter-culture
6	O	36	0	NNS	movements
6	O	37	0	,	,
6	O	38	0	CC	and
6	O	39	0	PRP	he
6	O	40	0	VBD	played
6	O	41	0	DT	a
6	O	42	0	JJ	vital
6	O	43	0	NN	part
6	O	44	0	IN	in
6	O	45	0	VBG	popularising
6	MISC	46	0	NNP	Eastern
6	O	47	0	NNS	religions
6	O	48	0	IN	in
6	O	49	0	DT	the
6	LOCATION	50	0	NNP	West
6	O	51	0	,	,
6	O	52	0	JJ	such
6	O	53	0	IN	as
6	MISC	54	0	NNP	Buddhism
6	O	55	0	,	,
6	ORGANIZATION	56	0	NNP	Tantra
6	O	57	0	CC	and
6	ORGANIZATION	58	0	NNP	Advaita
6	O	59	0	NNP	Vedanta.Aldous
6	LOCATION	60	0	NNP	Huxley
6	O	61	0	VBZ	is
6	O	62	0	RB	best
6	O	63	0	VBN	known
6	O	64	0	IN	for
6	O	65	0	PRP$	his
6	O	66	0	JJ	dystopian
6	O	67	0	JJ	novel
6	ORGANIZATION	68	0	NNP	Brave/New/World
6	O	69	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
6	O	70	0	CD	1932
6	O	71	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
6	O	72	0	,	,
6	O	73	0	CC	and
6	O	74	0	PRP$	his
6	O	75	0	NN	disquisition
6	O	76	0	IN	on
6	O	77	0	JJ	psychedelic
6	O	78	0	NNS	substances
6	O	79	0	,	,
6	ORGANIZATION	80	0	NN	The/Doors/of/Perception
6	O	81	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
6	O	82	0	CD	1954
6	O	83	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
6	O	84	0	.	.

7	O	0	0	IN	In
7	O	1	0	DT	the
7	O	2	0	JJ	inter-war
7	O	3	0	NNS	years
7	O	4	0	,	,
7	PERSON	5	0	NNP	Huxley
7	O	6	0	VBD	commanded
7	O	7	0	DT	a
7	O	8	0	JJ	formidable
7	O	9	0	NN	reputation
7	O	10	0	,	,
7	O	11	0	CC	and
7	O	12	0	PRP$	his
7	O	13	0	NN	work
7	O	14	0	VBD	was
7	O	15	0	VBN	considered
7	O	16	0	IN	alongside
7	O	17	0	DT	the
7	O	18	0	VBG	leading
7	O	19	0	NNS	modernists
7	O	20	0	.	.

8	O	0	0	PRP	He
8	O	1	0	VBD	was
8	O	2	0	RB	impressively
8	O	3	0	JJ	prolific
8	O	4	0	CC	and
8	O	5	0	VBD	wrote
8	O	6	0	IN	in
8	O	7	0	DT	a
8	O	8	0	NN	variety
8	O	9	0	IN	of
8	O	10	0	NNS	genres
8	O	11	0	,	,
8	O	12	0	VBG	producing
8	O	13	0	NN	poetry
8	O	14	0	,	,
8	O	15	0	JJ	short
8	O	16	0	NNS	stories
8	O	17	0	,	,
8	O	18	0	NNS	essays
8	O	19	0	,	,
8	O	20	0	NNS	novels
8	O	21	0	,	,
8	O	22	0	VBZ	plays
8	O	23	0	,	,
8	O	24	0	NN	biography
8	O	25	0	CC	and
8	O	26	0	NN	travel
8	O	27	0	NN	writing
8	O	28	0	.	.

9	O	0	0	PRP$	His
9	O	1	0	NN	work
9	O	2	0	VBD	appeared
9	O	3	0	IN	in
9	O	4	0	JJ	many
9	O	5	0	IN	of
9	O	6	0	DT	the
9	O	7	0	JJ	modernist
9	ORGANIZATION	8	0	NNS	Little/Magazines
9	O	9	0	,	,
9	O	10	0	JJ	such
9	O	11	0	IN	as
9	O	12	0	NNP	Coterie
9	O	13	0	,	,
9	ORGANIZATION	14	0	NNP	The/Egoist/and/Wheels
9	O	15	0	.	.

10	LOCATION	0	0	NNP	Huxley
10	O	1	0	VBD	was
10	O	2	0	DT	a
10	O	3	0	JJ	zealous
10	O	4	0	NN	individualist
10	O	5	0	:	:
10	O	6	0	IN	while
10	O	7	0	PRP	he
10	O	8	0	VBD	socialised
10	O	9	0	IN	with
10	PERSON	10	0	NNP	Virginia/Woolf
10	O	11	0	,	,
10	PERSON	12	0	NNP	Roger/Fry
10	O	13	0	CC	and
10	PERSON	14	0	NNP	Clive/Bell
10	O	15	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
10	O	16	0	IN	among
10	O	17	0	NNS	others
10	O	18	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
10	O	19	0	,	,
10	O	20	0	PRP	he
10	O	21	0	VBD	was
10	O	22	0	RB	never
10	O	23	0	NN	part
10	O	24	0	IN	of
10	O	25	0	DT	the
10	ORGANIZATION	26	0	NNP	Bloomsbury/Group
10	O	27	0	.	.

11	O	0	0	RB	Likewise
11	O	1	0	,	,
11	O	2	0	IN	though
11	O	3	0	DT	a
11	O	4	0	JJ	regular
11	O	5	0	NN	guest
11	O	6	0	IN	at
11	LOCATION	7	0	NNP	Garsington/Manor
11	O	8	0	,	,
11	O	9	0	DT	the
11	O	10	0	NN	home
11	O	11	0	IN	of
11	O	12	0	NN	society
11	O	13	0	NN	hostess
11	O	14	0	NNP	Lady
11	PERSON	15	0	NNP	Ottoline/Morrell
11	O	16	0	,	,
11	O	17	0	PRP	he
11	O	18	0	VBD	was
11	O	19	0	RB	not
11	O	20	0	VBN	regarded
11	O	21	0	IN	as
11	O	22	0	DT	a
11	O	23	0	NN	member
11	O	24	0	IN	of
11	O	25	0	PRP$	her
11	O	26	0	NN	pacifist
11	O	27	0	NN	coterie
11	O	28	0	WDT	that
11	O	29	0	VBD	included
11	PERSON	30	0	NNP	Lytton/Strachey
11	O	31	0	CC	and
11	PERSON	32	0	NNP	Bertrand/Russell
11	O	33	0	.	.

12	O	0	0	IN	After
12	O	1	0	VBG	moving
12	O	2	0	TO	to
12	LOCATION	3	0	NNP	America
12	O	4	0	,	,
12	PERSON	5	0	NNP	Huxley
12	O	6	0	VBD	became
12	O	7	0	RB	increasingly
12	O	8	0	VBN	concerned
12	O	9	0	IN	with
12	O	10	0	NN	mysticism
12	O	11	0	,	,
12	O	12	0	CC	and
12	O	13	0	PRP$	his
12	O	14	0	NN	reputation
12	O	15	0	VBD	declined
12	O	16	0	:	;
12	O	17	0	RB	however
12	O	18	0	,	,
12	O	19	0	DT	the
12	O	20	0	NN	work
12	O	21	0	PRP	he
12	O	22	0	VBD	produced
12	O	23	0	IN	during
12	O	24	0	DT	this
12	O	25	0	NN	period
12	O	26	0	VBD	was
12	O	27	0	VBN	championed
12	O	28	0	IN	by
12	O	29	0	JJ	key
12	O	30	0	NNS	figures
12	O	31	0	IN	in
12	O	32	0	DT	the
12	MISC	33	0	NNP	New/Age
12	O	34	0	CC	and
12	O	35	0	JJ	counter-culture
12	O	36	0	NNS	movements
12	O	37	0	,	,
12	O	38	0	CC	and
12	O	39	0	PRP	he
12	O	40	0	VBD	played
12	O	41	0	DT	a
12	O	42	0	JJ	vital
12	O	43	0	NN	part
12	O	44	0	IN	in
12	O	45	0	VBG	popularising
12	MISC	46	0	NNP	Eastern
12	O	47	0	NNS	religions
12	O	48	0	IN	in
12	O	49	0	DT	the
12	LOCATION	50	0	NNP	West
12	O	51	0	,	,
12	O	52	0	JJ	such
12	O	53	0	IN	as
12	MISC	54	0	NNP	Buddhism
12	O	55	0	,	,
12	ORGANIZATION	56	0	NNP	Tantra
12	O	57	0	CC	and
12	ORGANIZATION	58	0	NNP	Advaita
12	O	59	0	NNP	Vedanta.Aldous
12	LOCATION	60	0	NNP	Huxley
12	O	61	0	VBD	was
12	O	62	0	VBN	born
12	O	63	0	IN	on
12	O	64	0	CD	26
12	O	65	0	NNP	July
12	O	66	0	CD	1894
12	O	67	0	,	,
12	O	68	0	IN	near
12	LOCATION	69	0	NNP	Godalming
12	O	70	0	IN	in
12	LOCATION	71	0	NNP	Surrey
12	O	72	0	.	.

13	O	0	0	PRP	He
13	O	1	0	VBD	came
13	O	2	0	IN	from
13	O	3	0	DT	a
13	O	4	0	JJ	distinguished
13	O	5	0	JJ	intellectual
13	O	6	0	NN	lineage
13	O	7	0	:	:
13	O	8	0	PRP$	his
13	O	9	0	NN	grandfather
13	O	10	0	VBD	was
13	PERSON	11	0	NNP	T./H./Huxley
13	O	12	0	,	,
13	O	13	0	WP	who
13	O	14	0	VBD	was
13	O	15	0	VBN	nicknamed
13	O	16	0	``	`
13	PERSON	17	0	NNP	Darwin
13	O	18	0	POS	's
13	O	19	0	NN	bulldog
13	O	20	0	''	'
13	O	21	0	IN	for
13	O	22	0	PRP$	his
13	O	23	0	NN	advocacy
13	O	24	0	IN	of
13	O	25	0	JJ	evolutionary
13	O	26	0	NN	theory
13	O	27	0	:	;
13	O	28	0	CC	and
13	O	29	0	PRP$	his
13	O	30	0	NN	great-uncle
13	O	31	0	VBD	was
13	O	32	0	DT	the
13	O	33	0	NN	poet
13	O	34	0	CC	and
13	O	35	0	NN	critic
13	PERSON	36	0	NNP	Matthew/Arnold
13	O	37	0	.	.

14	O	0	0	PRP$	His
14	O	1	0	NN	childhood
14	O	2	0	VBD	was
14	O	3	0	VBN	marked
14	O	4	0	IN	by
14	O	5	0	CD	three
14	O	6	0	JJ	traumatic
14	O	7	0	NNS	episodes
14	O	8	0	WDT	that
14	O	9	0	VBD	helped
14	O	10	0	VB	shape
14	O	11	0	PRP	him
14	O	12	0	IN	as
14	O	13	0	DT	a
14	O	14	0	NN	writer
14	O	15	0	:	:
14	O	16	0	IN	in
14	O	17	0	CD	1908
14	O	18	0	,	,
14	O	19	0	PRP$	his
14	O	20	0	NN	mother
14	PERSON	21	0	NNP	Julia
14	O	22	0	VBD	died
14	O	23	0	IN	of
14	O	24	0	NN	cancer
14	O	25	0	:	;
14	O	26	0	CD	three
14	O	27	0	NNS	years
14	O	28	0	RB	later
14	O	29	0	,	,
14	O	30	0	IN	at
14	O	31	0	DT	the
14	O	32	0	NN	age
14	O	33	0	IN	of
14	O	34	0	CD	sixteen
14	O	35	0	,	,
14	O	36	0	PRP	he
14	O	37	0	VBD	contracted
14	O	38	0	DT	an
14	O	39	0	NN	eye
14	O	40	0	NN	infection
14	O	41	0	WDT	that
14	O	42	0	RB	permanently
14	O	43	0	VBD	impaired
14	O	44	0	PRP$	his
14	O	45	0	NN	eyesight
14	O	46	0	:	;
14	O	47	0	CC	and
14	O	48	0	IN	in
14	O	49	0	CD	1914
14	O	50	0	,	,
14	O	51	0	PRP$	his
14	O	52	0	NN	brother
14	PERSON	53	0	NNP	Trevenen
14	O	54	0	VBD	committed
14	O	55	0	NN	suicide
14	O	56	0	.	.

15	O	0	0	IN	After
15	O	1	0	VBG	attending
15	ORGANIZATION	2	0	NNP	Eton
15	O	3	0	,	,
15	LOCATION	4	0	NNP	Huxley
15	O	5	0	VBD	read
15	MISC	6	0	NNP	English
15	O	7	0	IN	at
15	ORGANIZATION	8	0	NNP	Balliol/College
15	O	9	0	,	,
15	ORGANIZATION	10	0	NNP	Oxford
15	O	11	0	.	.

16	O	0	0	PRP	He
16	O	1	0	VBD	attempted
16	O	2	0	TO	to
16	O	3	0	VB	enlist
16	O	4	0	IN	during
16	MISC	5	0	NNP	World/War/I
16	O	6	0	,	,
16	O	7	0	CC	but
16	O	8	0	VBD	was
16	O	9	0	VBN	rejected
16	O	10	0	JJ	due
16	O	11	0	TO	to
16	O	12	0	PRP$	his
16	O	13	0	JJ	poor
16	O	14	0	NN	eyesight
16	O	15	0	.	.

17	O	0	0	IN	Through
17	O	1	0	DT	the
17	O	2	0	NN	hospitality
17	O	3	0	IN	of
17	PERSON	4	0	NNP	Ottoline/Morrell
17	O	5	0	CC	and
17	O	6	0	PRP$	her
17	O	7	0	NN	husband
17	PERSON	8	0	NNP	Philip
17	O	9	0	,	,
17	PERSON	10	0	NNP	Huxley
17	O	11	0	VBD	met
17	O	12	0	JJ	many
17	O	13	0	JJ	eminent
17	O	14	0	NNS	artists
17	O	15	0	CC	and
17	O	16	0	NNS	intellectuals
17	O	17	0	,	,
17	O	18	0	RB	as
17	O	19	0	RB	well
17	O	20	0	IN	as
17	O	21	0	DT	the
17	MISC	22	0	JJ	Belgian
17	O	23	0	NN	refugee
17	PERSON	24	0	NNP	Maria/Nys
17	O	25	0	,	,
17	O	26	0	WP	whom
17	O	27	0	PRP	he
17	O	28	0	VBD	married
17	O	29	0	IN	in
17	O	30	0	CD	1919
17	O	31	0	.	.

18	O	0	0	PRP$	His
18	O	1	0	JJ	first
18	O	2	0	VBN	published
18	O	3	0	NN	book
18	O	4	0	VBD	was
18	O	5	0	DT	a
18	O	6	0	NN	volume
18	O	7	0	IN	of
18	O	8	0	NN	poetry
18	O	9	0	,	,
18	ORGANIZATION	10	0	NN	The/Burning/Wheel
18	O	11	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
18	O	12	0	CD	1916
18	O	13	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
18	O	14	0	.	.

19	O	0	0	IN	Despite
19	O	1	0	DT	the
19	O	2	0	JJ	modernist
19	O	3	0	NN	experimentation
19	O	4	0	IN	of
19	O	5	0	NNS	poets
19	O	6	0	JJ	such
19	O	7	0	IN	as
19	ORGANIZATION	8	0	NNP	Ezra/Pound
19	O	9	0	,	,
19	PERSON	10	0	NNP	Huxley
19	O	11	0	POS	's
19	O	12	0	NN	poetry
19	O	13	0	VBD	was
19	O	14	0	RB	fairly
19	O	15	0	JJ	conventional
19	O	16	0	CC	and
19	O	17	0	JJ	favoured
19	O	18	0	JJ	traditional
19	O	19	0	NNS	forms
19	O	20	0	.	.

20	ORGANIZATION	0	0	RB	Likewise
20	O	1	0	,	,
20	LOCATION	2	0	NNP	Huxley
20	O	3	0	POS	's
20	O	4	0	JJ	first
20	O	5	0	NN	novel
20	O	6	0	,	,
20	ORGANIZATION	7	0	NNP	Crome/Yellow
20	O	8	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
20	O	9	0	CD	1921
20	O	10	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
20	O	11	0	,	,
20	O	12	0	VBD	eschewed
20	O	13	0	DT	the
20	O	14	0	JJ	formal
20	O	15	0	NN	experimentation
20	O	16	0	IN	of
20	O	17	0	PRP$	his
20	O	18	0	JJ	modernist
20	O	19	0	NNS	contemporaries
20	O	20	0	CC	and
20	O	21	0	VBD	drew
20	O	22	0	NNS	comparisons
20	O	23	0	IN	with
20	O	24	0	DT	the
20	O	25	0	NN	work
20	O	26	0	IN	of
20	PERSON	27	0	NNP	Thomas/Love/Peacock
20	O	28	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
20	O	29	0	CD	1785-1866
20	O	30	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
20	O	31	0	.	.

21	O	0	0	IN	On
21	O	1	0	DT	the
21	O	2	0	JJ	other
21	O	3	0	NN	hand
21	O	4	0	,	,
21	PERSON	5	0	NNP	Huxley
21	O	6	0	POS	's
21	O	7	0	JJ	London-based
21	O	8	0	NNS	novels
21	O	9	0	IN	of
21	O	10	0	DT	the
21	O	11	0	CD	1920s
21	O	12	0	,	,
21	PERSON	13	0	NN	Antic/Hay
21	O	14	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
21	O	15	0	CD	1923
21	O	16	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
21	O	17	0	CC	and
21	O	18	0	NN	Point
21	O	19	0	NNP	Counter
21	O	20	0	NNP	Point
21	O	21	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
21	O	22	0	CD	1928
21	O	23	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
21	O	24	0	,	,
21	O	25	0	RB	vividly
21	O	26	0	VBN	captured
21	O	27	0	DT	the
21	O	28	0	JJ	post-war
21	O	29	0	NN	mood
21	O	30	0	IN	of
21	O	31	0	NN	anomie
21	O	32	0	,	,
21	O	33	0	NN	amorality
21	O	34	0	CC	and
21	O	35	0	JJ	empty
21	O	36	0	NN	hedonism
21	O	37	0	.	.

22	O	0	0	RB	Moreover
22	O	1	0	,	,
22	PERSON	2	0	NNP	Huxley
22	O	3	0	VBD	was
22	O	4	0	DT	a
22	O	5	0	NN	novelist
22	O	6	0	IN	of
22	O	7	0	NNS	ideas
22	O	8	0	WP$	whose
22	O	9	0	NN	work
22	O	10	0	VBZ	serves
22	O	11	0	IN	as
22	O	12	0	DT	a
22	O	13	0	NN	barometer
22	O	14	0	IN	of
22	O	15	0	DT	the
22	O	16	0	JJ	intellectual
22	O	17	0	NN	atmosphere
22	O	18	0	IN	of
22	O	19	0	PRP$	his
22	O	20	0	NN	era
22	O	21	0	.	.

23	O	0	0	IN	For
23	O	1	0	NN	instance
23	O	2	0	,	,
23	O	3	0	IN	in
23	O	4	0	PRP$	his
23	O	5	0	JJ	early
23	O	6	0	NN	work
23	O	7	0	PRP	he
23	O	8	0	VBD	satirised
23	O	9	0	NN	psychoanalysis
23	O	10	0	,	,
23	O	11	0	VBD	examined
23	O	12	0	DT	the
23	O	13	0	NN	impact
23	O	14	0	IN	of
23	O	15	0	NN	quantum
23	O	16	0	NNS	physics
23	O	17	0	,	,
23	O	18	0	VBD	deplored
23	O	19	0	DT	the
23	O	20	0	NN	standardisation
23	O	21	0	WDT	that
23	O	22	0	VBD	was
23	O	23	0	VBG	occurring
23	O	24	0	IN	in
23	O	25	0	NN	art
23	O	26	0	RB	as
23	O	27	0	RB	well
23	O	28	0	IN	as
23	O	29	0	NN	industry
23	O	30	0	,	,
23	O	31	0	VBN	explored
23	O	32	0	NN	mysticism
23	O	33	0	,	,
23	O	34	0	VBN	advocated
23	O	35	0	NNS	eugenics
23	O	36	0	,	,
23	O	37	0	CC	and
23	O	38	0	VBD	propounded
23	O	39	0	DT	a
23	O	40	0	NN	philosophy
23	O	41	0	RB	loosely
23	O	42	0	VBN	based
23	O	43	0	IN	on
23	O	44	0	DT	the
23	O	45	0	NNP	Weltanschauung
23	O	46	0	IN	of
23	O	47	0	PRP$	his
23	O	48	0	NN	friend
23	PERSON	49	0	NNP	D./H./Lawrence
23	O	50	0	.	.

24	LOCATION	0	0	NNP	Huxley
24	O	1	0	POS	's
24	O	2	0	JJ	classic
24	O	3	0	JJ	novel
24	ORGANIZATION	4	0	NNP	Brave/New/World
24	O	5	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
24	O	6	0	CD	1932
24	O	7	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
24	O	8	0	VBD	was
24	O	9	0	DT	a
24	O	10	0	JJ	baleful
24	O	11	0	NN	vision
24	O	12	0	IN	of
24	O	13	0	WP	what
24	O	14	0	DT	the
24	O	15	0	NN	world
24	O	16	0	MD	would
24	O	17	0	VB	look
24	O	18	0	IN	like
24	O	19	0	IN	if
24	O	20	0	DT	the
24	O	21	0	JJ	mechanistic
24	O	22	0	NNS	ideas
24	O	23	0	IN	of
24	PERSON	24	0	NNP	J./B./Watson
24	O	25	0	,	,
24	PERSON	26	0	NNP	Sigmund/Freud
24	O	27	0	,	,
24	PERSON	28	0	NNP	Henry/Ford
24	O	29	0	CC	and
24	PERSON	30	0	NNP	H./G./Wells
24	O	31	0	VBD	were
24	O	32	0	VBN	given
24	O	33	0	JJ	free
24	O	34	0	NN	reign
24	O	35	0	.	.

25	O	0	0	IN	In
25	O	1	0	CD	1934-35
25	O	2	0	,	,
25	ORGANIZATION	3	0	NNP	Huxley
25	O	4	0	VBD	suffered
25	O	5	0	IN	from
25	O	6	0	NN	insomnia
25	O	7	0	CC	and
25	O	8	0	NN	depression
25	O	9	0	CC	and
25	O	10	0	VBD	made
25	O	11	0	DT	some
25	O	12	0	JJ	decisive
25	O	13	0	NNS	changes
25	O	14	0	TO	to
25	O	15	0	PRP$	his
25	O	16	0	NN	life
25	O	17	0	IN	as
25	O	18	0	DT	a
25	O	19	0	NN	result
25	O	20	0	.	.

26	O	0	0	VBN	Encouraged
26	O	1	0	IN	by
26	O	2	0	PRP$	his
26	O	3	0	NN	friend
26	O	4	0	CC	and
26	O	5	0	JJ	fellow
26	O	6	0	NN	polymath
26	PERSON	7	0	NNP	Gerald/Heard
26	O	8	0	,	,
26	PERSON	9	0	NNP	Huxley
26	O	10	0	VBD	began
26	O	11	0	TO	to
26	O	12	0	VB	meditate
26	O	13	0	CC	and
26	O	14	0	VBD	joined
26	O	15	0	WP	what
26	O	16	0	MD	would
26	O	17	0	VB	become
26	O	18	0	DT	the
26	ORGANIZATION	19	0	NNP	Peace/Pledge/Union
26	O	20	0	.	.

27	O	0	0	VBG	Having
27	O	1	0	VBN	been
27	O	2	0	RB	alternately
27	O	3	0	VBN	attracted
27	O	4	0	CC	and
27	O	5	0	VBN	repelled
27	O	6	0	IN	by
27	O	7	0	NN	mysticism
27	O	8	0	IN	in
27	O	9	0	DT	the
27	O	10	0	CD	1920s
27	O	11	0	,	,
27	LOCATION	12	0	NNP	Huxley
27	O	13	0	VBD	began
27	O	14	0	TO	to
27	O	15	0	VB	espouse
27	O	16	0	DT	a
27	O	17	0	JJ	mystical
27	O	18	0	NN	philosophy
27	O	19	0	,	,
27	O	20	0	CC	both
27	O	21	0	IN	in
27	O	22	0	PRP$	his
27	O	23	0	NN	work
27	O	24	0	IN	with
27	O	25	0	DT	the
27	ORGANIZATION	26	0	NNP	Peace/Pledge/Union
27	O	27	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
27	O	28	0	IN	under
27	O	29	0	WP$	whose
27	O	30	0	NNS	auspices
27	O	31	0	PRP	he
27	O	32	0	VBD	wrote
27	O	33	0	DT	the
27	O	34	0	CD	1936
27	O	35	0	NN	pamphlet
27	O	36	0	WDT	What
27	O	37	0	VBP	Are
27	O	38	0	PRP	You
27	O	39	0	VBG	Going
27	O	40	0	TO	to
27	O	41	0	VB	Do
27	O	42	0	IN	About
27	O	43	0	PRP	It
27	O	44	0	.	?

28	O	0	0	DT	The
28	ORGANIZATION	1	0	NN	Case/for/Constructive/Peace
28	O	2	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
28	O	3	0	CC	and
28	O	4	0	IN	in
28	O	5	0	PRP$	his
28	O	6	0	NN	fiction
28	O	7	0	.	.

29	O	0	0	PRP	He
29	O	1	0	VBD	drew
29	O	2	0	IN	on
29	O	3	0	JJ	many
29	O	4	0	IN	of
29	O	5	0	DT	these
29	O	6	0	NNS	experiences
29	O	7	0	IN	in
29	O	8	0	PRP$	his
29	O	9	0	JJ	novel
29	O	10	0	JJ	Eyeless
29	O	11	0	IN	In
29	LOCATION	12	0	NNP	Gaza
29	O	13	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
29	O	14	0	CD	1936
29	O	15	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
29	O	16	0	,	,
29	O	17	0	WDT	which
29	O	18	0	NNS	charts
29	O	19	0	DT	the
29	O	20	0	JJ	spiritual
29	O	21	0	NN	journey
29	O	22	0	IN	of
29	PERSON	23	0	NNP	Anthony/Beavis
29	O	24	0	,	,
29	O	25	0	WP	who
29	O	26	0	VBZ	grows
29	O	27	0	VBN	disillusioned
29	O	28	0	IN	with
29	O	29	0	PRP$	his
29	O	30	0	JJ	cynical
29	O	31	0	NN	life
29	O	32	0	IN	of
29	O	33	0	JJ	loveless
29	O	34	0	NNS	affairs
29	O	35	0	CC	and
29	O	36	0	JJ	ivy-tower
29	O	37	0	NN	elitism
29	O	38	0	,	,
29	O	39	0	CC	and
29	O	40	0	VBZ	becomes
29	O	41	0	DT	an
29	O	42	0	NN	exponent
29	O	43	0	IN	of
29	O	44	0	NN	mysticism
29	O	45	0	CC	and
29	O	46	0	NN	pacifism.In
29	O	47	0	CD	1937
29	O	48	0	,	,
29	PERSON	49	0	NNP	Huxley
29	O	50	0	VBD	undertook
29	O	51	0	DT	a
29	O	52	0	NN	lecture
29	O	53	0	NN	tour
29	O	54	0	IN	of
29	LOCATION	55	0	NNP	America
29	O	56	0	CC	and
29	O	57	0	VBD	ended
29	O	58	0	RP	up
29	O	59	0	VBG	settling
29	O	60	0	IN	in
29	LOCATION	61	0	NNP	California
29	O	62	0	.	.

30	O	0	0	RB	Here
30	O	1	0	PRP	he
30	O	2	0	VBD	consolidated
30	O	3	0	PRP$	his
30	O	4	0	NN	knowledge
30	O	5	0	IN	of
30	MISC	6	0	NNP	Eastern
30	O	7	0	NN	mysticism
30	O	8	0	IN	through
30	O	9	0	PRP$	his
30	O	10	0	NN	association
30	O	11	0	IN	with
30	PERSON	12	0	NNP	Swami/Prabhavananda
30	O	13	0	,	,
30	O	14	0	DT	the
30	O	15	0	NN	head
30	O	16	0	IN	of
30	O	17	0	DT	the
30	ORGANIZATION	18	0	NNP	Vedanta/Society/for/Southern/California
30	O	19	0	,	,
30	O	20	0	CC	and
30	O	21	0	DT	the
30	MISC	22	0	JJ	Indian
30	O	23	0	NN	sage
30	O	24	0	CC	and
30	O	25	0	JJ	former
30	PERSON	26	0	NNP	Theosophist/Jiddu/Krishnamurti
30	O	27	0	.	.

31	O	0	0	PRP$	His
31	O	1	0	NN	fiction
31	O	2	0	VBD	became
31	O	3	0	DT	a
31	O	4	0	NN	vehicle
31	O	5	0	IN	for
31	O	6	0	PRP$	his
31	O	7	0	JJ	mystical
31	O	8	0	NNS	insights
31	O	9	0	,	,
31	O	10	0	RBS	most
31	O	11	0	RB	notably
31	O	12	0	IN	After
31	O	13	0	JJ	Many
31	O	14	0	DT	a
31	O	15	0	NN	Summer
31	O	16	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
31	O	17	0	CD	1939
31	O	18	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
31	O	19	0	,	,
31	ORGANIZATION	20	0	VB	Time/Must/Have
31	O	21	0	DT	a
31	O	22	0	NN	Stop
31	O	23	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
31	O	24	0	CD	1944
31	O	25	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
31	O	26	0	CC	and
31	MISC	27	0	NN	The/Genius
31	O	28	0	CC	and
31	O	29	0	DT	the
31	MISC	30	0	NN	Goddess
31	O	31	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
31	O	32	0	CD	1954
31	O	33	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
31	O	34	0	.	.

32	O	0	0	PRP	He
32	O	1	0	RB	also
32	O	2	0	VBD	wrote
32	O	3	0	DT	a
32	O	4	0	NN	biography
32	O	5	0	IN	of
32	O	6	0	DT	the
32	MISC	7	0	NNP	Catholic
32	O	8	0	NNP	mystic
32	O	9	0	NNP	Father
32	PERSON	10	0	NNP	Joseph
32	O	11	0	,	,
32	PERSON	12	0	NNP	Grey/Eminence
32	O	13	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
32	O	14	0	CD	1941
32	O	15	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
32	O	16	0	,	,
32	O	17	0	CC	and
32	O	18	0	DT	a
32	O	19	0	NN	book
32	O	20	0	IN	about
32	O	21	0	DT	the
32	O	22	0	NN	demonisation
32	O	23	0	IN	of
32	O	24	0	DT	the
32	O	25	0	JJ	seventeenth-century
32	O	26	0	NN	priest
32	PERSON	27	0	NNP	Urbain/Grandier
32	O	28	0	,	,
32	O	29	0	DT	The
32	ORGANIZATION	30	0	NNP	Devils/of/Loudon
32	O	31	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
32	O	32	0	CD	1952
32	O	33	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
32	O	34	0	.	.

33	O	0	0	IN	In
33	O	1	0	CD	1945
33	O	2	0	,	,
33	PERSON	3	0	NNP	Huxley
33	O	4	0	VBD	published
33	O	5	0	DT	an
33	O	6	0	NN	anthology
33	O	7	0	IN	of
33	O	8	0	JJ	mystical
33	O	9	0	NNS	writings
33	O	10	0	,	,
33	ORGANIZATION	11	0	NN	The/Perennial/Philosophy
33	O	12	0	,	,
33	O	13	0	IN	in
33	O	14	0	WDT	which
33	O	15	0	PRP	he
33	O	16	0	VBD	argued
33	O	17	0	IN	that
33	O	18	0	IN	while
33	O	19	0	NNS	mystics
33	O	20	0	IN	from
33	O	21	0	DT	the
33	MISC	22	0	NNP	Christian
33	O	23	0	,	,
33	MISC	24	0	NNP	Buddhist
33	O	25	0	,	,
33	MISC	26	0	NNP	Hindu
33	O	27	0	CC	and
33	MISC	28	0	JJ	Sufi
33	O	29	0	NNS	traditions
33	O	30	0	VBN	conceived
33	O	31	0	IN	of
33	PERSON	32	0	NNP	God
33	O	33	0	RB	differently
33	O	34	0	,	,
33	O	35	0	PRP$	their
33	O	36	0	NNS	experiences
33	O	37	0	IN	of
33	O	38	0	NN	union
33	O	39	0	IN	with
33	O	40	0	DT	the
33	O	41	0	NN	godhead
33	O	42	0	,	,
33	O	43	0	CC	or
33	O	44	0	WP	what
33	PERSON	45	0	NNP	Huxley
33	O	46	0	VBD	termed
33	O	47	0	DT	the
33	ORGANIZATION	48	0	NNP	Divine/Ground
33	O	49	0	,	,
33	O	50	0	CC	and
33	O	51	0	DT	the
33	O	52	0	NNS	insights
33	O	53	0	PRP	they
33	O	54	0	VBD	derived
33	O	55	0	IN	from
33	O	56	0	DT	this
33	O	57	0	,	,
33	O	58	0	VBD	were
33	O	59	0	RB	essentially
33	O	60	0	DT	the
33	O	61	0	JJ	same
33	O	62	0	.	.

34	O	0	0	IN	For
34	LOCATION	1	0	NNP	Huxley
34	O	2	0	,	,
34	O	3	0	DT	this
34	O	4	0	VBN	constituted
34	O	5	0	JJ	empirical
34	O	6	0	NN	evidence
34	O	7	0	IN	that
34	O	8	0	EX	there
34	O	9	0	VBD	was
34	O	10	0	DT	a
34	O	11	0	VBN	unified
34	O	12	0	JJ	metaphysical
34	O	13	0	NN	realm
34	O	14	0	IN	beyond
34	O	15	0	DT	the
34	O	16	0	JJ	phenomenal
34	O	17	0	NN	world
34	O	18	0	IN	of
34	O	19	0	NN	diversity
34	O	20	0	.	.

35	O	0	0	PRP$	His
35	O	1	0	NNS	experiments
35	O	2	0	IN	with
35	O	3	0	NN	mescaline
35	O	4	0	CC	and
35	ORGANIZATION	5	0	NN	LSD
35	O	6	0	VBD	were
35	O	7	0	VBN	conducted
35	O	8	0	IN	in
35	O	9	0	NN	order
35	O	10	0	TO	to
35	O	11	0	VB	apprehend
35	O	12	0	DT	this
35	O	13	0	JJ	metaphysical
35	O	14	0	NN	dimension
35	O	15	0	IN	for
35	O	16	0	PRP	himself
35	O	17	0	.	.

36	O	0	0	DT	The
36	O	1	0	NNS	books
36	ORGANIZATION	2	0	NN	The/Doors/of/Perception
36	O	3	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
36	O	4	0	CD	1954
36	O	5	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
36	O	6	0	CC	and
36	PERSON	7	0	NNP	Heaven
36	O	8	0	CC	and
36	PERSON	9	0	NNP	Hell
36	O	10	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
36	O	11	0	CD	1956
36	O	12	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
36	O	13	0	NN	record
36	O	14	0	PRP$	his
36	O	15	0	JJ	psychedelic
36	O	16	0	NNS	experiences
36	O	17	0	CC	and
36	O	18	0	DT	the
36	O	19	0	NNS	conclusions
36	O	20	0	PRP	he
36	O	21	0	VBD	drew
36	O	22	0	IN	from
36	O	23	0	PRP	them
36	O	24	0	.	.

37	O	0	0	IN	Despite
37	PERSON	1	0	NNP	Huxley
37	O	2	0	POS	's
37	O	3	0	NN	commitment
37	O	4	0	TO	to
37	O	5	0	NN	mysticism
37	O	6	0	,	,
37	O	7	0	PRP	he
37	O	8	0	RB	never
37	O	9	0	VBD	abandoned
37	O	10	0	PRP$	his
37	O	11	0	NN	faith
37	O	12	0	IN	in
37	O	13	0	NN	science
37	O	14	0	,	,
37	O	15	0	CC	and
37	O	16	0	IN	in
37	O	17	0	PRP$	his
37	O	18	0	JJ	later
37	O	19	0	NN	work
37	O	20	0	,	,
37	O	21	0	JJ	such
37	O	22	0	IN	as
37	O	23	0	NN	Island
37	O	24	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
37	O	25	0	CD	1962
37	O	26	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
37	O	27	0	CC	and
37	ORGANIZATION	28	0	NN	Literature/and/Science
37	O	29	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
37	O	30	0	CD	1963
37	O	31	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
37	O	32	0	,	,
37	O	33	0	PRP	he
37	O	34	0	VBD	argued
37	O	35	0	IN	that
37	O	36	0	IN	if
37	O	37	0	PRP	we
37	O	38	0	VBP	want
37	O	39	0	TO	to
37	O	40	0	VB	realise
37	O	41	0	PRP$	our
37	O	42	0	``	`
37	O	43	0	JJ	human
37	O	44	0	NNS	potentialities
37	O	45	0	POS	'
37	O	46	0	PRP	we
37	O	47	0	VBP	need
37	O	48	0	TO	to
37	O	49	0	VB	embrace
37	O	50	0	DT	both
37	O	51	0	.	.

38	O	0	0	NNP	Huxley
38	O	1	0	VBD	died
38	O	2	0	IN	of
38	O	3	0	NN	throat
38	O	4	0	NN	cancer
38	O	5	0	IN	on
38	O	6	0	DT	the
38	O	7	0	NN	day
38	O	8	0	IN	of
38	PERSON	9	0	NNP	John/F./Kennedy
38	O	10	0	POS	's
38	O	11	0	NN	assassination
38	O	12	0	,	,
38	O	13	0	CD	22
38	O	14	0	NNP	November
38	O	15	0	CD	1963
38	O	16	0	.	.

39	O	0	0	PRP$	His
39	O	1	0	NNS	essays
39	O	2	0	VBP	have
39	O	3	0	VBN	been
39	O	4	0	VBN	collected
39	O	5	0	IN	in
39	O	6	0	DT	the
39	ORGANIZATION	7	0	NNS	Complete/Essays
39	O	8	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	9	0	CD	6
39	O	10	0	NN	vols.
39	O	11	0	,	,
39	O	12	0	CD	2000-02
39	O	13	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	O	14	0	,	,
39	O	15	0	VBN	edited
39	O	16	0	IN	by
39	PERSON	17	0	NNP	James/Sexton
39	O	18	0	CC	and
39	PERSON	19	0	NNP	Robert/S./Baker
39	O	20	0	:	;
39	O	21	0	CC	and
39	O	22	0	CD	two
39	O	23	0	JJ	separate
39	O	24	0	NNS	volumes
39	O	25	0	IN	of
39	O	26	0	PRP$	his
39	O	27	0	NN	correspondence
39	O	28	0	VBP	have
39	O	29	0	VBN	been
39	O	30	0	VBN	published
39	O	31	0	,	,
39	O	32	0	VBN	edited
39	O	33	0	IN	by
39	PERSON	34	0	NNP	Grover/Smith
39	O	35	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	36	0	CD	1969
39	O	37	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	O	38	0	CC	and
39	PERSON	39	0	NNP	James/Sexton
39	O	40	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	41	0	CD	2007
39	O	42	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	O	43	0	NN	respectively.List
39	O	44	0	IN	of
39	O	45	0	NNP	Works
39	O	46	0	:	:
39	O	47	0	NNP	NovelsCrome
39	O	48	0	NNP	Yellow
39	O	49	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	50	0	CD	1921
39	O	51	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	PERSON	52	0	NN	Antic/Hay
39	O	53	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	54	0	CD	1923
39	O	55	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	O	56	0	DT	Those
39	PERSON	57	0	NNS	Barren/Leaves
39	O	58	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	59	0	CD	1925
39	O	60	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	O	61	0	NN	Point
39	O	62	0	NNP	Counter
39	O	63	0	NNP	Point
39	O	64	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	65	0	CD	1928
39	O	66	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	ORGANIZATION	67	0	NNP	Brave/New/World
39	O	68	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	69	0	CD	1932
39	O	70	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	ORGANIZATION	71	0	JJ	Eyeless
39	O	72	0	IN	in
39	LOCATION	73	0	NNP	Gaza
39	O	74	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	75	0	CD	1936
39	O	76	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	O	77	0	IN	After
39	O	78	0	JJ	Many
39	O	79	0	DT	a
39	O	80	0	NN	Summer
39	O	81	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	82	0	CD	1939
39	O	83	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	O	84	0	NNP	Time
39	O	85	0	MD	Must
39	O	86	0	VB	Have
39	O	87	0	DT	a
39	O	88	0	NN	Stop
39	O	89	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	90	0	CD	1944
39	O	91	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	ORGANIZATION	92	0	NN	Ape
39	O	93	0	CC	and
39	ORGANIZATION	94	0	NN	Essence
39	O	95	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	96	0	CD	1948
39	O	97	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	O	98	0	DT	The
39	MISC	99	0	NN	Genius
39	O	100	0	CC	and
39	O	101	0	DT	the
39	MISC	102	0	NN	Goddess
39	O	103	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	104	0	CD	1954
39	O	105	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	O	106	0	NN	Island
39	O	107	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	108	0	CD	1962
39	O	109	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	O	110	0	NNP	Short
39	PERSON	111	0	NNP	Story/CollectionsLimbo
39	O	112	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	113	0	CD	1920
39	O	114	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	ORGANIZATION	115	0	NNS	Mortal/Coils
39	O	116	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	117	0	CD	1922
39	O	118	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	O	119	0	JJ	Little
39	MISC	120	0	JJ	Mexican
39	O	121	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	122	0	CD	1924
39	O	123	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	O	124	0	CD	Two
39	O	125	0	CC	or
39	O	126	0	CD	Three
39	O	127	0	NNS	Graces
39	O	128	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	129	0	CD	1926
39	O	130	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	ORGANIZATION	131	0	NNS	Brief/Candles
39	O	132	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	133	0	CD	1930
39	O	134	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	ORGANIZATION	135	0	NN	PoetryThe/Burning/Wheel
39	O	136	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	137	0	CD	1916
39	O	138	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	PERSON	139	0	NNP	Jonah
39	O	140	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	141	0	CD	1917
39	O	142	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	O	143	0	DT	The
39	ORGANIZATION	144	0	NNP	Defeat/of/Youth
39	O	145	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	146	0	CD	1918
39	O	147	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	PERSON	148	0	NNP	Leda
39	O	149	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	150	0	CD	1920
39	O	151	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	PERSON	152	0	NNP	Arabia/Infelix
39	O	153	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	154	0	CD	1929
39	O	155	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	ORGANIZATION	156	0	NNP	The/Cicadas
39	O	157	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	158	0	CD	1931
39	O	159	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	ORGANIZATION	160	0	NN	BiographyGrey/Eminence
39	O	161	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	162	0	CD	1941
39	O	163	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	O	164	0	DT	The
39	ORGANIZATION	165	0	NNP	Devils/of/Loudon
39	O	166	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	167	0	CD	1952
39	O	168	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	O	169	0	NNP	Travel
39	O	170	0	NNP	WritingAlong
39	O	171	0	DT	the
39	MISC	172	0	NNP	Road
39	O	173	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	174	0	CD	1925
39	O	175	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	PERSON	176	0	NNP	Jesting/Pilate
39	O	177	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	178	0	CD	1926
39	O	179	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	O	180	0	IN	Beyond
39	O	181	0	DT	the
39	MISC	182	0	NNP	Mexique/Bay
39	O	183	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	184	0	CD	1934
39	O	185	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	ORGANIZATION	186	0	NNPS	Anthologies/Texts
39	O	187	0	CC	and
39	O	188	0	NNPS	Pretexts
39	O	189	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	190	0	CD	1932
39	O	191	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	O	192	0	DT	The
39	ORGANIZATION	193	0	NN	Perennial/Philosophy
39	O	194	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	195	0	CD	1945
39	O	196	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	ORGANIZATION	197	0	NNP	EssaysOn
39	O	198	0	DT	the
39	O	199	0	NN	Margin
39	O	200	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	201	0	CD	1923
39	O	202	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	O	203	0	JJ	Proper
39	O	204	0	NNS	Studies
39	O	205	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	206	0	CD	1927
39	O	207	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	O	208	0	VBP	Do
39	O	209	0	WP	What
39	PERSON	210	0	MD	You/Will
39	O	211	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	212	0	CD	1929
39	O	213	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	O	214	0	NNP	Music
39	O	215	0	IN	at
39	O	216	0	NNP	Night
39	O	217	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	218	0	CD	1931
39	O	219	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	O	220	0	DT	The
39	ORGANIZATION	221	0	NN	Olive/Tree
39	O	222	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	223	0	CD	1936
39	O	224	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	O	225	0	NNS	Themes
39	O	226	0	CC	and
39	O	227	0	NNS	Variations
39	O	228	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	229	0	CD	1950
39	O	230	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	ORGANIZATION	231	0	NNP	Adonis
39	O	232	0	CC	and
39	O	233	0	DT	the
39	O	234	0	NN	Alphabet
39	O	235	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	236	0	CD	1956
39	O	237	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	MISC	238	0	NNP	Brave/New/World/Revisited
39	O	239	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	240	0	CD	1958
39	O	241	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	O	242	0	NNP	Non-Fiction
39	PERSON	243	0	NNPS	BooksEnds
39	O	244	0	CC	and
39	O	245	0	NNP	Means
39	O	246	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	247	0	CD	1937
39	O	248	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	O	249	0	DT	The
39	O	250	0	NN	Art
39	O	251	0	IN	of
39	O	252	0	VBG	Seeing
39	O	253	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	254	0	CD	1942
39	O	255	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	ORGANIZATION	256	0	NN	The/Doors/of/Perception
39	O	257	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	258	0	CD	1954
39	O	259	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	ORGANIZATION	260	0	NNP	Heaven
39	O	261	0	CC	and
39	PERSON	262	0	NNP	Hell
39	O	263	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	264	0	CD	1956
39	O	265	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	ORGANIZATION	266	0	NNP	Literature/and/Science
39	O	267	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	268	0	CD	1963
39	O	269	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	MISC	270	0	NNP	DramaThe/World/of/Light
39	O	271	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	272	0	CD	1931
39	O	273	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	ORGANIZATION	274	0	NNP	Posthumous/Books/Letters/of/Aldous/Huxley
39	O	275	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	276	0	CD	1969
39	O	277	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	O	278	0	DT	The
39	MISC	279	0	NN	Human/Situation
39	O	280	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	281	0	CD	1978
39	O	282	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	ORGANIZATION	283	0	NNP	Aldous/Huxley
39	O	284	0	POS	's
39	ORGANIZATION	285	0	NNPS	Hearst/Essays
39	O	286	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	287	0	CD	1994
39	O	288	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	O	289	0	DT	The
39	LOCATION	290	0	NNP	Hidden/Huxley
39	O	291	0	:	:
39	O	292	0	NNP	Contempt
39	O	293	0	CC	and
39	O	294	0	NNP	Compassion
39	O	295	0	IN	for
39	O	296	0	DT	the
39	ORGANIZATION	297	0	NNP	Masses
39	O	298	0	CD	1920-36
39	O	299	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	300	0	CD	1994
39	O	301	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	PERSON	302	0	NNP	Jacob
39	O	303	0	POS	's
39	O	304	0	NNS	Hands
39	O	305	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	306	0	CD	1998
39	O	307	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	O	308	0	RB	Now
39	O	309	0	JJR	More
39	O	310	0	IN	than
39	O	311	0	RB	Ever
39	O	312	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
39	O	313	0	CD	2000
39	O	314	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
39	LOCATION	315	0	NNP	Aldous/Huxley
39	O	316	0	:	:
39	ORGANIZATION	317	0	NNS	Complete/Essays
39	O	318	0	,	,
39	O	319	0	CD	6
39	ORGANIZATION	320	0	NNS	Vols
39	O	321	0	.	.

40	O	0	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
40	O	1	0	CD	2000-02
40	O	2	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
40	O	3	0	VBN	Selected
40	O	4	0	NNS	Letters
40	O	5	0	IN	of
40	LOCATION	6	0	NNP	Aldous/Huxley
40	O	7	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
40	O	8	0	CD	2007
40	O	9	0	-RRB-	-RRB-

0	O	0	0	NN	Animation
0	O	1	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
0	O	2	0	VB	Enter
0	O	3	0	DT	any
0	O	4	0	JJ	variant
0	O	5	0	NNS	forms
0	O	6	0	IN	of
0	O	7	0	PRP$	your
0	O	8	0	NN	headword
0	O	9	0	:	--
0	O	10	0	NN	OPTIONAL
0	O	11	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
0	O	12	0	IN	Unlike
0	O	13	0	JJ	live-action
0	O	14	0	NN	film
0	O	15	0	,	,
0	O	16	0	WDT	which
0	O	17	0	VBZ	records
0	O	18	0	NN	motion
0	O	19	0	,	,
0	O	20	0	NN	animation
0	O	21	0	VBZ	creates
0	O	22	0	DT	the
0	O	23	0	NN	illusion
0	O	24	0	IN	of
0	O	25	0	NN	motion
0	O	26	0	IN	from
0	O	27	0	JJ	static
0	O	28	0	NN	imagery
0	O	29	0	.	.

1	O	0	0	JJ	Animated
1	O	1	0	NNS	films
1	O	2	0	VBP	are
1	O	3	0	VBN	made
1	O	4	0	VBG	using
1	O	5	0	DT	a
1	O	6	0	NN	variety
1	O	7	0	IN	of
1	O	8	0	NNS	techniques
1	O	9	0	,	,
1	O	10	0	JJ	such
1	O	11	0	IN	as
1	O	12	0	NN	cel
1	O	13	0	NN	animation
1	O	14	0	,	,
1	O	15	0	VBN	modified
1	O	16	0	NN	base
1	O	17	0	,	,
1	O	18	0	JJ	direct
1	O	19	0	NN	animation
1	O	20	0	,	,
1	O	21	0	NNS	cutouts
1	O	22	0	,	,
1	O	23	0	NN	stop-motion
1	O	24	0	,	,
1	O	25	0	NN	rotoscoping
1	O	26	0	,	,
1	O	27	0	NN	motion
1	O	28	0	NN	capture
1	O	29	0	,	,
1	O	30	0	CC	and
1	O	31	0	NN	computer
1	O	32	0	NNS	graphics
1	O	33	0	.	.

2	O	0	0	VBG	Dating
2	O	1	0	RB	back
2	O	2	0	TO	to
2	O	3	0	DT	the
2	O	4	0	JJ	early
2	O	5	0	CD	1900s
2	O	6	0	,	,
2	O	7	0	DT	the
2	O	8	0	NN	art
2	O	9	0	IN	of
2	O	10	0	NN	animation
2	O	11	0	VBZ	has
2	O	12	0	VBN	evolved
2	O	13	0	IN	with
2	O	14	0	DT	the
2	O	15	0	NN	help
2	O	16	0	IN	of
2	O	17	0	JJ	key
2	O	18	0	JJ	technological
2	O	19	0	NNS	advances
2	O	20	0	VBG	including
2	O	21	0	DT	the
2	O	22	0	NN	cel
2	O	23	0	NN	process
2	O	24	0	,	,
2	O	25	0	DT	the
2	O	26	0	JJ	multiplane
2	O	27	0	NN	camera
2	O	28	0	,	,
2	O	29	0	CC	and
2	O	30	0	NN	computer
2	O	31	0	NN	animation
2	O	32	0	NN	software
2	O	33	0	.	.

3	O	0	0	NN	Today
3	O	1	0	,	,
3	O	2	0	NN	animation
3	O	3	0	VBZ	plays
3	O	4	0	DT	an
3	O	5	0	RB	increasingly
3	O	6	0	JJ	prominent
3	O	7	0	NN	role
3	O	8	0	IN	in
3	LOCATION	9	0	NNP	Hollywood
3	O	10	0	NN	cinema
3	O	11	0	,	,
3	O	12	0	IN	as
3	O	13	0	JJ	many
3	O	14	0	JJ	live-action
3	O	15	0	NNS	features
3	O	16	0	VBP	rely
3	O	17	0	RB	heavily
3	O	18	0	IN	on
3	O	19	0	JJ	visual
3	O	20	0	NNS	effects
3	O	21	0	.	.

4	O	0	0	IN	In
4	O	1	0	DT	the
4	LOCATION	2	0	NNP	USA
4	O	3	0	,	,
4	O	4	0	DT	the
4	O	5	0	NN	history
4	O	6	0	IN	of
4	O	7	0	NN	animation
4	O	8	0	VBZ	is
4	O	9	0	RB	closely
4	O	10	0	VBN	tied
4	O	11	0	IN	with
4	O	12	0	DT	the
4	O	13	0	JJ	industrial
4	O	14	0	NN	model
4	O	15	0	CC	and
4	O	16	0	JJ	naturalistic
4	O	17	0	NNS	aesthetics
4	O	18	0	VBN	favoured
4	O	19	0	IN	by
4	PERSON	20	0	NNP	Walt/Disney
4	O	21	0	NNS	studios
4	O	22	0	,	,
4	O	23	0	RB	as
4	O	24	0	RB	well
4	O	25	0	IN	as
4	O	26	0	IN	with
4	O	27	0	DT	the
4	O	28	0	JJ	seven-minute
4	O	29	0	NN	screwball
4	O	30	0	NN	comedy
4	O	31	0	NN	cartoon
4	O	32	0	VBN	popularised
4	O	33	0	IN	by
4	ORGANIZATION	34	0	NNP	MGM
4	O	35	0	CC	and
4	PERSON	36	0	NNP	Warner/Bros.
4	O	37	0	.	.

5	O	0	0	IN	In
5	LOCATION	1	0	NNP	Europe
5	O	2	0	,	,
5	O	3	0	DT	the
5	O	4	0	JJ	large
5	O	5	0	NN	studio
5	O	6	0	NN	model
5	O	7	0	RB	never
5	O	8	0	VBD	gained
5	O	9	0	DT	a
5	O	10	0	NN	foothold
5	O	11	0	:	;
5	O	12	0	RB	instead
5	O	13	0	,	,
5	O	14	0	JJ	independent
5	O	15	0	NNS	animators
5	O	16	0	VBD	thrived
5	O	17	0	CC	and
5	O	18	0	VBD	produced
5	O	19	0	RB	stylistically
5	O	20	0	JJ	innovative
5	O	21	0	,	,
5	O	22	0	JJ	experimental
5	O	23	0	,	,
5	O	24	0	CC	and
5	O	25	0	RB	oftentimes
5	O	26	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
5	O	27	0	RB	especially
5	O	28	0	IN	in
5	O	29	0	DT	the
5	O	30	0	NN	case
5	O	31	0	IN	of
5	LOCATION	32	0	NNP	Eastern/Europe
5	O	33	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
5	O	34	0	RB	politically
5	O	35	0	JJ	subversive
5	O	36	0	NNS	films
5	O	37	0	.	.
