0	O	0	0	-LRB-	-LCB-
0	O	1	0	NN	\
0	O	2	0	NN	rtf1
0	O	3	0	CD	\
0	O	4	0	NNS	ansi
0	O	5	0	VBP	\
0	O	6	0	NN	ansicpg1252
0	O	7	0	CD	\
0	O	8	0	NN	cocoartf1404
0	O	9	0	CD	\
0	O	10	0	NN	cocoasubrtf130
0	O	11	0	-LRB-	-LCB-
0	O	12	0	NN	\
0	O	13	0	NN	fonttbl
0	O	14	0	CD	\
0	O	15	0	NN	f0
0	O	16	0	CD	\
0	O	17	0	NN	fnil
0	O	18	0	CD	\
0	O	19	0	NN	fcharset0
0	LOCATION	20	0	NNP	Cambria
0	O	21	0	:	;
0	O	22	0	CD	\
0	O	23	0	NN	f1
0	O	24	0	CD	\
0	O	25	0	NN	froman
0	O	26	0	CD	\
0	O	27	0	NN	fcharset0
0	O	28	0	NN	TimesNewRomanPSMT
0	O	29	0	:	;
0	O	30	0	-RRB-	-RCB-
0	O	31	0	-LRB-	-LCB-
0	O	32	0	CD	\
0	O	33	0	NN	colortbl
0	O	34	0	:	;
0	O	35	0	CD	\
0	O	36	0	NN	red255
0	O	37	0	CD	\
0	O	38	0	NN	green255
0	O	39	0	CD	\
0	O	40	0	NN	blue255
0	O	41	0	:	;
0	O	42	0	-RRB-	-RCB-
0	O	43	0	SYM	\
0	O	44	0	CD	margl1440
0	O	45	0	CD	\
0	O	46	0	NN	margr1440
0	O	47	0	CD	\
0	O	48	0	NN	vieww10800
0	O	49	0	CD	\
0	O	50	0	NN	viewh8400
0	O	51	0	CD	\
0	O	52	0	NN	viewkind0
0	O	53	0	CD	\
0	O	54	0	NN	deftab720
0	O	55	0	CD	\
0	O	56	0	NN	pard
0	O	57	0	CD	\
0	O	58	0	NN	pardeftab720
0	O	59	0	CD	\
0	O	60	0	NN	ri720
0	O	61	0	CD	\
0	O	62	0	NN	partightenfactor0
0	O	63	0	CD	\
0	O	64	0	NN	f0
0	O	65	0	CD	\
0	O	66	0	NN	fs24
0	O	67	0	CD	\
0	O	68	0	JJ	cf0
0	PERSON	69	0	NNP	Art/Deco
0	O	70	0	VBD	was
0	O	71	0	DT	the
0	O	72	0	JJ	predominant
0	O	73	0	JJ	decorative
0	O	74	0	NN	style
0	O	75	0	IN	in
0	LOCATION	76	0	NNP	Europe
0	O	77	0	CC	and
0	O	78	0	DT	the
0	LOCATION	79	0	NNPS	United/States
0	O	80	0	IN	between
0	O	81	0	DT	the
0	MISC	82	0	NNS	World/Wars
0	O	83	0	,	,
0	O	84	0	IN	with
0	O	85	0	PRP$	its
0	O	86	0	NN	peak
0	O	87	0	IN	of
0	O	88	0	NN	consumer
0	O	89	0	NN	popularity
0	O	90	0	VBN	reached
0	O	91	0	IN	during
0	O	92	0	DT	the
0	O	93	0	NNS	late-1920s
0	O	94	0	.	.

1	O	0	0	DT	The
1	O	1	0	JJ	new
1	O	2	0	NN	style
1	O	3	0	CC	and
1	O	4	0	VBG	accompanying
1	O	5	0	NN	attitude
1	O	6	0	VBD	were
1	O	7	0	JJ	synonymous
1	O	8	0	IN	with
1	O	9	0	VBG	being
1	O	10	0	NN	\
1	O	11	0	''	'
1	O	12	0	JJ	91modern
1	O	13	0	NN	\
1	O	14	0	CD	'92
1	O	15	0	IN	as
1	O	16	0	DT	the
1	O	17	0	NN	design
1	O	18	0	CC	and
1	O	19	0	NN	appearance
1	O	20	0	IN	of
1	LOCATION	21	0	NNP	Art/Deco
1	O	22	0	NNS	objects
1	O	23	0	VBD	incorporated
1	O	24	0	DT	a
1	O	25	0	JJ	unique
1	O	26	0	CC	and
1	O	27	0	JJ	new
1	O	28	0	NN	vocabulary
1	O	29	0	IN	of
1	O	30	0	NNS	forms
1	O	31	0	VBG	reflecting
1	O	32	0	DT	the
1	O	33	0	NNS	complexities
1	O	34	0	CC	and
1	O	35	0	NNS	innovations
1	O	36	0	IN	of
1	O	37	0	DT	the
1	O	38	0	JJ	emergent
1	O	39	0	JJ	twentieth-century
1	O	40	0	,	,
1	O	41	0	IN	with
1	O	42	0	DT	this
1	O	43	0	NN	period
1	O	44	0	RB	also
1	O	45	0	VBN	known
1	O	46	0	IN	as
1	O	47	0	DT	the
1	MISC	48	0	NN	Jazz/Age
1	O	49	0	CC	and
1	O	50	0	DT	the
1	LOCATION	51	0	NNP	Roaring/Twenties
1	O	52	0	.	.

2	PERSON	0	0	NNP	Art/Deco
2	O	1	0	VBZ	is
2	O	2	0	VBN	associated
2	O	3	0	IN	with
2	O	4	0	DT	the
2	O	5	0	JJ	hedonistic
2	O	6	0	VB	abandon
2	O	7	0	IN	of
2	O	8	0	DT	a
2	O	9	0	JJ	post-war
2	O	10	0	NN	society
2	O	11	0	WDT	that
2	O	12	0	VBD	was
2	O	13	0	VBN	determined
2	O	14	0	TO	to
2	O	15	0	VB	enjoy
2	O	16	0	NN	life
2	O	17	0	RB	once
2	O	18	0	RB	again
2	O	19	0	,	,
2	O	20	0	IN	while
2	O	21	0	DT	the
2	O	22	0	NN	consumer
2	O	23	0	VB	embrace
2	O	24	0	IN	of
2	O	25	0	RB	newly
2	O	26	0	VBN	designed
2	O	27	0	NNS	products
2	O	28	0	WDT	that
2	O	29	0	VBD	popularized
2	PERSON	30	0	NNP	Art/Deco
2	O	31	0	VBZ	reflects
2	O	32	0	DT	the
2	O	33	0	JJ	dramatic
2	O	34	0	JJ	social
2	O	35	0	NNS	changes
2	O	36	0	CC	and
2	O	37	0	JJ	technological
2	O	38	0	NNS	advancements
2	O	39	0	VBG	happening
2	O	40	0	IN	throughout
2	O	41	0	DT	this
2	O	42	0	NN	period
2	O	43	0	.	.

3	O	0	0	NN	\
3	O	1	0	CD	\
3	PERSON	2	0	NNP	Art/Deco
3	O	3	0	NN	style
3	O	4	0	VBZ	is
3	O	5	0	VBN	characterized
3	O	6	0	IN	by
3	O	7	0	PRP$	its
3	O	8	0	NN	preference
3	O	9	0	IN	for
3	O	10	0	VBN	simplified
3	O	11	0	JJ	geometric
3	O	12	0	NNS	forms
3	O	13	0	CC	and
3	O	14	0	JJ	stylized
3	O	15	0	JJ	natural
3	O	16	0	NNS	forms
3	O	17	0	,	,
3	O	18	0	VBG	including
3	O	19	0	NNS	flowers
3	O	20	0	,	,
3	O	21	0	NNS	animals
3	O	22	0	,	,
3	O	23	0	CC	and
3	O	24	0	JJ	female
3	O	25	0	NNS	figures
3	O	26	0	IN	in
3	O	27	0	PRP$	its
3	O	28	0	NNS	decorations
3	O	29	0	,	,
3	O	30	0	IN	with
3	O	31	0	DT	these
3	O	32	0	NNS	motifs
3	O	33	0	VBD	applied
3	O	34	0	TO	to
3	O	35	0	NNS	objects
3	O	36	0	IN	in
3	O	37	0	DT	every
3	O	38	0	NN	area
3	O	39	0	IN	of
3	O	40	0	NN	architecture
3	O	41	0	,	,
3	O	42	0	NN	furniture
3	O	43	0	,	,
3	O	44	0	JJ	industrial
3	O	45	0	NN	design
3	O	46	0	,	,
3	O	47	0	DT	the
3	O	48	0	JJ	decorative
3	O	49	0	NNS	arts
3	O	50	0	,	,
3	O	51	0	NN	fashion
3	O	52	0	,	,
3	O	53	0	NN	jewelry
3	O	54	0	,	,
3	O	55	0	NNS	graphics
3	O	56	0	,	,
3	O	57	0	NN	bookbinding
3	O	58	0	,	,
3	O	59	0	NN	glassware
3	O	60	0	,	,
3	O	61	0	CC	and
3	O	62	0	NNS	ceramics
3	O	63	0	.	.

4	O	0	0	IN	As
4	O	1	0	DT	a
4	O	2	0	NN	style
4	O	3	0	,	,
4	O	4	0	PRP	it
4	O	5	0	VBZ	is
4	O	6	0	VBN	known
4	O	7	0	RB	primarily
4	O	8	0	IN	for
4	O	9	0	PRP$	its
4	O	10	0	NN	opulence
4	O	11	0	IN	in
4	O	12	0	NNS	materials
4	O	13	0	CC	and
4	O	14	0	NN	sense
4	O	15	0	IN	of
4	O	16	0	NN	glamour
4	O	17	0	,	,
4	O	18	0	NN	luxury
4	O	19	0	,	,
4	O	20	0	CC	and
4	O	21	0	NN	prosperity
4	O	22	0	,	,
4	O	23	0	IN	with
4	O	24	0	CD	one
4	O	25	0	IN	of
4	O	26	0	PRP$	its
4	O	27	0	RBS	most
4	O	28	0	VBG	defining
4	O	29	0	NNS	features
4	O	30	0	VBG	being
4	O	31	0	DT	the
4	O	32	0	JJ	streamlined
4	O	33	0	NN	curve
4	O	34	0	IN	in
4	O	35	0	DT	the
4	O	36	0	NN	shape
4	O	37	0	IN	of
4	O	38	0	JJ	many
4	O	39	0	IN	of
4	O	40	0	PRP$	its
4	O	41	0	NNS	objects
4	O	42	0	.	.

5	O	0	0	DT	The
5	MISC	1	0	NNP	Art/Deco
5	O	2	0	NN	synthesis
5	O	3	0	IN	of
5	O	4	0	JJ	decorative
5	O	5	0	NNS	elements
5	O	6	0	VBN	brought
5	O	7	0	RB	together
5	O	8	0	JJ	geometric
5	O	9	0	CC	and
5	O	10	0	JJ	exotic
5	O	11	0	NNS	shapes
5	O	12	0	,	,
5	O	13	0	JJ	luxurious
5	O	14	0	NNS	materials
5	O	15	0	,	,
5	O	16	0	JJ	bold
5	O	17	0	NN	color
5	O	18	0	,	,
5	O	19	0	CC	and
5	O	20	0	VBN	heightened
5	O	21	0	NN	aestheticism
5	O	22	0	.	.

6	ORGANIZATION	0	0	NNP	Certain/Art/Deco
6	O	1	0	NNS	motifs
6	O	2	0	RB	also
6	O	3	0	VBD	reflected
6	O	4	0	JJ	popular
6	O	5	0	JJ	geographic
6	O	6	0	NNS	interests
6	O	7	0	IN	at
6	O	8	0	DT	the
6	O	9	0	NN	time
6	O	10	0	.	.

7	O	0	0	NNP	Zigzags
7	O	1	0	,	,
7	O	2	0	VBD	stepped
7	O	3	0	JJ	pyramidal
7	O	4	0	NNS	forms
7	O	5	0	,	,
7	O	6	0	CC	and
7	O	7	0	NNS	sunbursts
7	O	8	0	VBD	were
7	O	9	0	VBN	inspired
7	O	10	0	IN	by
7	O	11	0	DT	the
7	MISC	12	0	NNP	Near/Eastern
7	O	13	0	CC	and
7	MISC	14	0	JJ	Aztec
7	O	15	0	NNS	cultures
7	O	16	0	,	,
7	O	17	0	CC	and
7	O	18	0	IN	by
7	O	19	0	DT	the
7	O	20	0	NN	interest
7	O	21	0	VBN	generated
7	O	22	0	IN	from
7	O	23	0	DT	the
7	O	24	0	JJ	recent
7	O	25	0	NNS	discoveries
7	O	26	0	IN	in
7	LOCATION	27	0	NNP	Egypt
7	O	28	0	IN	in
7	O	29	0	DT	the
7	O	30	0	CD	1920s
7	O	31	0	,	,
7	O	32	0	VBG	including
7	O	33	0	NNP	King
7	PERSON	34	0	NNP	Tutankhamen
7	O	35	0	NN	\
7	O	36	0	''	'
7	O	37	0	NNS	92s
7	O	38	0	NN	tomb
7	O	39	0	.	.

8	PERSON	0	0	NNP	Art/Deco
8	O	1	0	NNS	designers
8	O	2	0	VBD	continued
8	O	3	0	TO	to
8	O	4	0	VB	mine
8	O	5	0	DT	the
8	MISC	6	0	JJ	French
8	O	7	0	NNS	styles
8	O	8	0	IN	from
8	O	9	0	DT	the
8	O	10	0	NN	past
8	O	11	0	IN	for
8	O	12	0	JJ	traditional
8	O	13	0	NNS	elements
8	O	14	0	WDT	that
8	O	15	0	VBD	contributed
8	O	16	0	DT	a
8	O	17	0	NN	sense
8	O	18	0	IN	of
8	MISC	19	0	JJ	Classical
8	O	20	0	NN	restraint
8	O	21	0	CC	and
8	O	22	0	NN	grandeur
8	O	23	0	IN	with
8	O	24	0	JJ	elegant
8	O	25	0	NNS	proportions
8	O	26	0	CC	and
8	O	27	0	JJ	stylized
8	O	28	0	JJ	natural
8	O	29	0	NNS	motifs
8	O	30	0	IN	of
8	O	31	0	NNS	figures
8	O	32	0	,	,
8	O	33	0	JJ	floral
8	O	34	0	NNS	garlands
8	O	35	0	,	,
8	O	36	0	CC	and
8	O	37	0	NNS	cornucopias
8	O	38	0	.	.

9	O	0	0	CC	But
9	O	1	0	,	,
9	O	2	0	IN	like
9	ORGANIZATION	3	0	NNP	Art/Nouveau
9	O	4	0	,	,
9	O	5	0	WDT	which
9	O	6	0	PRP	it
9	O	7	0	VBD	replaced
9	O	8	0	IN	in
9	O	9	0	NN	popularity
9	O	10	0	,	,
9	PERSON	11	0	NNP	Art/Deco
9	O	12	0	IN	as
9	O	13	0	DT	a
9	O	14	0	NN	style
9	O	15	0	VBD	was
9	O	16	0	RB	thoroughly
9	O	17	0	VBN	engaged
9	O	18	0	IN	with
9	O	19	0	WP	what
9	O	20	0	VBD	was
9	O	21	0	JJ	current
9	O	22	0	CC	and
9	O	23	0	WP	what
9	O	24	0	PRP	it
9	O	25	0	VBD	meant
9	O	26	0	TO	to
9	O	27	0	VB	be
9	O	28	0	JJ	modern
9	O	29	0	.	.

10	O	0	0	NN	\
10	O	1	0	CD	\
10	O	2	0	DT	The
10	O	3	0	NNS	collaborations
10	O	4	0	IN	among
10	O	5	0	NNS	artists
10	O	6	0	,	,
10	O	7	0	NNS	designers
10	O	8	0	,	,
10	O	9	0	CC	and
10	O	10	0	NN	fashion
10	O	11	0	NNS	designers
10	O	12	0	VBD	led
10	O	13	0	TO	to
10	O	14	0	DT	some
10	O	15	0	IN	of
10	O	16	0	DT	the
10	O	17	0	RBS	most
10	O	18	0	JJ	innovative
10	O	19	0	CC	and
10	O	20	0	JJ	interesting
10	O	21	0	NNS	examples
10	O	22	0	IN	of
10	LOCATION	23	0	NNP	Art/Deco
10	O	24	0	NNS	ensembles
10	O	25	0	,	,
10	O	26	0	JJ	such
10	O	27	0	IN	as
10	O	28	0	DT	the
10	O	29	0	JJ	tribal
10	O	30	0	NN	theme
10	O	31	0	NN	d
10	O	32	0	CD	\
10	O	33	0	``	`
10	O	34	0	NN	e9cor
10	O	35	0	VBN	made
10	O	36	0	IN	by
10	PERSON	37	0	NNP	Eileen/Gray
10	O	38	0	,	,
10	PERSON	39	0	NNP	Paul/Iribe
10	O	40	0	,	,
10	O	41	0	CC	and
10	PERSON	42	0	NNP	Pierre/Legrain
10	O	43	0	IN	for
10	O	44	0	DT	the
10	O	45	0	NN	home
10	O	46	0	IN	of
10	O	47	0	JJ	successful
10	O	48	0	NN	couturier
10	PERSON	49	0	NNP	Jacques/Doucet
10	O	50	0	,	,
10	O	51	0	CC	or
10	O	52	0	DT	the
10	O	53	0	NN	textile
10	O	54	0	NNS	designs
10	O	55	0	IN	by
10	O	56	0	DT	the
10	O	57	0	NN	artist
10	PERSON	58	0	NNP	Raoul/Dufy
10	O	59	0	IN	for
10	O	60	0	DT	the
10	O	61	0	NN	fashion
10	O	62	0	NN	designer
10	PERSON	63	0	NNP	Paul/Poiret
10	O	64	0	.	.

11	O	0	0	RBR	More
11	O	1	0	JJ	moderate
11	O	2	0	NNS	versions
11	O	3	0	IN	of
11	O	4	0	DT	these
11	O	5	0	JJ	lavish
11	O	6	0	NNS	interiors
11	O	7	0	VBD	were
11	O	8	0	RB	soon
11	O	9	0	JJ	available
11	O	10	0	IN	from
11	O	11	0	DT	the
11	O	12	0	NN	design
11	O	13	0	NNS	studios
11	O	14	0	VBN	affiliated
11	O	15	0	IN	with
11	O	16	0	DT	the
11	O	17	0	VBG	leading
11	O	18	0	NN	department
11	O	19	0	NNS	stores
11	O	20	0	IN	in
11	LOCATION	21	0	NNP	Paris
11	O	22	0	,	,
11	O	23	0	VBG	including
11	LOCATION	24	0	NNP	Lafayette
11	O	25	0	,	,
11	PERSON	26	0	NNP	Le/Bon
11	O	27	0	NNP	March
11	O	28	0	CD	\
11	O	29	0	``	`
11	O	30	0	NN	e9
11	O	31	0	,	,
11	O	32	0	CC	and
11	PERSON	33	0	NNP	Printemps
11	O	34	0	,	,
11	O	35	0	DT	all
11	O	36	0	IN	of
11	O	37	0	WDT	which
11	O	38	0	VBN	employed
11	O	39	0	VBG	leading
11	O	40	0	NNS	designers
11	O	41	0	,	,
11	O	42	0	JJ	such
11	O	43	0	IN	as
11	PERSON	44	0	NNP	Paul/Follot
11	O	45	0	,	,
11	PERSON	46	0	NNP	Ren
11	O	47	0	NNP	\
11	O	48	0	``	`
11	O	49	0	VBD	e9
11	PERSON	50	0	NNP	Prou
11	O	51	0	,	,
11	O	52	0	CC	and
11	PERSON	53	0	NNP	Maurice/Defr
11	O	54	0	CD	\
11	O	55	0	``	`
11	O	56	0	NN	e8ne
11	O	57	0	,	,
11	O	58	0	TO	to
11	O	59	0	VB	create
11	O	60	0	NNS	designs
11	O	61	0	WDT	that
11	O	62	0	MD	would
11	O	63	0	VB	appeal
11	O	64	0	TO	to
11	O	65	0	DT	the
11	O	66	0	NN	mass
11	O	67	0	NN	public
11	O	68	0	VBG	seeking
11	O	69	0	DT	the
11	O	70	0	JJ	same
11	O	71	0	JJ	elegant
11	O	72	0	NN	sophistication
11	O	73	0	JJ	available
11	O	74	0	TO	to
11	O	75	0	JJ	wealthy
11	O	76	0	NNS	connoisseurs
11	O	77	0	.	.

12	O	0	0	NN	\
12	O	1	0	CD	\
12	MISC	2	0	NNP	French
12	O	3	0	NNP	Art
12	PERSON	4	0	NNP	Deco
12	O	5	0	IN	in
12	O	6	0	JJ	particular
12	O	7	0	VBZ	is
12	O	8	0	VBN	characterized
12	O	9	0	IN	by
12	O	10	0	PRP$	its
12	O	11	0	JJ	exquisite
12	O	12	0	NN	craftsmanship
12	O	13	0	CC	and
12	O	14	0	PRP$	its
12	O	15	0	JJ	luxurious
12	O	16	0	NN	wealth
12	O	17	0	IN	of
12	O	18	0	NNS	materials
12	O	19	0	,	,
12	O	20	0	IN	as
12	O	21	0	VBN	seen
12	O	22	0	IN	in
12	O	23	0	DT	the
12	O	24	0	NNS	ensembles
12	O	25	0	IN	of
12	LOCATION	26	0	NNP	Jacques
12	O	27	0	:	-
12	O	28	0	CD	\
12	O	29	0	``	`
12	O	30	0	JJ	c9mile
12	PERSON	31	0	NN	Ruhlmann
12	O	32	0	CC	or
12	O	33	0	DT	the
12	O	34	0	NNS	designers
12	O	35	0	NN	S
12	O	36	0	CD	\
12	O	37	0	``	`
12	O	38	0	FW	fce
12	O	39	0	FW	et
12	PERSON	40	0	NN	Mare
12	O	41	0	.	.

13	PERSON	0	0	NNP	Ruhlmann
13	O	1	0	NN	\
13	O	2	0	''	'
13	O	3	0	NNS	92s
13	O	4	0	VBP	corner
13	O	5	0	NN	cabinet
13	O	6	0	IN	in
13	O	7	0	JJ	lacquered
13	O	8	0	NN	rosewood
13	O	9	0	,	,
13	O	10	0	IN	of
13	O	11	0	WDT	which
13	O	12	0	EX	there
13	O	13	0	VBP	are
13	O	14	0	JJ	several
13	O	15	0	NNS	variations
13	O	16	0	,	,
13	O	17	0	VBZ	takes
13	O	18	0	PRP$	its
13	O	19	0	JJ	overall
13	O	20	0	NN	shape
13	O	21	0	IN	from
13	O	22	0	DT	the
13	O	23	0	JJ	eighteenth
13	O	24	0	NN	century
13	O	25	0	CC	but
13	O	26	0	VBZ	features
13	O	27	0	JJ	delicate
13	O	28	0	NNS	inlays
13	O	29	0	IN	of
13	O	30	0	NN	ivory
13	O	31	0	IN	in
13	O	32	0	DT	the
13	O	33	0	JJ	stylized
13	O	34	0	JJ	floral
13	O	35	0	NN	bouquet
13	O	36	0	VBG	decorating
13	O	37	0	PRP$	its
13	O	38	0	NN	front
13	O	39	0	.	.

14	O	0	0	DT	A
14	O	1	0	JJ	subtle
14	O	2	0	JJ	rectangular
14	O	3	0	NN	border
14	O	4	0	VBN	formed
14	O	5	0	IN	from
14	O	6	0	NN	ivory
14	O	7	0	NNS	circles
14	O	8	0	VBZ	outlines
14	O	9	0	DT	the
14	O	10	0	NN	cabinet
14	O	11	0	NN	\
14	O	12	0	''	'
14	O	13	0	NNS	92s
14	O	14	0	JJ	front
14	O	15	0	RB	subtly
14	O	16	0	VBG	offsetting
14	O	17	0	PRP$	its
14	O	18	0	JJ	square
14	O	19	0	NN	shape
14	O	20	0	,	,
14	O	21	0	IN	with
14	O	22	0	DT	these
14	O	23	0	NNS	circles
14	O	24	0	RB	then
14	O	25	0	VBD	carried
14	O	26	0	IN	over
14	O	27	0	TO	to
14	O	28	0	DT	the
14	O	29	0	NNS	decorations
14	O	30	0	WDT	that
14	O	31	0	VBP	adorn
14	O	32	0	DT	the
14	O	33	0	NN	base
14	O	34	0	IN	of
14	O	35	0	DT	the
14	O	36	0	NNS	legs
14	O	37	0	.	.

15	O	0	0	NN	\
15	O	1	0	CD	\
15	O	2	0	IN	In
15	O	3	0	DT	the
15	LOCATION	4	0	NNPS	United/States
15	O	5	0	,	,
15	O	6	0	DT	the
15	O	7	0	JJ	characteristic
15	PERSON	8	0	NNP	Art/Deco
15	O	9	0	JJ	architectural
15	O	10	0	NN	design
15	O	11	0	VBD	included
15	O	12	0	DT	the
15	O	13	0	JJ	ascendant
15	O	14	0	VBD	stepped
15	O	15	0	NNS	forms
15	O	16	0	WDT	that
15	O	17	0	VBD	were
15	O	18	0	RB	ideally
15	O	19	0	VBN	suited
15	O	20	0	TO	to
15	O	21	0	DT	the
15	O	22	0	JJ	slender
15	O	23	0	NN	form
15	O	24	0	IN	of
15	O	25	0	DT	the
15	O	26	0	JJ	urban
15	O	27	0	NN	skyscraper
15	O	28	0	VBD	made
15	O	29	0	JJ	possible
15	O	30	0	IN	with
15	O	31	0	DT	the
15	O	32	0	NN	development
15	O	33	0	IN	of
15	O	34	0	DT	the
15	O	35	0	NN	elevator
15	O	36	0	.	.

16	O	0	0	RB	Similarly
16	O	1	0	,	,
16	O	2	0	DT	the
16	O	3	0	JJ	streamlined
16	O	4	0	JJ	aesthetic
16	O	5	0	IN	of
16	O	6	0	DT	the
16	PERSON	7	0	NNP	Art/Deco
16	O	8	0	NN	curve
16	O	9	0	VBD	was
16	O	10	0	VBN	found
16	O	11	0	TO	to
16	O	12	0	VB	be
16	O	13	0	RB	ideally
16	O	14	0	VBN	suited
16	O	15	0	IN	for
16	O	16	0	NN	apartment
16	O	17	0	NNS	buildings
16	O	18	0	,	,
16	O	19	0	NNS	trains
16	O	20	0	,	,
16	O	21	0	NNS	automobiles
16	O	22	0	,	,
16	O	23	0	CC	and
16	O	24	0	NN	furniture
16	O	25	0	,	,
16	O	26	0	IN	with
16	O	27	0	DT	the
16	O	28	0	VBN	rounded
16	O	29	0	NNS	corners
16	O	30	0	CC	and
16	O	31	0	JJ	gentle
16	O	32	0	NNS	curves
16	O	33	0	JJ	reflective
16	O	34	0	IN	of
16	O	35	0	JJ	effortless
16	O	36	0	CC	and
16	O	37	0	JJ	graceful
16	O	38	0	RB	forward
16	O	39	0	NN	motion
16	O	40	0	CC	and
16	O	41	0	JJ	technological
16	O	42	0	NN	advancement
16	O	43	0	.	.

17	O	0	0	NNP	Industrial
17	O	1	0	NNS	designers
17	O	2	0	RB	soon
17	O	3	0	VBD	adopted
17	O	4	0	DT	the
17	O	5	0	JJ	streamlined
17	O	6	0	NN	curve
17	O	7	0	IN	for
17	O	8	0	NN	consumer
17	O	9	0	NNS	products
17	O	10	0	,	,
17	O	11	0	VBG	including
17	O	12	0	NNS	radios
17	O	13	0	,	,
17	O	14	0	NNS	clocks
17	O	15	0	,	,
17	O	16	0	NN	cigarette
17	O	17	0	NNS	lighters
17	O	18	0	,	,
17	O	19	0	CC	and
17	O	20	0	JJ	other
17	O	21	0	NN	household
17	O	22	0	NNS	appliances
17	O	23	0	RB	now
17	O	24	0	VBG	being
17	O	25	0	VBN	made
17	O	26	0	IN	from
17	LOCATION	27	0	NNP	Bakelite
17	O	28	0	CC	and
17	O	29	0	JJ	other
17	O	30	0	JJ	new
17	O	31	0	NNS	types
17	O	32	0	IN	of
17	O	33	0	NNS	plastics
17	O	34	0	.	.

18	O	0	0	NN	\
18	O	1	0	CD	\
18	O	2	0	JJ	Several
18	O	3	0	NNS	factors
18	O	4	0	VBD	were
18	O	5	0	JJ	influential
18	O	6	0	IN	in
18	O	7	0	DT	the
18	O	8	0	NN	development
18	O	9	0	CC	and
18	O	10	0	NN	popularization
18	O	11	0	IN	of
18	LOCATION	12	0	NNP	Art/Deco
18	O	13	0	VBG	beginning
18	O	14	0	IN	in
18	LOCATION	15	0	NNP	Paris
18	O	16	0	IN	in
18	O	17	0	DT	the
18	O	18	0	JJ	first
18	O	19	0	NN	decade
18	O	20	0	IN	of
18	O	21	0	DT	the
18	O	22	0	JJ	twentieth
18	O	23	0	NN	century
18	O	24	0	.	.

19	O	0	0	VBN	Founded
19	O	1	0	IN	in
19	O	2	0	CD	1901
19	O	3	0	,	,
19	O	4	0	DT	the
19	LOCATION	5	0	NNP	Soci
19	O	6	0	NNP	\
19	O	7	0	``	`
19	O	8	0	FW	e9t
19	O	9	0	FW	\
19	O	10	0	``	`
19	O	11	0	FW	e9
19	O	12	0	FW	des
19	PERSON	13	0	FW	Artistes
19	O	14	0	NN	D
19	O	15	0	CD	\
19	O	16	0	``	`
19	O	17	0	NNS	e9corateurs
19	O	18	0	VBD	worked
19	O	19	0	TO	to
19	O	20	0	VB	promote
19	O	21	0	DT	the
19	O	22	0	RBS	most
19	O	23	0	JJ	talented
19	O	24	0	NNS	designers
19	O	25	0	IN	in
19	LOCATION	26	0	NNP	France
19	O	27	0	TO	to
19	O	28	0	VB	reinforce
19	O	29	0	DT	the
19	O	30	0	NN	country
19	O	31	0	NN	\
19	O	32	0	''	'
19	O	33	0	NNS	92s
19	O	34	0	NN	position
19	O	35	0	IN	at
19	O	36	0	DT	the
19	O	37	0	NN	forefront
19	O	38	0	IN	of
19	O	39	0	RB	increasingly
19	O	40	0	JJ	competitive
19	MISC	41	0	JJ	European
19	O	42	0	NNS	markets
19	O	43	0	.	.

20	O	0	0	DT	This
20	O	1	0	NN	impetus
20	O	2	0	VBD	was
20	O	3	0	RB	largely
20	O	4	0	IN	in
20	O	5	0	NN	response
20	O	6	0	TO	to
20	O	7	0	DT	the
20	O	8	0	NNS	exhibits
20	O	9	0	IN	at
20	O	10	0	DT	the
20	ORGANIZATION	11	0	NNP	Universal/Exposition
20	O	12	0	IN	in
20	LOCATION	13	0	NNP	Paris
20	O	14	0	IN	in
20	O	15	0	CD	1900
20	O	16	0	,	,
20	O	17	0	WRB	where
20	O	18	0	DT	the
20	ORGANIZATION	19	0	NNP	Art/Nouveau
20	O	20	0	NN	style
20	O	21	0	VBD	was
20	O	22	0	VBN	seen
20	O	23	0	IN	as
20	O	24	0	VBG	having
20	O	25	0	VBN	become
20	O	26	0	RB	too
20	O	27	0	VBN	commercialized
20	O	28	0	CC	and
20	O	29	0	VBN	diluted
20	O	30	0	.	.

21	O	0	0	DT	The
21	ORGANIZATION	1	0	NNP	Soci
21	O	2	0	NNP	\
21	O	3	0	``	`
21	O	4	0	FW	e9t
21	O	5	0	FW	\
21	O	6	0	``	`
21	O	7	0	FW	e9
21	O	8	0	FW	\
21	O	9	0	''	'
21	O	10	0	NNS	92s
21	O	11	0	NNS	efforts
21	O	12	0	TO	to
21	O	13	0	VB	organize
21	O	14	0	DT	another
21	O	15	0	JJ	international
21	O	16	0	NN	exposition
21	O	17	0	VBD	were
21	O	18	0	RB	initially
21	O	19	0	VBN	delayed
21	O	20	0	IN	because
21	O	21	0	IN	of
21	MISC	22	0	CD	World/War/One
21	O	23	0	.	.

22	O	0	0	WRB	When
22	O	1	0	RB	finally
22	O	2	0	VBN	realized
22	O	3	0	,	,
22	O	4	0	DT	the
22	MISC	5	0	NNP	Art/Deco
22	O	6	0	NN	style
22	O	7	0	VBD	was
22	O	8	0	VBN	seen
22	O	9	0	IN	at
22	O	10	0	PRP$	its
22	O	11	0	JJS	best
22	O	12	0	NN	expression
22	O	13	0	IN	in
22	O	14	0	DT	the
22	O	15	0	JJ	various
22	O	16	0	NNS	pavilions
22	O	17	0	CC	and
22	O	18	0	NNS	ensembles
22	O	19	0	IN	at
22	O	20	0	DT	the
22	ORGANIZATION	21	0	NNP	Exposition/Internationale/des/Arts
22	O	22	0	NN	d
22	O	23	0	CD	\
22	O	24	0	``	`
22	O	25	0	NNS	e9coratifs
22	O	26	0	FW	et
22	O	27	0	FW	industriels
22	O	28	0	NNS	modernes
22	O	29	0	,	,
22	O	30	0	VBN	held
22	O	31	0	IN	in
22	LOCATION	32	0	NNP	Paris
22	O	33	0	IN	in
22	O	34	0	CD	1925
22	O	35	0	,	,
22	O	36	0	WDT	which
22	O	37	0	VBD	drew
22	O	38	0	IN	over
22	O	39	0	CD	6
22	O	40	0	CD	million
22	O	41	0	NNS	visitors
22	O	42	0	,	,
22	O	43	0	CC	and
22	O	44	0	IN	from
22	O	45	0	WDT	which
22	O	46	0	DT	the
22	O	47	0	NN	name
22	PERSON	48	0	NNP	Art/Deco
22	O	49	0	VBD	was
22	O	50	0	RB	eventually
22	O	51	0	VBN	applied
22	O	52	0	TO	to
22	O	53	0	VB	describe
22	O	54	0	WP	what
22	O	55	0	VBD	was
22	O	56	0	DT	the
22	O	57	0	JJ	predominant
22	O	58	0	NN	style
22	O	59	0	IN	in
22	O	60	0	DT	the
22	O	61	0	NNS	objects
22	O	62	0	CC	and
22	O	63	0	VBZ	exhibits
22	O	64	0	IN	on
22	O	65	0	NN	view
22	O	66	0	.	.

23	O	0	0	NN	\
23	O	1	0	CD	\
23	O	2	0	IN	From
23	O	3	0	DT	the
23	O	4	0	CD	1925
23	O	5	0	NNP	Exposition
23	O	6	0	,	,
23	O	7	0	CD	one
23	O	8	0	JJ	prime
23	O	9	0	NN	example
23	O	10	0	IN	of
23	MISC	11	0	NNP	French
23	O	12	0	NNP	Art
23	PERSON	13	0	NNP	Deco
23	O	14	0	VBZ	is
23	O	15	0	DT	the
23	O	16	0	NN	pavilion
23	O	17	0	NN	\
23	O	18	0	''	'
23	O	19	0	NN	91H
23	O	20	0	CD	\
23	O	21	0	``	`
23	O	22	0	NN	f4tel
23	O	23	0	NN	d
23	O	24	0	NN	\
23	O	25	0	''	'
23	O	26	0	JJ	92un
23	O	27	0	NNP	Collectionneur
23	O	28	0	CD	\
23	O	29	0	CD	'92
23	O	30	0	VBN	designed
23	O	31	0	IN	by
23	PERSON	32	0	NNP	Pierre/Patout
23	O	33	0	.	.

24	O	0	0	DT	The
24	O	1	0	NN	exterior
24	O	2	0	VBZ	features
24	O	3	0	VBD	stepped
24	O	4	0	JJ	architectural
24	O	5	0	NNS	forms
24	O	6	0	VBG	incorporating
24	O	7	0	JJ	unadorned
24	O	8	0	JJ	geometric
24	O	9	0	NNS	shapes
24	O	10	0	IN	with
24	O	11	0	DT	an
24	O	12	0	JJ	elegant
24	O	13	0	JJ	plain
24	O	14	0	NN	fa
24	O	15	0	CD	\
24	O	16	0	``	`
24	O	17	0	VB	e7ade
24	O	18	0	CC	and
24	O	19	0	DT	a
24	O	20	0	NN	variation
24	O	21	0	IN	of
24	O	22	0	DT	the
24	O	23	0	JJ	restrained
24	MISC	24	0	JJ	Classical
24	O	25	0	NN	vocabulary
24	O	26	0	IN	of
24	O	27	0	NNS	columns
24	O	28	0	CC	and
24	O	29	0	DT	a
24	O	30	0	JJ	decorative
24	O	31	0	NN	frieze
24	O	32	0	.	.

25	O	0	0	DT	The
25	O	1	0	JJ	overall
25	O	2	0	NN	building
25	O	3	0	VBZ	is
25	O	4	0	DT	a
25	O	5	0	JJ	harmonious
25	O	6	0	NN	balance
25	O	7	0	IN	of
25	O	8	0	NN	square
25	O	9	0	,	,
25	O	10	0	JJ	circular
25	O	11	0	,	,
25	O	12	0	JJ	horizontal
25	O	13	0	CC	and
25	O	14	0	JJ	vertical
25	O	15	0	NNS	elements
25	O	16	0	IN	with
25	O	17	0	JJ	solid
25	O	18	0	CC	and
25	O	19	0	NN	glass
25	O	20	0	NNS	masses
25	O	21	0	.	.

26	PERSON	0	0	NNP	Ruhlmann
26	O	1	0	VBD	designed
26	O	2	0	PRP$	its
26	MISC	3	0	NNP	Grand-Salon
26	O	4	0	NN	interior
26	O	5	0	CC	and
26	O	6	0	DT	this
26	O	7	0	NN	ensemble
26	O	8	0	VBZ	remains
26	O	9	0	CD	one
26	O	10	0	IN	of
26	O	11	0	DT	the
26	O	12	0	JJS	best
26	O	13	0	NNS	examples
26	O	14	0	IN	of
26	PERSON	15	0	NNP	Art/Deco
26	O	16	0	NN	\
26	O	17	0	''	'
26	O	18	0	NNS	92s
26	O	19	0	NN	sumptuousness
26	O	20	0	CC	and
26	O	21	0	JJ	overall
26	O	22	0	NN	eclecticism
26	O	23	0	.	.

27	O	0	0	DT	The
27	O	1	0	NN	wall
27	O	2	0	NNS	coverings
27	O	3	0	VBD	featured
27	O	4	0	DT	a
27	O	5	0	VBG	repeating
27	O	6	0	JJ	red
27	O	7	0	NN	pattern
27	O	8	0	IN	of
27	O	9	0	NNS	birds
27	O	10	0	CC	and
27	O	11	0	JJ	floral
27	O	12	0	NNS	garlands
27	O	13	0	IN	over
27	O	14	0	DT	a
27	O	15	0	JJ	yellow
27	O	16	0	NN	ground
27	O	17	0	WDT	that
27	O	18	0	VBZ	is
27	O	19	0	VBN	carried
27	O	20	0	RP	over
27	O	21	0	IN	into
27	O	22	0	DT	the
27	O	23	0	NN	carpeting
27	O	24	0	CC	and
27	O	25	0	DT	the
27	O	26	0	NN	upholstery
27	O	27	0	IN	of
27	O	28	0	DT	the
27	O	29	0	NN	furniture
27	O	30	0	.	.

28	O	0	0	DT	The
28	O	1	0	RB	relatively
28	O	2	0	JJ	simple
28	O	3	0	NNS	lines
28	O	4	0	CC	and
28	O	5	0	NNS	shapes
28	O	6	0	IN	of
28	O	7	0	DT	the
28	O	8	0	NN	furniture
28	O	9	0	MD	may
28	O	10	0	VB	appear
28	O	11	0	RB	deceptively
28	O	12	0	JJ	simple
28	O	13	0	IN	until
28	O	14	0	DT	the
28	O	15	0	NNS	materials
28	O	16	0	,	,
28	O	17	0	NN	craftsmanship
28	O	18	0	,	,
28	O	19	0	CC	and
28	O	20	0	NN	beauty
28	O	21	0	IN	of
28	O	22	0	DT	each
28	O	23	0	JJ	individual
28	O	24	0	NN	piece
28	O	25	0	VBZ	is
28	O	26	0	VBN	recognized
28	O	27	0	.	.

29	O	0	0	IN	For
29	O	1	0	NN	example
29	O	2	0	,	,
29	O	3	0	DT	a
29	O	4	0	JJ	large
29	O	5	0	NN	cabinet
29	O	6	0	IN	by
29	PERSON	7	0	NNP	Ruhlmann
29	O	8	0	,	,
29	PERSON	9	0	NNP	Jean/Dunand
29	O	10	0	,	,
29	O	11	0	CC	and
29	PERSON	12	0	NNP	Jean/Lambert-Rucki
29	O	13	0	IN	from
29	O	14	0	DT	this
29	O	15	0	NN	room
29	O	16	0	VBZ	is
29	O	17	0	JJ	simple
29	O	18	0	IN	in
29	O	19	0	NN	form
29	O	20	0	RB	yet
29	O	21	0	PRP$	its
29	O	22	0	NN	luxuriousness
29	O	23	0	VBZ	comes
29	O	24	0	IN	from
29	O	25	0	DT	the
29	O	26	0	JJ	black
29	O	27	0	NN	lacquer
29	O	28	0	NN	exterior
29	O	29	0	VBN	incised
29	O	30	0	IN	with
29	O	31	0	NN	silver
29	O	32	0	NN	decoration
29	O	33	0	VBG	depicting
29	O	34	0	CD	two
29	O	35	0	NNS	animals
29	O	36	0	.	.

30	O	0	0	PRP	They
30	O	1	0	VBP	are
30	O	2	0	VBN	made
30	O	3	0	IN	from
30	O	4	0	JJ	stylized
30	O	5	0	JJ	geometric
30	O	6	0	NNS	shapes
30	O	7	0	CC	and
30	O	8	0	NN	zigzag
30	O	9	0	NNS	lines
30	O	10	0	IN	with
30	O	11	0	DT	these
30	O	12	0	NNS	lines
30	O	13	0	RB	then
30	O	14	0	VBD	angled
30	O	15	0	IN	across
30	O	16	0	DT	the
30	O	17	0	JJ	top
30	O	18	0	TO	to
30	O	19	0	VB	echo
30	O	20	0	DT	the
30	O	21	0	NNS	rays
30	O	22	0	IN	of
30	O	23	0	DT	the
30	O	24	0	NN	sun
30	O	25	0	.	.

31	O	0	0	DT	The
31	O	1	0	JJ	undulating
31	O	2	0	NNS	sides
31	O	3	0	IN	of
31	O	4	0	DT	the
31	O	5	0	NN	cabinet
31	O	6	0	NN	balance
31	O	7	0	DT	the
31	O	8	0	JJ	flat
31	O	9	0	NN	expanse
31	O	10	0	IN	of
31	O	11	0	DT	the
31	O	12	0	NN	middle
31	O	13	0	IN	while
31	O	14	0	DT	the
31	O	15	0	JJ	subtle
31	O	16	0	JJ	linear
31	O	17	0	NNS	decorations
31	O	18	0	VBP	are
31	O	19	0	VBN	repeated
31	O	20	0	IN	throughout
31	O	21	0	TO	to
31	O	22	0	VB	lighten
31	O	23	0	PRP$	its
31	O	24	0	JJ	overall
31	O	25	0	NN	solidity
31	O	26	0	.	.

32	O	0	0	NNP	Lacquer
32	O	1	0	VBD	was
32	O	2	0	DT	a
32	O	3	0	JJ	favored
32	O	4	0	NN	technique
32	O	5	0	IN	for
32	O	6	0	NN	furniture
32	O	7	0	IN	during
32	O	8	0	DT	the
32	PERSON	9	0	NNP	Art/Deco
32	O	10	0	NN	period
32	O	11	0	IN	with
32	PERSON	12	0	NNP	Jean/Dunand
32	O	13	0	CD	one
32	O	14	0	IN	of
32	O	15	0	PRP$	its
32	O	16	0	NNS	masters
32	O	17	0	.	.

33	O	0	0	PRP	It
33	O	1	0	VBD	was
33	O	2	0	VBN	introduced
33	O	3	0	IN	by
33	MISC	4	0	JJ	Japanese
33	O	5	0	NNS	craftsmen
33	O	6	0	CC	and
33	O	7	0	VBZ	requires
33	O	8	0	JJ	intensive
33	O	9	0	NN	labor
33	O	10	0	,	,
33	O	11	0	NN	time
33	O	12	0	,	,
33	O	13	0	CC	and
33	O	14	0	NN	expertise
33	O	15	0	TO	to
33	O	16	0	VB	achieve
33	O	17	0	DT	the
33	O	18	0	JJ	smooth
33	O	19	0	CC	and
33	O	20	0	JJ	flawless
33	O	21	0	NN	surface
33	O	22	0	VBN	seen
33	O	23	0	RB	here
33	O	24	0	.	.

34	O	0	0	NN	\
34	O	1	0	SYM	\
34	O	2	0	FW	pard
34	O	3	0	FW	\
34	O	4	0	NN	pardeftab720
34	O	5	0	CD	\
34	O	6	0	NN	ri720
34	O	7	0	CD	\
34	O	8	0	NN	partightenfactor0
34	O	9	0	CD	\
34	O	10	0	NN	f1
34	O	11	0	CD	\
34	O	12	0	NN	cf0
34	O	13	0	CD	\
34	O	14	0	CD	\
34	O	15	0	NN	pard
34	O	16	0	CD	\
34	O	17	0	NN	pardeftab720
34	O	18	0	CD	\
34	O	19	0	NN	ri720
34	O	20	0	CD	\
34	O	21	0	NN	partightenfactor0
34	O	22	0	CD	\
34	O	23	0	NN	f0
34	O	24	0	CD	\
34	O	25	0	NN	cf0
34	O	26	0	JJ	Coincident
34	O	27	0	IN	with
34	O	28	0	DT	the
34	O	29	0	NNS	efforts
34	O	30	0	IN	of
34	O	31	0	DT	the
34	ORGANIZATION	32	0	NNP	Soci
34	O	33	0	NNP	\
34	O	34	0	``	`
34	O	35	0	FW	e9t
34	O	36	0	FW	\
34	O	37	0	``	`
34	O	38	0	FW	e9
34	O	39	0	FW	des
34	PERSON	40	0	FW	Artistes
34	O	41	0	NN	D
34	O	42	0	CD	\
34	O	43	0	``	`
34	O	44	0	NNS	e9corateurs
34	O	45	0	TO	to
34	O	46	0	VB	revitalize
34	O	47	0	DT	the
34	O	48	0	NN	design
34	O	49	0	NN	trade
34	O	50	0	,	,
34	O	51	0	VBG	leading
34	MISC	52	0	JJ	Parisian
34	O	53	0	NNS	artists
34	O	54	0	RB	similarly
34	O	55	0	VBD	recognized
34	O	56	0	DT	the
34	O	57	0	NN	need
34	O	58	0	TO	to
34	O	59	0	VB	exhibit
34	O	60	0	RB	together
34	O	61	0	,	,
34	O	62	0	VBG	founding
34	O	63	0	DT	the
34	ORGANIZATION	64	0	NNP	Salon
34	O	65	0	NN	d
34	O	66	0	NN	\
34	O	67	0	''	'
34	O	68	0	NN	92Automne
34	O	69	0	IN	in
34	O	70	0	CD	1903
34	O	71	0	.	.

35	O	0	0	DT	The
35	O	1	0	NN	group
35	O	2	0	VBD	was
35	O	3	0	JJ	responsible
35	O	4	0	IN	for
35	O	5	0	VBG	introducing
35	MISC	6	0	NNPS	Parisians
35	O	7	0	TO	to
35	O	8	0	DT	the
35	O	9	0	NN	work
35	O	10	0	IN	of
35	O	11	0	VBG	leading
35	O	12	0	NNS	artists
35	O	13	0	,	,
35	O	14	0	VBG	including
35	PERSON	15	0	NNP	Paul/Gauguin
35	O	16	0	,	,
35	PERSON	17	0	NNP	Paul/Cezanne
35	O	18	0	,	,
35	PERSON	19	0	NNP	Puvis/de/Chavannes
35	O	20	0	,	,
35	PERSON	21	0	NNP	Odilon/Redon
35	O	22	0	,	,
35	O	23	0	CC	and
35	PERSON	24	0	NNP	Henri/de/Toulouse-Lautrec
35	O	25	0	IN	among
35	O	26	0	NNS	others
35	O	27	0	.	.

36	O	0	0	IN	In
36	O	1	0	CD	1905
36	O	2	0	,	,
36	O	3	0	DT	the
36	ORGANIZATION	4	0	NNP	Salon
36	O	5	0	NN	d
36	O	6	0	NN	\
36	O	7	0	''	'
36	O	8	0	NN	92Automne
36	O	9	0	VBD	introduced
36	O	10	0	DT	the
36	O	11	0	NN	work
36	O	12	0	IN	of
36	O	13	0	DT	the
36	LOCATION	14	0	NNP	Fauves
36	O	15	0	,	,
36	O	16	0	RB	principally
36	PERSON	17	0	NNP	Henri/Matisse
36	O	18	0	CC	and
36	PERSON	19	0	NNP	Andre/Derain
36	O	20	0	,	,
36	O	21	0	WP$	whose
36	O	22	0	JJ	liberated
36	O	23	0	CC	and
36	O	24	0	JJ	abstract
36	O	25	0	NN	use
36	O	26	0	IN	of
36	O	27	0	NN	color
36	O	28	0	CC	and
36	O	29	0	VBD	simplified
36	O	30	0	NNS	forms
36	O	31	0	VBN	designated
36	O	32	0	PRP	them
36	O	33	0	IN	as
36	O	34	0	NN	\
36	O	35	0	''	'
36	O	36	0	JJ	91wild
36	O	37	0	NNS	beasts
36	O	38	0	.	.

37	O	0	0	NN	\
37	O	1	0	CD	'92
37	PERSON	2	0	NNP	Matisse
37	O	3	0	NN	\
37	O	4	0	''	'
37	O	5	0	NNS	92s
37	O	6	0	VBG	curving
37	O	7	0	NN	arabesque
37	O	8	0	NNS	lines
37	O	9	0	,	,
37	O	10	0	IN	along
37	O	11	0	IN	with
37	O	12	0	DT	the
37	O	13	0	NN	flattening
37	O	14	0	IN	of
37	O	15	0	NN	form
37	O	16	0	,	,
37	O	17	0	JJ	bold
37	O	18	0	NNS	colors
37	O	19	0	,	,
37	O	20	0	CC	and
37	O	21	0	JJ	linear
37	O	22	0	NNS	reductions
37	O	23	0	VBG	occurring
37	O	24	0	IN	in
37	O	25	0	JJ	modern
37	O	26	0	NN	art
37	O	27	0	,	,
37	O	28	0	VBD	were
37	O	29	0	RB	quickly
37	O	30	0	VBN	adapted
37	O	31	0	IN	by
37	O	32	0	JJ	commercial
37	O	33	0	NNS	designers
37	O	34	0	IN	in
37	O	35	0	DT	the
37	O	36	0	NN	creation
37	O	37	0	IN	of
37	ORGANIZATION	38	0	NNP	Art/Deco
37	O	39	0	NNS	objects
37	O	40	0	IN	for
37	O	41	0	NN	sale
37	O	42	0	TO	to
37	O	43	0	DT	the
37	O	44	0	JJR	wider
37	O	45	0	NN	public
37	O	46	0	.	.

38	O	0	0	NN	\
38	O	1	0	CD	\
38	O	2	0	DT	The
38	O	3	0	JJ	formal
38	O	4	0	NNS	experiments
38	O	5	0	IN	of
38	MISC	6	0	NNP	Cubism
38	O	7	0	VBD	led
38	O	8	0	TO	to
38	O	9	0	DT	an
38	O	10	0	VBN	increased
38	O	11	0	NN	interest
38	O	12	0	IN	in
38	O	13	0	JJ	geometric
38	O	14	0	NN	form
38	O	15	0	CC	and
38	O	16	0	NN	abstraction
38	O	17	0	IN	in
38	O	18	0	JJ	many
38	O	19	0	NNS	realms
38	O	20	0	IN	of
38	O	21	0	NN	art
38	O	22	0	CC	and
38	O	23	0	NN	design
38	O	24	0	.	.

39	O	0	0	DT	The
39	MISC	1	0	NNS	Italian/Futurists
39	O	2	0	RB	also
39	O	3	0	VBD	explored
39	O	4	0	JJ	dynamic
39	O	5	0	NN	movement
39	O	6	0	,	,
39	O	7	0	NN	speed
39	O	8	0	,	,
39	O	9	0	CC	and
39	O	10	0	DT	the
39	O	11	0	NN	machine
39	O	12	0	JJ	aesthetic
39	O	13	0	.	.

40	O	0	0	DT	The
40	O	1	0	NN	exploration
40	O	2	0	IN	of
40	O	3	0	NN	movement
40	O	4	0	VBG	using
40	O	5	0	JJ	pure
40	O	6	0	NNS	areas
40	O	7	0	IN	of
40	O	8	0	NN	color
40	O	9	0	CC	and
40	O	10	0	JJ	non-representational
40	O	11	0	NNS	forms
40	O	12	0	VBZ	permeates
40	O	13	0	DT	the
40	O	14	0	NN	work
40	O	15	0	IN	of
40	LOCATION	16	0	NNP	Robert
40	O	17	0	CC	and
40	PERSON	18	0	NNP	Sonia/Delaunay
40	O	19	0	.	.

41	O	0	0	PRP	They
41	O	1	0	VBD	coined
41	O	2	0	DT	the
41	O	3	0	NN	term
41	O	4	0	NN	\
41	O	5	0	''	'
41	O	6	0	NN	91simultaneity
41	O	7	0	CD	\
41	O	8	0	CD	'92
41	O	9	0	TO	to
41	O	10	0	VB	characterize
41	O	11	0	WRB	how
41	O	12	0	PRP$	their
41	O	13	0	JJ	abstract
41	O	14	0	NN	imagery
41	O	15	0	VBN	made
41	O	16	0	IN	of
41	O	17	0	VBG	interpenetrating
41	O	18	0	JJ	geometric
41	O	19	0	NNS	areas
41	O	20	0	IN	of
41	O	21	0	JJ	pure
41	O	22	0	NN	color
41	O	23	0	VBD	visualized
41	O	24	0	DT	the
41	O	25	0	JJ	rapid
41	O	26	0	NN	motion
41	O	27	0	CC	and
41	O	28	0	NN	movement
41	O	29	0	WDT	that
41	O	30	0	VBD	structured
41	O	31	0	JJ	urban
41	O	32	0	NN	life
41	O	33	0	.	.

42	O	0	0	RB	Soon
42	O	1	0	,	,
42	PERSON	2	0	NNP	Sonia/Delaunay
42	O	3	0	VBD	began
42	O	4	0	VBG	applying
42	O	5	0	DT	these
42	O	6	0	NNS	designs
42	O	7	0	TO	to
42	O	8	0	NN	clothing
42	O	9	0	CC	and
42	O	10	0	NNS	objects
42	O	11	0	,	,
42	O	12	0	WDT	which
42	O	13	0	VBD	were
42	O	14	0	VBN	sold
42	O	15	0	IN	through
42	O	16	0	VBG	leading
42	O	17	0	NN	department
42	O	18	0	NNS	stores
42	O	19	0	CC	and
42	O	20	0	IN	at
42	O	21	0	PRP$	her
42	ORGANIZATION	22	0	NNP	Simultan
42	O	23	0	NN	\
42	O	24	0	``	`
42	O	25	0	NN	e9
42	O	26	0	NNS	boutiques
42	O	27	0	,	,
42	O	28	0	VBG	including
42	O	29	0	CD	one
42	O	30	0	IN	at
42	O	31	0	DT	the
42	O	32	0	CD	1925
42	O	33	0	NNP	Exposition
42	O	34	0	.	.

43	O	0	0	NN	\
43	O	1	0	CD	\
43	O	2	0	DT	The
43	PERSON	3	0	NNP	Ballets/Russes
43	O	4	0	VBD	was
43	O	5	0	CD	one
43	O	6	0	IN	of
43	O	7	0	DT	the
43	O	8	0	RBS	most
43	O	9	0	JJ	important
43	O	10	0	NNS	influences
43	O	11	0	IN	on
43	O	12	0	DT	the
43	O	13	0	NN	development
43	O	14	0	IN	of
43	O	15	0	JJ	visual
43	O	16	0	NN	culture
43	O	17	0	IN	in
43	O	18	0	DT	the
43	O	19	0	NNS	1910s
43	O	20	0	.	.

44	O	0	0	VBN	Brought
44	O	1	0	TO	to
44	LOCATION	2	0	NNP	Paris
44	O	3	0	IN	in
44	O	4	0	CD	1909
44	O	5	0	,	,
44	O	6	0	DT	the
44	O	7	0	NNS	performances
44	O	8	0	IN	by
44	PERSON	9	0	NNP	Serge/Diaghilev
44	O	10	0	NN	\
44	O	11	0	''	'
44	O	12	0	NNS	92s
44	O	13	0	NN	company
44	O	14	0	CC	and
44	O	15	0	PRP$	his
44	O	16	0	JJ	talented
44	O	17	0	NNS	collaborators
44	O	18	0	,	,
44	O	19	0	VBG	including
44	O	20	0	DT	the
44	O	21	0	NN	designer
44	O	22	0	NN	L
44	O	23	0	CD	\
44	O	24	0	``	`
44	O	25	0	FW	e9on
44	PERSON	26	0	FW	Bakst
44	O	27	0	,	,
44	O	28	0	JJ	astonished
44	O	29	0	NNS	audiences
44	O	30	0	CC	and
44	O	31	0	VBD	inspired
44	O	32	0	NNS	designers
44	O	33	0	IN	with
44	O	34	0	PRP$	their
44	O	35	0	VBG	enveloping
44	O	36	0	CC	and
44	O	37	0	VBG	intoxicating
44	O	38	0	NN	mixture
44	O	39	0	IN	of
44	O	40	0	NN	ornament
44	O	41	0	,	,
44	O	42	0	NN	pattern
44	O	43	0	,	,
44	O	44	0	CC	and
44	O	45	0	NN	color
44	O	46	0	IN	in
44	O	47	0	NNS	spectacles
44	O	48	0	VBG	evoking
44	O	49	0	JJ	exotic
44	O	50	0	CC	and
44	O	51	0	JJ	far-away
44	O	52	0	NNS	realms
44	O	53	0	CC	or
44	O	54	0	JJ	rhythmic
44	MISC	55	0	NN	Cubist
44	O	56	0	NN	modernism
44	O	57	0	IN	in
44	O	58	0	DT	the
44	O	59	0	NN	dancing
44	O	60	0	,	,
44	O	61	0	NNS	costumes
44	O	62	0	,	,
44	O	63	0	CC	and
44	O	64	0	JJ	scenic
44	O	65	0	NNS	designs
44	O	66	0	IN	for
44	O	67	0	PRP$	their
44	O	68	0	JJ	varied
44	O	69	0	NNS	productions
44	O	70	0	.	.

45	O	0	0	NN	\
45	O	1	0	CD	\
45	O	2	0	CD	One
45	O	3	0	NN	example
45	O	4	0	IN	of
45	O	5	0	WRB	how
45	O	6	0	DT	these
45	O	7	0	NNS	ideas
45	O	8	0	IN	from
45	O	9	0	DT	the
45	O	10	0	JJ	visual
45	O	11	0	NNS	arts
45	O	12	0	VBD	were
45	O	13	0	VBN	translated
45	O	14	0	IN	into
45	O	15	0	DT	the
45	O	16	0	NN	realm
45	O	17	0	IN	of
45	LOCATION	18	0	NNP	Art/Deco
45	O	19	0	VBZ	is
45	O	20	0	VBN	seen
45	O	21	0	IN	in
45	O	22	0	NN	furniture
45	O	23	0	NN	designer
45	PERSON	24	0	NNP	Andr
45	O	25	0	CD	\
45	O	26	0	``	`
45	O	27	0	FW	e9
45	PERSON	28	0	FW	Groult
45	O	29	0	FW	\
45	O	30	0	''	'
45	O	31	0	JJ	92s
45	O	32	0	NN	chiffonier
45	O	33	0	CC	or
45	O	34	0	NN	bureau
45	O	35	0	VBD	made
45	O	36	0	IN	for
45	O	37	0	DT	a
45	O	38	0	NN	woman
45	O	39	0	NN	\
45	O	40	0	''	'
45	O	41	0	NNS	92s
45	O	42	0	NN	room
45	O	43	0	IN	of
45	O	44	0	DT	a
45	O	45	0	NN	pavilion
45	O	46	0	IN	at
45	O	47	0	DT	the
45	O	48	0	CD	1925
45	O	49	0	NNP	Exposition
45	O	50	0	.	.

46	O	0	0	PRP$	Its
46	O	1	0	JJ	anthropomorphic
46	O	2	0	NN	shape
46	O	3	0	NNS	echoes
46	O	4	0	DT	the
46	O	5	0	JJ	curvaceous
46	O	6	0	JJ	female
46	O	7	0	NN	form
46	O	8	0	CC	and
46	O	9	0	PRP	it
46	O	10	0	VBZ	is
46	O	11	0	VBN	made
46	O	12	0	IN	from
46	O	13	0	RB	typically
46	O	14	0	JJ	exotic
46	O	15	0	NNS	materials
46	O	16	0	,	,
46	O	17	0	VBG	including
46	O	18	0	NN	ivory
46	O	19	0	NNS	keyholes
46	O	20	0	CC	and
46	O	21	0	NN	sharkskin
46	O	22	0	,	,
46	O	23	0	RB	also
46	O	24	0	VBN	known
46	O	25	0	IN	as
46	O	26	0	NN	shagreen
46	O	27	0	,	,
46	O	28	0	IN	in
46	O	29	0	DT	a
46	O	30	0	JJ	bold
46	O	31	0	JJ	yellow
46	O	32	0	NN	color
46	O	33	0	.	.

47	O	0	0	DT	The
47	O	1	0	NN	shagreen
47	O	2	0	VBZ	has
47	O	3	0	VBN	been
47	O	4	0	VBN	applied
47	O	5	0	IN	in
47	O	6	0	DT	the
47	O	7	0	NN	pattern
47	O	8	0	IN	of
47	O	9	0	DT	a
47	O	10	0	JJ	large
47	O	11	0	NN	sun
47	O	12	0	IN	at
47	O	13	0	DT	the
47	O	14	0	JJ	bottom
47	O	15	0	VBG	emitting
47	O	16	0	NNS	rays
47	O	17	0	WDT	that
47	O	18	0	JJ	alternate
47	O	19	0	IN	into
47	O	20	0	NNS	squares
47	O	21	0	CC	and
47	O	22	0	NNS	circles
47	O	23	0	IN	as
47	O	24	0	PRP	they
47	O	25	0	VBP	reach
47	O	26	0	DT	the
47	O	27	0	JJ	top
47	O	28	0	VBG	resulting
47	O	29	0	IN	in
47	O	30	0	DT	an
47	O	31	0	JJ	exciting
47	O	32	0	RB	yet
47	O	33	0	VBN	restrained
47	O	34	0	NN	object
47	O	35	0	IN	in
47	O	36	0	WDT	which
47	O	37	0	PRP$	its
47	O	38	0	JJ	sophisticated
47	O	39	0	CC	and
47	O	40	0	JJ	luxurious
47	O	41	0	NN	appearance
47	O	42	0	VBP	are
47	O	43	0	PRP$	its
47	O	44	0	JJ	foremost
47	O	45	0	NNS	concerns
47	O	46	0	.	.

48	O	0	0	NN	\
48	O	1	0	CD	\
48	O	2	0	IN	Throughout
48	O	3	0	DT	the
48	O	4	0	NN	beginning
48	O	5	0	IN	of
48	O	6	0	DT	the
48	O	7	0	JJ	twentieth
48	O	8	0	NN	century
48	O	9	0	,	,
48	O	10	0	DT	the
48	O	11	0	NN	appeal
48	O	12	0	IN	of
48	O	13	0	DT	the
48	O	14	0	JJ	exotic
48	O	15	0	VBD	was
48	O	16	0	RB	continually
48	O	17	0	VBN	fueled
48	O	18	0	IN	by
48	LOCATION	19	0	NNP	France
48	O	20	0	NN	\
48	O	21	0	''	'
48	O	22	0	NNS	92s
48	O	23	0	JJ	vast
48	O	24	0	JJ	colonial
48	O	25	0	NNS	territories
48	O	26	0	,	,
48	O	27	0	JJ	inspiring
48	O	28	0	DT	an
48	O	29	0	NN	interest
48	O	30	0	IN	in
48	O	31	0	JJ	primitive
48	O	32	0	CC	or
48	O	33	0	JJ	tribal
48	O	34	0	NNS	forms
48	O	35	0	IN	from
48	LOCATION	36	0	NNP	Africa
48	O	37	0	:	;
48	O	38	0	DT	an
48	O	39	0	NN	interest
48	O	40	0	IN	in
48	O	41	0	JJ	new
48	O	42	0	NNS	techniques
48	O	43	0	CC	and
48	O	44	0	JJ	aestheticized
48	O	45	0	NN	surface
48	O	46	0	NNS	qualities
48	O	47	0	,	,
48	O	48	0	VBG	including
48	O	49	0	NN	lacquer
48	O	50	0	CC	and
48	O	51	0	JJ	ceramic
48	O	52	0	NN	glazing
48	O	53	0	IN	from
48	LOCATION	54	0	NNP	Asia
48	O	55	0	:	;
48	O	56	0	CC	and
48	O	57	0	DT	the
48	O	58	0	NN	use
48	O	59	0	IN	of
48	O	60	0	JJ	rare
48	O	61	0	CC	and
48	O	62	0	JJ	exotic
48	O	63	0	NNS	woods
48	O	64	0	,	,
48	O	65	0	JJ	semi-precious
48	O	66	0	NNS	stones
48	O	67	0	,	,
48	O	68	0	CC	and
48	O	69	0	JJ	other
48	O	70	0	NNS	materials
48	O	71	0	IN	from
48	O	72	0	DT	the
48	O	73	0	NNS	colonies
48	O	74	0	,	,
48	O	75	0	JJ	such
48	O	76	0	IN	as
48	O	77	0	NN	sharkskin
48	O	78	0	,	,
48	O	79	0	NN	tortoiseshell
48	O	80	0	,	,
48	O	81	0	CC	and
48	O	82	0	NN	ivory
48	O	83	0	IN	for
48	O	84	0	NNS	inlays
48	O	85	0	.	.

49	MISC	0	0	JJ	African
49	O	1	0	NNS	objects
49	O	2	0	CC	and
49	O	3	0	NNS	sculptures
49	O	4	0	VBD	had
49	O	5	0	VBN	helped
49	O	6	0	JJ	modern
49	O	7	0	NNS	artists
49	O	8	0	,	,
49	O	9	0	VBG	including
49	PERSON	10	0	NNP	Henri/Matisse
49	O	11	0	CC	and
49	PERSON	12	0	NNP	Pablo/Picasso
49	O	13	0	,	,
49	O	14	0	TO	to
49	O	15	0	NN	harness
49	O	16	0	DT	the
49	O	17	0	JJ	geometric
49	O	18	0	NNS	forms
49	O	19	0	CC	and
49	O	20	0	JJ	bold
49	O	21	0	JJ	linear
49	O	22	0	NNS	elements
49	O	23	0	VBN	seen
49	O	24	0	IN	in
49	MISC	25	0	JJ	African
49	O	26	0	NNS	objects
49	O	27	0	TO	to
49	O	28	0	VB	formulate
49	O	29	0	PRP$	their
49	O	30	0	JJ	abstract
49	O	31	0	NNS	vocabularies
49	O	32	0	IN	in
49	O	33	0	DT	the
49	O	34	0	JJ	fine
49	O	35	0	NNS	arts
49	O	36	0	WDT	that
49	O	37	0	RB	soon
49	O	38	0	VBD	revitalized
49	O	39	0	NN	imagery
49	O	40	0	IN	in
49	O	41	0	DT	the
49	O	42	0	NN	design
49	O	43	0	NN	realm
49	O	44	0	IN	during
49	O	45	0	DT	the
49	MISC	46	0	NNP	Art/Deco
49	O	47	0	NN	period
49	O	48	0	.	.

50	O	0	0	NN	\
50	MISC	1	0	NN	\/Travel
50	O	2	0	,	,
50	O	3	0	NN	adventure
50	O	4	0	,	,
50	O	5	0	CC	and
50	O	6	0	DT	the
50	O	7	0	JJ	ongoing
50	O	8	0	JJ	contemporary
50	O	9	0	NN	interest
50	O	10	0	IN	in
50	O	11	0	DT	these
50	O	12	0	JJ	faraway
50	O	13	0	NN	colonial
50	O	14	0	NNS	destinations
50	O	15	0	VBD	supplied
50	O	16	0	NNS	motifs
50	O	17	0	WDT	that
50	O	18	0	VBD	were
50	O	19	0	VBN	applied
50	O	20	0	TO	to
50	O	21	0	NNS	graphics
50	O	22	0	CC	and
50	O	23	0	NN	advertising
50	O	24	0	VBG	using
50	O	25	0	JJ	streamlined
50	PERSON	26	0	NNP	Art/Deco
50	O	27	0	NNS	forms
50	O	28	0	.	.

51	O	0	0	IN	After
51	O	1	0	DT	the
51	O	2	0	NNS	restrictions
51	O	3	0	IN	in
51	O	4	0	NN	place
51	O	5	0	IN	during
51	O	6	0	DT	the
51	O	7	0	NN	war
51	O	8	0	,	,
51	O	9	0	JJ	many
51	O	10	0	NNS	people
51	O	11	0	VBD	were
51	O	12	0	RB	now
51	O	13	0	VBN	captivated
51	O	14	0	IN	by
51	O	15	0	DT	the
51	O	16	0	NN	allure
51	O	17	0	IN	of
51	O	18	0	NN	travel
51	O	19	0	CC	and
51	O	20	0	NN	leisure
51	O	21	0	VBD	made
51	O	22	0	RB	increasingly
51	O	23	0	JJ	accessible
51	O	24	0	IN	with
51	O	25	0	DT	the
51	O	26	0	NN	automobile
51	O	27	0	,	,
51	O	28	0	NNS	railroads
51	O	29	0	,	,
51	O	30	0	CC	and
51	O	31	0	NN	luxury
51	O	32	0	NN	ocean
51	O	33	0	NNS	liners
51	O	34	0	.	.

52	O	0	0	DT	Some
52	O	1	0	IN	of
52	O	2	0	DT	the
52	O	3	0	RBS	most
52	O	4	0	JJ	representative
52	O	5	0	NNS	examples
52	O	6	0	IN	of
52	ORGANIZATION	7	0	NNP	Art/Deco
52	O	8	0	VBD	came
52	O	9	0	IN	from
52	O	10	0	DT	these
52	MISC	11	0	JJ	trans-Atlantic
52	O	12	0	NN	cruise
52	O	13	0	NNS	ships
52	O	14	0	.	.

53	O	0	0	DT	A
53	O	1	0	NN	poster
53	O	2	0	IN	by
53	PERSON	3	0	NNP	A./M./Cassandre
53	O	4	0	,	,
53	O	5	0	DT	a
53	O	6	0	VBG	leading
53	O	7	0	JJ	graphic
53	O	8	0	NN	artist
53	O	9	0	,	,
53	O	10	0	VBZ	advertises
53	O	11	0	DT	the
53	PERSON	12	0	NNP	Normandie
53	O	13	0	,	,
53	O	14	0	CD	one
53	O	15	0	IN	of
53	O	16	0	DT	the
53	O	17	0	JJS	largest
53	O	18	0	NN	cruise
53	O	19	0	NNS	ships
53	O	20	0	IN	from
53	O	21	0	DT	this
53	O	22	0	NN	era
53	O	23	0	,	,
53	O	24	0	IN	in
53	O	25	0	WDT	which
53	O	26	0	DT	the
53	O	27	0	JJ	tall
53	O	28	0	JJ	elegant
53	O	29	0	NN	ship
53	O	30	0	VBZ	glides
53	O	31	0	RB	majestically
53	O	32	0	IN	through
53	O	33	0	DT	the
53	O	34	0	JJ	calm
53	O	35	0	NN	water
53	O	36	0	,	,
53	O	37	0	PRP$	its
53	O	38	0	NN	bow
53	O	39	0	VBG	featuring
53	O	40	0	DT	the
53	O	41	0	JJ	streamlined
53	O	42	0	NN	curve
53	O	43	0	RB	so
53	O	44	0	JJ	representative
53	O	45	0	IN	of
53	ORGANIZATION	46	0	NNP	Art/Deco
53	O	47	0	.	.

54	MISC	0	0	NNP	Onboard
54	O	1	0	DT	these
54	O	2	0	NN	cruise
54	O	3	0	NNS	liners
54	O	4	0	,	,
54	O	5	0	DT	the
54	O	6	0	NN	luxury
54	O	7	0	CC	and
54	O	8	0	NN	craftsmanship
54	O	9	0	IN	of
54	ORGANIZATION	10	0	NNP	Art/Deco
54	O	11	0	VBD	realized
54	O	12	0	PRP$	its
54	O	13	0	JJS	fullest
54	O	14	0	NN	expression
54	O	15	0	IN	in
54	O	16	0	JJ	fantastical
54	O	17	0	CC	and
54	O	18	0	JJ	lavish
54	O	19	0	NNS	ensembles
54	O	20	0	IN	of
54	O	21	0	NN	furniture
54	O	22	0	,	,
54	O	23	0	NN	lighting
54	O	24	0	,	,
54	O	25	0	CC	and
54	O	26	0	NNS	artworks
54	O	27	0	WDT	that
54	O	28	0	VBD	fulfilled
54	O	29	0	DT	the
54	O	30	0	RBS	most
54	O	31	0	JJ	opulent
54	O	32	0	CC	and
54	O	33	0	JJ	luxurious
54	O	34	0	NNS	tastes
54	O	35	0	.	.

55	O	0	0	NN	\
55	O	1	0	CD	\
55	O	2	0	JJ	Much
55	O	3	0	IN	of
55	LOCATION	4	0	NNP	Art/Deco
55	O	5	0	VBZ	appears
55	O	6	0	IN	in
55	O	7	0	NN	hindsight
55	O	8	0	IN	as
55	O	9	0	DT	a
55	O	10	0	NN	glittering
55	O	11	0	NN	fa
55	O	12	0	CD	\
55	O	13	0	``	`
55	O	14	0	VB	e7ade
55	O	15	0	DT	that
55	O	16	0	VBD	hid
55	O	17	0	JJ	ongoing
55	O	18	0	JJ	economic
55	O	19	0	NNS	hardships
55	O	20	0	CC	and
55	O	21	0	JJ	political
55	O	22	0	NNS	instabilities
55	O	23	0	.	.

56	O	0	0	IN	In
56	O	1	0	DT	the
56	LOCATION	2	0	NNPS	United/States
56	O	3	0	,	,
56	O	4	0	NNP	Prohibition
56	O	5	0	VBD	led
56	O	6	0	TO	to
56	O	7	0	DT	the
56	O	8	0	NN	rise
56	O	9	0	IN	of
56	O	10	0	JJ	organized
56	O	11	0	NN	crime
56	O	12	0	CC	and
56	O	13	0	DT	a
56	O	14	0	NN	sense
56	O	15	0	IN	of
56	O	16	0	NN	illicitness
56	O	17	0	VBN	associated
56	O	18	0	IN	with
56	O	19	0	NN	jazz
56	O	20	0	NNS	clubs
56	O	21	0	CC	and
56	O	22	0	JJ	popular
56	O	23	0	NN	culture
56	O	24	0	.	.

57	O	0	0	IN	As
57	O	1	0	JJ	many
57	O	2	0	NNS	people
57	O	3	0	VBD	sought
57	O	4	0	TO	to
57	O	5	0	VB	escape
57	O	6	0	PRP$	their
57	O	7	0	JJ	mundane
57	O	8	0	JJ	daily
57	O	9	0	NNS	concerns
57	O	10	0	,	,
57	O	11	0	DT	the
57	O	12	0	NNS	movies
57	O	13	0	VBD	provided
57	O	14	0	DT	a
57	O	15	0	JJ	great
57	O	16	0	NN	refuge
57	O	17	0	.	.

58	O	0	0	NNS	Costumes
58	O	1	0	,	,
58	O	2	0	NNS	sets
58	O	3	0	,	,
58	O	4	0	CC	and
58	O	5	0	NN	lighting
58	O	6	0	VBD	were
58	O	7	0	DT	all
58	O	8	0	NNS	vehicles
58	O	9	0	IN	for
58	O	10	0	VBG	popularizing
58	O	11	0	DT	the
58	O	12	0	JJ	elegant
58	O	13	0	CC	and
58	O	14	0	JJ	seductive
58	O	15	0	NN	atmosphere
58	O	16	0	IN	of
58	ORGANIZATION	17	0	NNP	Art/Deco
58	O	18	0	.	.

59	O	0	0	NN	\
59	O	1	0	CD	\
59	O	2	0	DT	The
59	O	3	0	NN	popularity
59	O	4	0	IN	of
59	ORGANIZATION	5	0	NNP	Art/Deco
59	O	6	0	VBD	waned
59	O	7	0	IN	as
59	O	8	0	NN	interest
59	O	9	0	VBD	grew
59	O	10	0	IN	in
59	O	11	0	NN	cost
59	O	12	0	JJ	effective
59	O	13	0	NN	mass
59	O	14	0	NN	production
59	O	15	0	CC	and
59	O	16	0	JJ	industrial
59	O	17	0	NNS	materials
59	O	18	0	,	,
59	O	19	0	JJ	such
59	O	20	0	IN	as
59	O	21	0	JJ	tubular
59	O	22	0	NN	steel
59	O	23	0	,	,
59	O	24	0	WDT	that
59	O	25	0	VBD	lacked
59	O	26	0	JJ	excess
59	O	27	0	NN	ornamentation
59	O	28	0	CC	and
59	O	29	0	VBD	was
59	O	30	0	VBN	suited
59	O	31	0	TO	to
59	O	32	0	DT	the
59	O	33	0	NN	ethos
59	O	34	0	IN	of
59	O	35	0	NN	\
59	O	36	0	''	'
59	O	37	0	JJ	91form
59	O	38	0	VBG	following
59	O	39	0	NN	function
59	O	40	0	CD	\
59	O	41	0	CD	'92
59	O	42	0	WDT	that
59	O	43	0	VBD	began
59	O	44	0	TO	to
59	O	45	0	VB	influence
59	O	46	0	DT	the
59	O	47	0	NN	direction
59	O	48	0	IN	of
59	O	49	0	JJ	modern
59	O	50	0	NN	design
59	O	51	0	IN	from
59	O	52	0	NNS	architects
59	O	53	0	JJ	such
59	O	54	0	IN	as
59	ORGANIZATION	55	0	NNP	Le/Corbusier
59	O	56	0	CC	and
59	PERSON	57	0	NNP	Walter/Gropius
59	O	58	0	.	.

60	O	0	0	DT	The
60	O	1	0	VBG	burgeoning
60	O	2	0	NN	modernism
60	O	3	0	IN	of
60	O	4	0	DT	the
60	MISC	5	0	NNP	Bauhaus
60	O	6	0	JJ	aesthetic
60	O	7	0	VBD	existed
60	O	8	0	RB	harmoniously
60	O	9	0	IN	with
60	O	10	0	DT	the
60	O	11	0	JJ	streamlined
60	PERSON	12	0	NNP	Art/Deco
60	O	13	0	TO	to
60	O	14	0	DT	an
60	O	15	0	NN	extent
60	O	16	0	IN	as
60	O	17	0	DT	the
60	O	18	0	JJ	chaise-lounge
60	O	19	0	NN	chair
60	O	20	0	IN	by
60	ORGANIZATION	21	0	NNP	Le/Corbusier
60	O	22	0	,	,
60	PERSON	23	0	NNP	Pierre/Jeanneret
60	O	24	0	,	,
60	O	25	0	CC	and
60	PERSON	26	0	NNP	Charlotte/Perriand
60	O	27	0	IN	in
60	O	28	0	JJ	chrome-plated
60	O	29	0	JJ	tubular
60	O	30	0	NN	steel
60	O	31	0	VBN	covered
60	O	32	0	IN	with
60	O	33	0	NN	cowhide
60	O	34	0	NN	upholstery
60	O	35	0	VBZ	illustrates
60	O	36	0	.	.

61	O	0	0	DT	The
61	O	1	0	NN	disregard
61	O	2	0	IN	for
61	O	3	0	NN	cost
61	O	4	0	CC	or
61	O	5	0	NN	practicality
61	O	6	0	IN	in
61	O	7	0	DT	the
61	O	8	0	NNS	materials
61	O	9	0	CC	and
61	O	10	0	DT	the
61	O	11	0	JJ	opulent
61	O	12	0	NNS	designs
61	O	13	0	IN	of
61	ORGANIZATION	14	0	NNP	Art/Deco
61	O	15	0	NNS	ensembles
61	O	16	0	RB	eventually
61	O	17	0	VBD	led
61	O	18	0	TO	to
61	O	19	0	PRP$	its
61	O	20	0	NN	demise
61	O	21	0	,	,
61	O	22	0	DT	an
61	O	23	0	NN	end
61	O	24	0	WDT	that
61	O	25	0	VBD	was
61	O	26	0	JJ	inescapable
61	O	27	0	IN	with
61	O	28	0	DT	the
61	O	29	0	NN	beginning
61	O	30	0	IN	of
61	O	31	0	DT	the
61	LOCATION	32	0	NNP	Great/Depression
61	O	33	0	IN	in
61	O	34	0	CD	1929
61	O	35	0	CC	and
61	O	36	0	VBG	escalating
61	O	37	0	JJ	political
61	O	38	0	NNS	tensions
61	O	39	0	IN	throughout
61	LOCATION	40	0	NNP	Europe
61	O	41	0	IN	in
61	O	42	0	DT	the
61	O	43	0	NNS	1930s
61	O	44	0	.	.

62	O	0	0	NN	\
62	O	1	0	CD	\
62	O	2	0	DT	The
62	O	3	0	RBS	most
62	O	4	0	JJ	triumphant
62	O	5	0	JJ	crowning
62	O	6	0	NNS	examples
62	O	7	0	IN	of
62	ORGANIZATION	8	0	NNP	Art/Deco
62	O	9	0	NN	architecture
62	O	10	0	VBP	are
62	O	11	0	DT	the
62	O	12	0	NNS	skyscrapers
62	O	13	0	IN	in
62	LOCATION	14	0	NNP	New/York/City
62	O	15	0	,	,
62	O	16	0	VBG	including
62	O	17	0	DT	the
62	ORGANIZATION	18	0	NNP	Chrysler/Building
62	O	19	0	,	,
62	O	20	0	CD	1927-30
62	O	21	0	,	,
62	O	22	0	CC	and
62	O	23	0	DT	the
62	ORGANIZATION	24	0	NNP	Empire/State/Building
62	O	25	0	,	,
62	O	26	0	CD	1929-31
62	O	27	0	.	.

63	O	0	0	JJ	Geometric
63	O	1	0	CC	and
63	O	2	0	VBD	stepped
63	O	3	0	JJ	pyramidal
63	O	4	0	NNS	forms
63	O	5	0	IN	in
63	O	6	0	DT	each
63	O	7	0	VBP	evoke
63	O	8	0	DT	the
63	O	9	0	JJ	streamlined
63	O	10	0	JJ	aesthetic
63	O	11	0	IN	that
63	O	12	0	VBD	prevailed
63	O	13	0	IN	in
63	O	14	0	DT	the
63	O	15	0	JJ	preceding
63	O	16	0	NN	period
63	O	17	0	.	.

64	O	0	0	DT	These
64	O	1	0	VBP	serve
64	O	2	0	IN	as
64	O	3	0	DT	a
64	O	4	0	JJ	dynamic
64	O	5	0	NN	reminder
64	O	6	0	IN	of
64	O	7	0	DT	the
64	LOCATION	8	0	NNP	Art/Deco
64	O	9	0	,	,
64	O	10	0	DT	the
64	O	11	0	JJ	final
64	O	12	0	NN	design
64	O	13	0	NN	style
64	O	14	0	IN	of
64	O	15	0	DT	the
64	O	16	0	JJ	twentieth-century
64	O	17	0	DT	that
64	O	18	0	VBD	was
64	O	19	0	VBN	conceived
64	O	20	0	IN	of
64	O	21	0	IN	as
64	O	22	0	DT	a
64	O	23	0	JJ	complete
64	O	24	0	CC	and
64	O	25	0	JJ	all-encompassing
64	O	26	0	NN	program
64	O	27	0	VBG	uniting
64	O	28	0	NN	architecture
64	O	29	0	,	,
64	O	30	0	NNS	arts
64	O	31	0	,	,
64	O	32	0	NN	clothing
64	O	33	0	,	,
64	O	34	0	NNS	graphics
64	O	35	0	,	,
64	O	36	0	CC	and
64	O	37	0	DT	the
64	O	38	0	VBN	applied
64	O	39	0	NNS	arts
64	O	40	0	.	.

65	O	0	0	NN	\
65	O	1	0	-RRB-	-RCB-

0	PERSON	0	0	NNP	Ball
0	O	1	0	,	,
0	PERSON	2	0	NNP	Hugo
0	O	3	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
0	O	4	0	CD	1886-1927
0	O	5	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
0	O	6	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
0	O	7	0	VB	Enter
0	O	8	0	DT	any
0	O	9	0	JJ	variant
0	O	10	0	NNS	forms
0	O	11	0	IN	of
0	O	12	0	PRP$	your
0	O	13	0	NN	headword
0	O	14	0	:	--
0	O	15	0	NN	OPTIONAL
0	O	16	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
0	LOCATION	17	0	VBN	Born
0	O	18	0	IN	in
0	LOCATION	19	0	NNP	Pirmasens
0	O	20	0	IN	on
0	O	21	0	CD	22
0	O	22	0	NNP	February
0	O	23	0	CD	1886
0	O	24	0	,	,
0	O	25	0	DT	the
0	MISC	26	0	JJ	German
0	O	27	0	NN	writer
0	PERSON	28	0	NNP	Hugo/Ball
0	O	29	0	VBZ	is
0	O	30	0	RB	best
0	O	31	0	VBN	known
0	O	32	0	IN	as
0	O	33	0	DT	the
0	O	34	0	NN	co-founder
0	O	35	0	,	,
0	O	36	0	IN	with
0	PERSON	37	0	NNP	Tristan/Tzara
0	O	38	0	,	,
0	O	39	0	IN	of
0	O	40	0	DT	the
0	ORGANIZATION	41	0	NNP	Cabaret/Voltaire
0	O	42	0	CC	and
0	O	43	0	DT	the
0	MISC	44	0	NNP	Dada
0	O	45	0	NN	movement
0	O	46	0	IN	in
0	LOCATION	47	0	NNP	Zurich
0	O	48	0	.	.

1	O	0	0	JJ	Active
1	O	1	0	RB	initially
1	O	2	0	IN	as
1	O	3	0	DT	an
1	MISC	4	0	JJ	Expressionist
1	O	5	0	NN	playwright
1	O	6	0	CC	and
1	O	7	0	NN	dramaturge
1	O	8	0	IN	in
1	LOCATION	9	0	NNP	Munich
1	O	10	0	CC	and
1	O	11	0	IN	as
1	O	12	0	DT	a
1	O	13	0	NN	journalist
1	O	14	0	CC	and
1	O	15	0	JJ	literary
1	O	16	0	NN	critic
1	O	17	0	IN	in
1	LOCATION	18	0	NNP	Berlin
1	O	19	0	IN	in
1	O	20	0	DT	the
1	O	21	0	NNS	years
1	O	22	0	VBG	leading
1	O	23	0	RP	up
1	O	24	0	TO	to
1	MISC	25	0	NNP	World/War
1	O	26	0	NNP	I
1	O	27	0	,	,
1	PERSON	28	0	NNP	Ball
1	O	29	0	VBD	left
1	LOCATION	30	0	NNP	Germany
1	O	31	0	IN	with
1	O	32	0	PRP$	his
1	O	33	0	NN	companion
1	O	34	0	CC	and
1	O	35	0	JJ	future
1	O	36	0	NN	wife
1	PERSON	37	0	NNP	Emmy/Hennings
1	O	38	0	IN	in
1	O	39	0	CD	1915
1	O	40	0	.	.

2	O	0	0	PRP	They
2	O	1	0	VBD	remained
2	O	2	0	IN	in
2	LOCATION	3	0	NNP	Switzerland
2	O	4	0	IN	for
2	O	5	0	DT	the
2	O	6	0	NN	rest
2	O	7	0	IN	of
2	O	8	0	PRP$	their
2	O	9	0	NNS	lives
2	O	10	0	.	.

3	O	0	0	VBG	Following
3	O	1	0	PRP$	his
3	O	2	0	NN	period
3	O	3	0	IN	of
3	LOCATION	4	0	NN	Dada
3	O	5	0	NNS	activities
3	O	6	0	IN	in
3	O	7	0	CD	1916
3	O	8	0	CC	and
3	O	9	0	CD	1917
3	O	10	0	,	,
3	PERSON	11	0	NNP	Ball
3	O	12	0	VBD	was
3	O	13	0	DT	a
3	O	14	0	NN	journalist
3	O	15	0	IN	for
3	O	16	0	DT	a
3	O	17	0	JJ	centre-left
3	O	18	0	NN	newspaper
3	O	19	0	IN	for
3	O	20	0	CD	three
3	O	21	0	NNS	years
3	O	22	0	.	.

4	O	0	0	VBG	Reconverting
4	O	1	0	TO	to
4	O	2	0	DT	the
4	MISC	3	0	NNP	Catholic
4	O	4	0	NN	faith
4	O	5	0	IN	of
4	O	6	0	PRP$	his
4	O	7	0	NN	childhood
4	O	8	0	,	,
4	PERSON	9	0	NNP	Ball
4	O	10	0	VBD	spent
4	O	11	0	DT	the
4	O	12	0	NN	remainder
4	O	13	0	IN	of
4	O	14	0	PRP$	his
4	O	15	0	NN	life
4	O	16	0	IN	in
4	O	17	0	JJ	relative
4	O	18	0	NN	seclusion
4	O	19	0	IN	in
4	LOCATION	20	0	NNP	Ticino
4	O	21	0	,	,
4	O	22	0	WRB	where
4	O	23	0	PRP	he
4	O	24	0	VBD	wrote
4	O	25	0	DT	a
4	O	26	0	NN	series
4	O	27	0	IN	of
4	O	28	0	JJ	religious
4	O	29	0	NNS	books
4	O	30	0	CC	and
4	O	31	0	VBD	revised
4	O	32	0	PRP$	his
4	O	33	0	NNS	diaries
4	O	34	0	IN	for
4	O	35	0	NN	publication.Born
4	O	36	0	IN	in
4	LOCATION	37	0	NNP	Pirmasens
4	O	38	0	IN	on
4	O	39	0	CD	22
4	O	40	0	NNP	February
4	O	41	0	CD	1886
4	O	42	0	,	,
4	O	43	0	DT	the
4	MISC	44	0	JJ	German
4	O	45	0	NN	writer
4	PERSON	46	0	NNP	Hugo/Ball
4	O	47	0	VBZ	is
4	O	48	0	RB	best
4	O	49	0	VBN	known
4	O	50	0	IN	as
4	O	51	0	DT	the
4	O	52	0	NN	co-founder
4	O	53	0	,	,
4	O	54	0	IN	with
4	PERSON	55	0	NNP	Tristan/Tzara
4	O	56	0	,	,
4	O	57	0	IN	of
4	O	58	0	DT	the
4	ORGANIZATION	59	0	NNP	Cabaret/Voltaire
4	O	60	0	CC	and
4	O	61	0	DT	the
4	MISC	62	0	NNP	Dada
4	O	63	0	NN	movement
4	O	64	0	IN	in
4	LOCATION	65	0	NNP	Zurich
4	O	66	0	.	.

5	O	0	0	JJ	Active
5	O	1	0	RB	initially
5	O	2	0	IN	as
5	O	3	0	DT	an
5	MISC	4	0	JJ	Expressionist
5	O	5	0	NN	playwright
5	O	6	0	CC	and
5	O	7	0	NN	dramaturge
5	O	8	0	IN	in
5	LOCATION	9	0	NNP	Munich
5	O	10	0	CC	and
5	O	11	0	IN	as
5	O	12	0	DT	a
5	O	13	0	NN	journalist
5	O	14	0	CC	and
5	O	15	0	JJ	literary
5	O	16	0	NN	critic
5	O	17	0	IN	in
5	LOCATION	18	0	NNP	Berlin
5	O	19	0	IN	in
5	O	20	0	DT	the
5	O	21	0	NNS	years
5	O	22	0	VBG	leading
5	O	23	0	RP	up
5	O	24	0	TO	to
5	MISC	25	0	NNP	World/War
5	O	26	0	NNP	I
5	O	27	0	,	,
5	PERSON	28	0	NNP	Ball
5	O	29	0	VBD	left
5	LOCATION	30	0	NNP	Germany
5	O	31	0	IN	with
5	O	32	0	PRP$	his
5	O	33	0	NN	companion
5	O	34	0	CC	and
5	O	35	0	JJ	future
5	O	36	0	NN	wife
5	PERSON	37	0	NNP	Emmy/Hennings
5	O	38	0	IN	in
5	O	39	0	CD	1915
5	O	40	0	.	.

6	O	0	0	PRP	They
6	O	1	0	VBD	remained
6	O	2	0	IN	in
6	LOCATION	3	0	NNP	Switzerland
6	O	4	0	IN	for
6	O	5	0	DT	the
6	O	6	0	NN	rest
6	O	7	0	IN	of
6	O	8	0	PRP$	their
6	O	9	0	NNS	lives
6	O	10	0	.	.

7	O	0	0	VBG	Following
7	O	1	0	PRP$	his
7	O	2	0	NN	period
7	O	3	0	IN	of
7	LOCATION	4	0	NN	Dada
7	O	5	0	NNS	activities
7	O	6	0	IN	in
7	O	7	0	CD	1916
7	O	8	0	CC	and
7	O	9	0	CD	1917
7	O	10	0	,	,
7	PERSON	11	0	NNP	Ball
7	O	12	0	VBD	was
7	O	13	0	DT	a
7	O	14	0	NN	journalist
7	O	15	0	IN	for
7	O	16	0	DT	a
7	O	17	0	JJ	centre-left
7	O	18	0	NN	newspaper
7	O	19	0	IN	for
7	O	20	0	CD	three
7	O	21	0	NNS	years
7	O	22	0	.	.

8	O	0	0	VBG	Reconverting
8	O	1	0	TO	to
8	O	2	0	DT	the
8	MISC	3	0	NNP	Catholic
8	O	4	0	NN	faith
8	O	5	0	IN	of
8	O	6	0	PRP$	his
8	O	7	0	NN	childhood
8	O	8	0	,	,
8	PERSON	9	0	NNP	Ball
8	O	10	0	VBD	spent
8	O	11	0	DT	the
8	O	12	0	NN	remainder
8	O	13	0	IN	of
8	O	14	0	PRP$	his
8	O	15	0	NN	life
8	O	16	0	IN	in
8	O	17	0	JJ	relative
8	O	18	0	NN	seclusion
8	O	19	0	IN	in
8	LOCATION	20	0	NNP	Ticino
8	O	21	0	,	,
8	O	22	0	WRB	where
8	O	23	0	PRP	he
8	O	24	0	VBD	wrote
8	O	25	0	DT	a
8	O	26	0	NN	series
8	O	27	0	IN	of
8	O	28	0	JJ	religious
8	O	29	0	NNS	books
8	O	30	0	CC	and
8	O	31	0	VBD	revised
8	O	32	0	PRP$	his
8	O	33	0	NNS	diaries
8	O	34	0	IN	for
8	O	35	0	NN	publication.A
8	O	36	0	NN	series
8	O	37	0	IN	of
8	O	38	0	RB	fairly
8	O	39	0	JJ	conventional
8	O	40	0	JJ	romantic
8	O	41	0	NN	nature
8	O	42	0	NNS	poems
8	O	43	0	,	,
8	O	44	0	VBN	published
8	O	45	0	IN	in
8	O	46	0	DT	the
8	O	47	0	JJ	local
8	O	48	0	NN	journal
8	PERSON	49	0	NNP	Der/Pflzerwald
8	O	50	0	,	,
8	O	51	0	VBD	constituted
8	PERSON	52	0	NNP	Ball
8	O	53	0	POS	's
8	O	54	0	JJ	literary
8	O	55	0	NN	debut
8	O	56	0	.	.

9	O	0	0	VBG	Enrolling
9	O	1	0	IN	at
9	O	2	0	DT	the
9	ORGANIZATION	3	0	NNP	University/of/Munich
9	O	4	0	,	,
9	O	5	0	PRP	he
9	O	6	0	VBD	began
9	O	7	0	NN	work
9	O	8	0	IN	on
9	O	9	0	DT	a
9	O	10	0	NN	dissertation
9	O	11	0	VBN	entitled
9	ORGANIZATION	12	0	NNP	Nietzsche
9	O	13	0	IN	in
9	LOCATION	14	0	NNP	Basel
9	O	15	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
9	O	16	0	VBG	surviving
9	O	17	0	NNS	fragments
9	O	18	0	VBN	published
9	O	19	0	IN	in
9	O	20	0	CD	1978
9	O	21	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
9	O	22	0	,	,
9	O	23	0	CC	but
9	O	24	0	DT	this
9	O	25	0	NN	work
9	O	26	0	,	,
9	O	27	0	RB	as
9	O	28	0	RB	well
9	O	29	0	IN	as
9	O	30	0	PRP$	his
9	O	31	0	JJ	academic
9	O	32	0	NNS	studies
9	O	33	0	,	,
9	O	34	0	VBD	remained
9	O	35	0	NN	incomplete.The
9	O	36	0	NNS	years
9	O	37	0	CD	1910-1914
9	O	38	0	VBD	marked
9	O	39	0	DT	the
9	O	40	0	NN	period
9	O	41	0	IN	of
9	PERSON	42	0	NNP	Ball
9	O	43	0	POS	's
9	O	44	0	RBS	most
9	O	45	0	JJ	active
9	O	46	0	NN	involvement
9	O	47	0	IN	in
9	O	48	0	DT	the
9	O	49	0	NN	theatre
9	O	50	0	NNS	scenes
9	O	51	0	IN	in
9	LOCATION	52	0	NNP	Munich
9	O	53	0	CC	and
9	LOCATION	54	0	NNP	Berlin
9	O	55	0	.	.

10	O	0	0	PRP	It
10	O	1	0	VBD	was
10	O	2	0	IN	during
10	O	3	0	DT	these
10	O	4	0	NNS	years
10	O	5	0	WDT	that
10	PERSON	6	0	NNP	Wassily/Kandinsky
10	O	7	0	VBD	became
10	O	8	0	DT	a
10	O	9	0	JJ	key
10	O	10	0	NN	influence
10	O	11	0	IN	on
10	PERSON	12	0	NNP	Ball
10	O	13	0	POS	's
10	O	14	0	NN	approach
10	O	15	0	TO	to
10	O	16	0	DT	the
10	O	17	0	NNS	arts
10	O	18	0	.	.

11	O	0	0	DT	The
11	O	1	0	NN	advent
11	O	2	0	IN	of
11	O	3	0	DT	the
11	O	4	0	NN	war
11	O	5	0	VBD	prevented
11	O	6	0	DT	the
11	O	7	0	CD	two
11	O	8	0	IN	from
11	O	9	0	VBG	realizing
11	O	10	0	PRP$	their
11	O	11	0	NN	project
11	O	12	0	TO	to
11	O	13	0	VBN	found
11	O	14	0	DT	an
11	O	15	0	``	`
11	O	16	0	NNS	artists
11	O	17	0	POS	'
11	O	18	0	NN	theatre
11	O	19	0	,	,
11	O	20	0	''	'
11	O	21	0	CC	but
11	O	22	0	DT	the
11	MISC	23	0	JJ	Russian
11	O	24	0	NN	artist
11	O	25	0	POS	's
11	O	26	0	NN	philosophy
11	O	27	0	IN	of
11	O	28	0	JJ	total
11	O	29	0	NN	theatre
11	O	30	0	MD	would
11	O	31	0	VB	inform
11	O	32	0	DT	the
11	O	33	0	NNS	performances
11	O	34	0	VBN	held
11	O	35	0	IN	in
11	LOCATION	36	0	NNP	Zurich
11	O	37	0	DT	a
11	O	38	0	JJ	few
11	O	39	0	NNS	years
11	O	40	0	NNP	later.While
11	PERSON	41	0	NNP	Ball
11	O	42	0	VBD	played
11	O	43	0	DT	a
11	O	44	0	JJ	significant
11	O	45	0	NN	role
11	O	46	0	IN	in
11	MISC	47	0	JJ	German
11	O	48	0	NN	theatre
11	O	49	0	IN	during
11	O	50	0	DT	this
11	O	51	0	NN	period
11	O	52	0	,	,
11	O	53	0	PRP	he
11	O	54	0	VBD	achieved
11	O	55	0	JJ	little
11	O	56	0	NN	success
11	O	57	0	IN	as
11	O	58	0	DT	a
11	O	59	0	NN	playwright
11	O	60	0	.	.

12	O	0	0	IN	Although
12	O	1	0	CD	one
12	O	2	0	NN	play
12	O	3	0	,	,
12	PERSON	4	0	NNP	Die/Nase/des/Michelangelo
12	O	5	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
12	O	6	0	CD	1911
12	O	7	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
12	O	8	0	,	,
12	O	9	0	CC	and
12	O	10	0	DT	the
12	O	11	0	JJ	first
12	O	12	0	NN	act
12	O	13	0	IN	of
12	O	14	0	DT	another
12	O	15	0	,	,
12	PERSON	16	0	NNP	Der/Henker
12	O	17	0	NNP	von
12	ORGANIZATION	18	0	NNP	Brescia
12	O	19	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
12	O	20	0	CD	1914
12	O	21	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
12	O	22	0	,	,
12	O	23	0	VBD	were
12	O	24	0	VBN	published
12	O	25	0	,	,
12	O	26	0	NN	none
12	O	27	0	VBD	was
12	O	28	0	VBN	produced
12	O	29	0	IN	in
12	LOCATION	30	0	NNP	Germany
12	O	31	0	IN	in
12	O	32	0	DT	the
12	O	33	0	NN	author
12	O	34	0	POS	's
12	O	35	0	NN	lifetime
12	O	36	0	.	.

13	O	0	0	NNP	Ball
13	O	1	0	RB	also
13	O	2	0	VBD	contributed
13	O	3	0	NNS	poems
13	O	4	0	TO	to
13	O	5	0	JJ	several
13	O	6	0	IN	of
13	O	7	0	DT	the
13	O	8	0	JJ	major
13	MISC	9	0	NN	Expressionist
13	O	10	0	NNS	journals
13	O	11	0	.	.

14	O	0	0	CD	One
14	O	1	0	IN	of
14	O	2	0	DT	these
14	O	3	0	NNS	poems
14	O	4	0	,	,
14	O	5	0	``	`
14	PERSON	6	0	FW	Der/Henker
14	O	7	0	''	'
14	O	8	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
14	O	9	0	CD	1913
14	O	10	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
14	O	11	0	,	,
14	O	12	0	VBN	published
14	O	13	0	IN	in
14	O	14	0	DT	the
14	O	15	0	JJ	inaugural
14	O	16	0	NN	issue
14	O	17	0	IN	of
14	O	18	0	NN	Revolution
14	O	19	0	,	,
14	O	20	0	VBD	caused
14	O	21	0	IN	that
14	O	22	0	NN	journal
14	O	23	0	TO	to
14	O	24	0	VB	be
14	O	25	0	VBN	seized
14	O	26	0	IN	by
14	O	27	0	DT	the
14	O	28	0	NNS	authorities
14	O	29	0	IN	for
14	O	30	0	NN	obscenity
14	O	31	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
14	O	32	0	DT	an
14	O	33	0	NN	action
14	O	34	0	RB	later
14	O	35	0	VBD	reversed
14	O	36	0	IN	in
14	O	37	0	NN	court
14	O	38	0	IN	because
14	O	39	0	DT	the
14	O	40	0	NN	poem
14	O	41	0	VBD	was
14	O	42	0	VBN	deemed
14	O	43	0	RB	too
14	O	44	0	JJ	obscure
14	O	45	0	TO	to
14	O	46	0	VB	be
14	O	47	0	JJ	obscene
14	O	48	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
14	O	49	0	.	.

15	O	0	0	IN	In
15	O	1	0	NN	addition
15	O	2	0	,	,
15	PERSON	3	0	NNP	Ball
15	O	4	0	VBD	wrote
15	O	5	0	CC	and
15	O	6	0	VBD	published
15	O	7	0	NN	poetry
15	O	8	0	RB	pseudonymously
15	O	9	0	IN	in
15	O	10	0	NN	collaboration
15	O	11	0	IN	with
15	PERSON	12	0	NNP	Hans/Leybold
15	O	13	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
15	O	14	0	VBN	signed
15	O	15	0	``	`
15	PERSON	16	0	NN	Ha/Hu/Baley
15	O	17	0	''	'
15	O	18	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
15	O	19	0	CC	and
15	O	20	0	IN	with
15	PERSON	21	0	NN	Klabund
15	O	22	0	CC	and
15	ORGANIZATION	23	0	NNP	Marietta/di/Monaco
15	O	24	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
15	O	25	0	IN	as
15	O	26	0	``	`
15	PERSON	27	0	NNP	Klarinetta/Klaball
15	O	28	0	POS	'
15	O	29	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
15	O	30	0	.	.

16	O	0	0	VBG	Sharing
16	O	1	0	IN	with
16	O	2	0	JJ	many
16	O	3	0	JJ	youthful
16	MISC	4	0	JJ	German
16	O	5	0	NNS	intellectuals
16	O	6	0	DT	an
16	O	7	0	JJ	initial
16	O	8	0	NN	enthusiasm
16	O	9	0	IN	for
16	O	10	0	DT	the
16	O	11	0	NN	war
16	O	12	0	,	,
16	O	13	0	CC	and
16	O	14	0	VBG	volunteering
16	O	15	0	RB	unsuccessfully
16	O	16	0	IN	for
16	O	17	0	JJ	military
16	O	18	0	NN	duty
16	O	19	0	,	,
16	PERSON	20	0	NNP	Ball
16	O	21	0	VBD	leaned
16	O	22	0	RB	increasingly
16	O	23	0	IN	toward
16	O	24	0	NN	pacifism
16	O	25	0	IN	after
16	O	26	0	VBG	witnessing
16	O	27	0	DT	the
16	O	28	0	NNS	horrors
16	O	29	0	IN	of
16	O	30	0	JJ	modern
16	O	31	0	NN	warfare
16	O	32	0	IN	during
16	O	33	0	DT	a
16	O	34	0	NN	visit
16	O	35	0	TO	to
16	O	36	0	DT	the
16	O	37	0	NN	front
16	O	38	0	.	.

17	O	0	0	RBR	More
17	O	1	0	CC	and
17	O	2	0	RBR	more
17	O	3	0	JJ	outspoken
17	O	4	0	IN	as
17	O	5	0	DT	a
17	O	6	0	NN	journalist
17	O	7	0	CC	and
17	O	8	0	NN	organiser
17	O	9	0	IN	of
17	O	10	0	JJ	public
17	O	11	0	NNS	events
17	O	12	0	IN	in
17	LOCATION	13	0	NNP	Berlin
17	O	14	0	,	,
17	O	15	0	DT	the
17	O	16	0	NN	author
17	O	17	0	RB	finally
17	O	18	0	VBD	found
17	O	19	0	PRP	it
17	O	20	0	JJ	necessary
17	O	21	0	TO	to
17	O	22	0	VB	immigrate
17	O	23	0	TO	to
17	LOCATION	24	0	NNP	Zurich
17	O	25	0	IN	in
17	O	26	0	NNP	May
17	O	27	0	CD	1915
17	O	28	0	.	.

18	O	0	0	RB	There
18	O	1	0	,	,
18	O	2	0	PRP	he
18	O	3	0	CC	and
18	PERSON	4	0	NNP	Hennings
18	O	5	0	RB	barely
18	O	6	0	VBD	managed
18	O	7	0	TO	to
18	O	8	0	VB	earn
18	O	9	0	DT	a
18	O	10	0	NN	living
18	O	11	0	IN	as
18	O	12	0	NNS	members
18	O	13	0	IN	of
18	O	14	0	DT	a
18	O	15	0	JJ	small
18	O	16	0	NN	cabaret
18	O	17	0	NN	company
18	O	18	0	.	.

19	O	0	0	IN	In
19	O	1	0	NNP	February
19	O	2	0	CD	1916
19	PERSON	3	0	NNP	Ball
19	O	4	0	CC	and
19	PERSON	5	0	NNP	Hennings
19	O	6	0	,	,
19	O	7	0	RB	together
19	O	8	0	IN	with
19	O	9	0	JJ	other
19	O	10	0	NNS	artists
19	O	11	0	WP	who
19	O	12	0	VBD	had
19	O	13	0	VBN	taken
19	O	14	0	NN	refuge
19	O	15	0	IN	in
19	O	16	0	JJ	neutral
19	LOCATION	17	0	NNP	Switzerland
19	O	18	0	,	,
19	O	19	0	VBD	founded
19	O	20	0	DT	the
19	PERSON	21	0	NNP	Cabaret/Voltaire
19	O	22	0	,	,
19	O	23	0	WP$	whose
19	O	24	0	JJ	riotous
19	O	25	0	,	,
19	O	26	0	JJ	multilingual
19	O	27	0	NNS	performances
19	O	28	0	VBD	gave
19	O	29	0	NN	rise
19	O	30	0	IN	within
19	O	31	0	DT	a
19	O	32	0	JJ	few
19	O	33	0	NNS	months
19	O	34	0	TO	to
19	O	35	0	DT	the
19	LOCATION	36	0	NNP	Dada
19	O	37	0	NN	movement
19	O	38	0	.	.

20	PERSON	0	0	NNP	Ball
20	O	1	0	POS	's
20	O	2	0	NN	involvement
20	O	3	0	IN	in
20	O	4	0	DT	the
20	O	5	0	NN	movement
20	O	6	0	VBD	was
20	O	7	0	JJ	intense
20	O	8	0	,	,
20	O	9	0	CC	but
20	O	10	0	JJ	short-lived
20	O	11	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
20	O	12	0	CD	1916-1917
20	O	13	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
20	O	14	0	.	.

21	O	0	0	PRP	He
21	O	1	0	VBD	wrote
21	O	2	0	CC	and
21	O	3	0	VBD	performed
21	O	4	0	NNS	poems
21	O	5	0	CC	and
21	O	6	0	NNS	sketches
21	O	7	0	,	,
21	O	8	0	VBD	lectured
21	O	9	0	,	,
21	O	10	0	CC	and
21	O	11	0	VBD	played
21	O	12	0	NN	piano
21	O	13	0	.	.

22	PERSON	0	0	NNP	Ball
22	O	1	0	POS	's
22	O	2	0	JJS	most
22	O	3	0	JJ	influential
22	O	4	0	NNS	works
22	O	5	0	VBP	stem
22	O	6	0	IN	from
22	O	7	0	DT	this
22	O	8	0	JJ	brief
22	PERSON	9	0	NN	Dada
22	O	10	0	NN	period
22	O	11	0	.	.

23	O	0	0	DT	The
23	O	1	0	JJS	best-known
23	O	2	0	IN	of
23	O	3	0	DT	these
23	O	4	0	VBP	are
23	O	5	0	PRP$	his
23	O	6	0	CD	six
23	O	7	0	JJ	sound
23	O	8	0	NNS	poems
23	O	9	0	IN	of
23	O	10	0	CD	1916
23	O	11	0	,	,
23	O	12	0	NNS	compositions
23	O	13	0	VBN	comprised
23	O	14	0	IN	of
23	O	15	0	RB	apparently
23	O	16	0	JJ	meaningless
23	O	17	0	NNS	syllables
23	O	18	0	CC	but
23	O	19	0	VBN	filled
23	O	20	0	IN	with
23	O	21	0	JJ	onomatopoeic
23	O	22	0	NNS	effects
23	O	23	0	CC	and
23	O	24	0	JJ	occasional
23	O	25	0	NNS	allusions
23	O	26	0	TO	to
23	MISC	27	0	JJ	German
23	O	28	0	NN	vocabulary
23	O	29	0	,	,
23	O	30	0	VBN	intended
23	O	31	0	IN	for
23	O	32	0	NN	recitation
23	O	33	0	IN	at
23	O	34	0	DT	the
23	ORGANIZATION	35	0	NNP	Cabaret/Voltaire
23	O	36	0	CC	and
23	O	37	0	JJ	similar
23	O	38	0	NNS	venues
23	O	39	0	VBP	File
23	O	40	0	:	:
23	O	41	0	DT	The
23	ORGANIZATION	42	0	NN	Sound/Poem/`/Karawane
23	O	43	0	''	'
23	O	44	0	IN	as
23	O	45	0	VBN	printed
23	O	46	0	IN	in
23	O	47	0	DT	the
23	MISC	48	0	NN	Dada/Almanach.jpegHugo/Ball/'s/Sound/Poem/`/Karawane
23	O	49	0	''	'
23	O	50	0	NN	1Source
23	O	51	0	:	:
23	O	52	0	VB	Copy
23	O	53	0	IN	in
23	O	54	0	DT	the
23	ORGANIZATION	55	0	NNP	International/Dada/Archive
23	O	56	0	,	,
23	O	57	0	JJ	Special
23	O	58	0	NNS	Collections
23	O	59	0	,	,
23	ORGANIZATION	60	0	NNPS	University/of/Iowa/Libraries
23	O	61	0	:	;
23	O	62	0	NN	image
23	O	63	0	JJ	available
23	O	64	0	IN	at
23	O	65	0	NNS	http://guity-novin.blogspot.ca/2011/08/chapter-44-dadaism-meeting-point-of-all.htmlBalls
23	O	66	0	CD	two
23	O	67	0	NNS	novels
23	O	68	0	RB	also
23	O	69	0	VBP	stem
23	O	70	0	IN	from
23	O	71	0	PRP$	his
23	PERSON	72	0	NN	Dada
23	O	73	0	NN	period
23	O	74	0	.	.

24	PERSON	0	0	NN	Flametti
24	O	1	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
24	O	2	0	CD	1918
24	O	3	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
24	O	4	0	VBZ	is
24	O	5	0	DT	the
24	O	6	0	NN	story
24	O	7	0	IN	of
24	O	8	0	DT	a
24	O	9	0	RB	mildly
24	O	10	0	JJ	disreputable
24	O	11	0	NN	group
24	O	12	0	IN	of
24	O	13	0	NN	cabaret
24	O	14	0	NNS	performers
24	O	15	0	RB	not
24	O	16	0	IN	unlike
24	O	17	0	DT	the
24	O	18	0	NNS	members
24	O	19	0	IN	of
24	O	20	0	DT	the
24	ORGANIZATION	21	0	NNP	Cabaret/Voltaire
24	O	22	0	CC	and
24	O	23	0	PRP$	its
24	O	24	0	NN	predecessor
24	O	25	0	,	,
24	O	26	0	DT	the
24	ORGANIZATION	27	0	NNP	Maxim/Ensemble
24	O	28	0	.	.

25	O	0	0	DT	The
25	O	1	0	RB	posthumously
25	O	2	0	VBN	published
25	PERSON	3	0	NNP	Tenderenda/der/Phantast
25	O	4	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
25	PERSON	5	0	NNP	Tenderenda
25	O	6	0	DT	the
25	LOCATION	7	0	NNP	Fantast
25	O	8	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
25	O	9	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
25	O	10	0	CD	1967
25	O	11	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
25	O	12	0	VBZ	is
25	O	13	0	DT	a
25	O	14	0	JJ	fanciful
25	O	15	0	,	,
25	O	16	0	JJ	allegorical
25	O	17	0	NN	reworking
25	O	18	0	IN	of
25	PERSON	19	0	NNP	Ball
25	O	20	0	POS	's
25	O	21	0	NNS	experiences
25	O	22	0	IN	from
25	O	23	0	CD	1914
25	O	24	0	TO	to
25	O	25	0	CD	1920
25	O	26	0	:	;
25	O	27	0	``	`
25	PERSON	28	0	NN	Dada
25	O	29	0	''	'
25	O	30	0	VBZ	appears
25	O	31	0	IN	as
25	O	32	0	DT	a
25	O	33	0	NN	character
25	O	34	0	IN	in
25	O	35	0	DT	the
25	O	36	0	JJ	novel
25	O	37	0	,	,
25	O	38	0	WDT	which
25	O	39	0	VBZ	incorporates
25	O	40	0	DT	some
25	O	41	0	IN	of
25	O	42	0	DT	the
25	O	43	0	JJ	sound
25	O	44	0	NNS	poems
25	O	45	0	.	.

26	O	0	0	RB	Also
26	O	1	0	VBN	performed
26	O	2	0	IN	at
26	O	3	0	DT	the
26	ORGANIZATION	4	0	NNP	Cabaret/Voltaire
26	O	5	0	VBD	were
26	O	6	0	DT	the
26	O	7	0	JJ	bitter
26	O	8	0	,	,
26	O	9	0	JJ	ironic
26	O	10	0	JJ	anti-war
26	O	11	0	NN	poem
26	O	12	0	``	`
26	O	13	0	NNP	Totentanz
26	O	14	0	CD	1916
26	O	15	0	''	'
26	O	16	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
26	O	17	0	``	`
26	ORGANIZATION	18	0	NNP	Dance/of/Death
26	O	19	0	POS	'
26	O	20	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
26	O	21	0	CC	and
26	O	22	0	DT	the
26	O	23	0	JJ	short
26	O	24	0	JJ	theatrical
26	O	25	0	NN	sketch
26	LOCATION	26	0	NNP	Ein/Krippenspiel
26	O	27	0	:	:
26	PERSON	28	0	NNP	Bruitistisch
26	O	29	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
26	O	30	0	NNP	A
26	ORGANIZATION	31	0	NNP	Bruitist/Nativity/Play
26	O	32	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
26	O	33	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
26	O	34	0	CD	1986
26	O	35	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
26	O	36	0	:	;
26	O	37	0	DT	the
26	O	38	0	JJ	latter
26	O	39	0	VBZ	is
26	O	40	0	DT	an
26	O	41	0	JJ	eclectic
26	O	42	0	NN	hybrid
26	O	43	0	IN	of
26	O	44	0	DT	a
26	O	45	0	JJ	sound
26	O	46	0	NN	poem
26	O	47	0	CC	and
26	O	48	0	DT	a
26	MISC	49	0	NNP	Christmas
26	O	50	0	NN	play
26	O	51	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
26	O	52	0	VBN	premiered
26	O	53	0	IN	in
26	O	54	0	NNP	June
26	O	55	0	CD	1916
26	O	56	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
26	O	57	0	.	.

27	O	0	0	RB	Partly
27	O	1	0	JJ	due
27	O	2	0	TO	to
27	O	3	0	NN	exhaustion
27	O	4	0	IN	from
27	O	5	0	DT	the
27	O	6	0	NN	intensity
27	O	7	0	IN	of
27	O	8	0	DT	the
27	O	9	0	NN	activity
27	O	10	0	,	,
27	O	11	0	CC	and
27	O	12	0	RB	partly
27	O	13	0	IN	because
27	O	14	0	IN	of
27	O	15	0	NNS	disagreements
27	O	16	0	IN	with
27	PERSON	17	0	NNP	Tzara
27	O	18	0	,	,
27	PERSON	19	0	NNP	Ball
27	O	20	0	VBD	severed
27	O	21	0	PRP$	his
27	O	22	0	NNS	ties
27	O	23	0	IN	with
27	PERSON	24	0	NN	Dada
27	O	25	0	IN	in
27	O	26	0	NNP	May
27	O	27	0	CD	1917
27	O	28	0	.	.

28	O	0	0	EX	There
28	O	1	0	VBD	followed
28	O	2	0	DT	a
28	O	3	0	JJ	three-year
28	O	4	0	NN	period
28	O	5	0	IN	of
28	O	6	0	JJ	journalistic
28	O	7	0	NN	work
28	O	8	0	,	,
28	O	9	0	VBG	writing
28	O	10	0	NNS	articles
28	O	11	0	RB	chiefly
28	O	12	0	IN	for
28	O	13	0	DT	the
28	O	14	0	JJ	centre-left
28	O	15	0	NN	newspaper
28	O	16	0	VBP	Die
28	O	17	0	NN	freie
28	O	18	0	NNP	Zeitung
28	O	19	0	:	;
28	O	20	0	JJ	many
28	O	21	0	IN	of
28	O	22	0	DT	these
28	O	23	0	NNS	articles
28	O	24	0	VBP	have
28	O	25	0	VBN	been
28	O	26	0	VBN	collected
28	O	27	0	IN	in
28	LOCATION	28	0	NNP	Der/Knstler
28	O	29	0	VBD	und
28	O	30	0	VB	die
28	O	31	0	NN	Zeitkrankheit
28	O	32	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
28	O	33	0	CD	1984
28	O	34	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
28	O	35	0	.	.

29	O	0	0	IN	In
29	O	1	0	CD	1920
29	O	2	0	,	,
29	PERSON	3	0	NNP	Ball
29	O	4	0	CC	and
29	PERSON	5	0	NNP	Hennings
29	O	6	0	VBN	married
29	O	7	0	CC	and
29	O	8	0	VBN	moved
29	O	9	0	IN	with
29	PERSON	10	0	NNP	Hennings
29	O	11	0	POS	's
29	O	12	0	NN	daughter
29	O	13	0	TO	to
29	PERSON	14	0	NNP	Agnuzzo
29	O	15	0	,	,
29	O	16	0	NNP	Ticino.Zur
29	PERSON	17	0	NNP	Kritik
29	O	18	0	FW	der
29	O	19	0	FW	deutschen
29	PERSON	20	0	NNP	Intelligenz
29	O	21	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
29	O	22	0	NNP	Critique
29	O	23	0	IN	of
29	O	24	0	DT	the
29	ORGANIZATION	25	0	NN	German/Intelligentsia
29	O	26	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
29	O	27	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
29	O	28	0	CD	1919
29	O	29	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
29	O	30	0	VBZ	is
29	O	31	0	DT	a
29	O	32	0	JJ	transitional
29	O	33	0	NN	work
29	O	34	0	IN	in
29	O	35	0	WDT	which
29	PERSON	36	0	NNP	Ball
29	O	37	0	NNS	traces
29	LOCATION	38	0	NNP	Germany
29	O	39	0	POS	's
29	O	40	0	JJ	militaristic
29	O	41	0	NN	culture
29	O	42	0	RB	back
29	O	43	0	TO	to
29	LOCATION	44	0	NNP	Luther
29	O	45	0	CC	and
29	O	46	0	VBZ	proposes
29	O	47	0	IN	that
29	MISC	48	0	JJ	Russian
29	O	49	0	NN	anarchism
29	O	50	0	CC	and
29	O	51	0	DT	the
29	MISC	52	0	NN	French/Revolution
29	O	53	0	MD	should
29	O	54	0	VB	serve
29	O	55	0	IN	as
29	O	56	0	NNS	models
29	O	57	0	IN	for
29	O	58	0	DT	a
29	O	59	0	JJ	post-war
29	O	60	0	NN	culture
29	O	61	0	.	.

30	O	0	0	PRP$	His
30	O	1	0	CD	1924
30	O	2	0	NN	revision
30	O	3	0	IN	of
30	O	4	0	DT	the
30	O	5	0	NN	work
30	O	6	0	IN	as
30	ORGANIZATION	7	0	NN	Die/Folgen/der/Reformation
30	O	8	0	VBZ	eliminates
30	O	9	0	DT	the
30	O	10	0	NN	emphasis
30	O	11	0	IN	on
30	O	12	0	NN	revolution
30	O	13	0	CC	and
30	O	14	0	NN	anarchism
30	O	15	0	CC	and
30	O	16	0	VBZ	brings
30	O	17	0	PRP	it
30	O	18	0	IN	into
30	O	19	0	NN	conformity
30	O	20	0	IN	with
30	O	21	0	JJ	conventional
30	MISC	22	0	JJ	Catholic
30	O	23	0	NNS	teachings
30	O	24	0	.	.

31	O	0	0	RB	Nevertheless
31	O	1	0	,	,
31	O	2	0	PRP$	his
31	O	3	0	JJ	religious
31	O	4	0	NNS	writings
31	O	5	0	VBD	were
31	O	6	0	RB	not
31	O	7	0	RB	particularly
31	O	8	0	JJ	well-received
31	O	9	0	IN	by
31	O	10	0	DT	the
31	O	11	0	NNP	Church
31	O	12	0	NNP	authorities.Ball
31	O	13	0	POS	's
31	O	14	0	NN	return
31	O	15	0	TO	to
31	MISC	16	0	NNP	Catholicism
31	O	17	0	VBD	was
31	O	18	0	VBN	marked
31	O	19	0	IN	by
31	O	20	0	DT	a
31	O	21	0	JJ	strong
31	O	22	0	VBG	leaning
31	O	23	0	IN	toward
31	O	24	0	NN	mysticism
31	O	25	0	CC	and
31	O	26	0	NN	asceticism
31	O	27	0	.	.

32	O	0	0	PRP$	His
32	O	1	0	JJ	own
32	O	2	0	JJ	secluded
32	O	3	0	NN	life-style
32	O	4	0	IN	in
32	LOCATION	5	0	NNP	Agnuzzo
32	O	6	0	IN	after
32	O	7	0	CD	1920
32	O	8	0	VBZ	is
32	O	9	0	VBN	reflected
32	O	10	0	IN	in
32	O	11	0	PRP$	his
32	O	12	0	NN	biography
32	O	13	0	IN	of
32	O	14	0	CD	three
32	O	15	0	IN	of
32	O	16	0	DT	the
32	O	17	0	JJ	early
32	ORGANIZATION	18	0	NNS	Orthodox/Desert/Fathers
32	O	19	0	,	,
32	PERSON	20	0	NNP	Byzantinisches/Christentum
32	O	21	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
32	O	22	0	CD	1923
32	O	23	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
32	O	24	0	.	.

33	O	0	0	NNP	Ball
33	O	1	0	CC	and
33	PERSON	2	0	NNP	Hennings
33	O	3	0	VBD	developed
33	O	4	0	DT	a
33	O	5	0	JJ	close
33	O	6	0	NN	friendship
33	O	7	0	IN	with
33	PERSON	8	0	NNP	Hermann/Hesse
33	O	9	0	,	,
33	O	10	0	WP	who
33	O	11	0	VBD	lived
33	O	12	0	RB	nearby
33	O	13	0	:	;
33	PERSON	14	0	NNP	Ball
33	O	15	0	POS	's
33	PERSON	16	0	NNP	Hermann/Hesse
33	O	17	0	:	:
33	PERSON	18	0	NNP	Sein/Leben
33	O	19	0	NN	und
33	O	20	0	NN	sein
33	PERSON	21	0	NN	Werk
33	O	22	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
33	O	23	0	CD	1927
33	O	24	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
33	O	25	0	VBD	was
33	O	26	0	DT	the
33	O	27	0	JJ	first
33	O	28	0	VBN	published
33	O	29	0	NN	biography
33	O	30	0	IN	of
33	O	31	0	DT	that
33	O	32	0	NNP	writer.Although
33	PERSON	33	0	NNP	Ball
33	O	34	0	POS	's
33	O	35	0	VBN	edited
33	O	36	0	NN	diary
33	PERSON	37	0	NNP	Die/Flucht
33	O	38	0	NN	aus
33	O	39	0	VBD	der
33	O	40	0	NNP	Zeit
33	O	41	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
33	MISC	42	0	NNP	Flight/Out/of/Time
33	O	43	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
33	O	44	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
33	O	45	0	CD	1927
33	O	46	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
33	O	47	0	VBZ	is
33	O	48	0	VBN	considered
33	O	49	0	CD	one
33	O	50	0	IN	of
33	O	51	0	DT	the
33	O	52	0	NN	source
33	O	53	0	NNS	documents
33	O	54	0	IN	of
33	LOCATION	55	0	NNP	Zurich/Dada
33	O	56	0	,	,
33	O	57	0	VBG	offering
33	O	58	0	JJ	first-hand
33	O	59	0	NNS	accounts
33	O	60	0	IN	of
33	O	61	0	JJ	many
33	O	62	0	IN	of
33	O	63	0	DT	the
33	O	64	0	JJ	key
33	O	65	0	NNS	events
33	O	66	0	IN	of
33	O	67	0	DT	the
33	O	68	0	JJ	initial
33	O	69	0	NN	phase
33	O	70	0	IN	of
33	O	71	0	DT	the
33	O	72	0	NN	movement
33	O	73	0	,	,
33	O	74	0	PRP	it
33	O	75	0	VBZ	is
33	O	76	0	JJ	uncertain
33	O	77	0	WRB	how
33	O	78	0	JJ	reliable
33	O	79	0	DT	this
33	O	80	0	NN	account
33	O	81	0	VBZ	is
33	O	82	0	,	,
33	O	83	0	IN	since
33	O	84	0	DT	the
33	O	85	0	NN	book
33	O	86	0	VBZ	constitutes
33	O	87	0	DT	the
33	O	88	0	NN	author
33	O	89	0	POS	's
33	O	90	0	NN	interpretation
33	O	91	0	IN	of
33	O	92	0	PRP$	his
33	O	93	0	NN	life
33	O	94	0	IN	from
33	O	95	0	DT	the
33	O	96	0	NN	standpoint
33	O	97	0	IN	of
33	O	98	0	PRP$	his
33	O	99	0	JJ	religious
33	O	100	0	NN	conversion
33	O	101	0	.	.

34	O	0	0	RB	Unfortunately
34	O	1	0	,	,
34	O	2	0	DT	the
34	O	3	0	JJ	original
34	O	4	0	NNS	diaries
34	O	5	0	IN	on
34	O	6	0	WDT	which
34	O	7	0	DT	the
34	O	8	0	NN	book
34	O	9	0	VBZ	is
34	O	10	0	VBN	based
34	O	11	0	VBP	have
34	O	12	0	RB	not
34	O	13	0	VBN	survived
34	O	14	0	.	.

35	PERSON	0	0	NNP	Hugo/Ball
35	O	1	0	VBD	died
35	O	2	0	IN	on
35	O	3	0	CD	14
35	O	4	0	NNP	December
35	O	5	0	CD	1927
35	O	6	0	IN	in
35	PERSON	7	0	NNP	Sant
35	O	8	0	POS	'
35	PERSON	9	0	NNP	Abbondio
35	O	10	0	,	,
35	O	11	0	NNP	Ticino.List
35	O	12	0	IN	of
35	ORGANIZATION	13	0	NNP	WorksFlametti
35	O	14	0	,	,
35	O	15	0	NN	oder
35	O	16	0	,	,
35	PERSON	17	0	NNP	Vom/Dandysmus/der/Armen
35	O	18	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
35	O	19	0	CD	1918
35	O	20	0	,	,
35	PERSON	21	0	NNP	Flametti
35	O	22	0	,	,
35	O	23	0	CC	or
35	O	24	0	,	,
35	ORGANIZATION	25	0	NNP	The/Dandyism/of/the/Poor
35	O	26	0	,	,
35	O	27	0	CD	2014
35	O	28	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
35	PERSON	29	0	NNP	Tenderenda/der/Phantast
35	O	30	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
35	O	31	0	CD	1967
35	O	32	0	,	,
35	PERSON	33	0	NNP	Ball
35	O	34	0	CC	and
35	O	35	0	NNP	Hammer
35	O	36	0	:	:
35	PERSON	37	0	NNP	Hugo/Ball
35	O	38	0	POS	's
35	PERSON	39	0	NNP	Tenderenda
35	O	40	0	DT	the
35	LOCATION	41	0	NNP	Fantast
35	O	42	0	,	,
35	O	43	0	CD	2002
35	O	44	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
35	PERSON	45	0	NNP	Zur/Kritik
35	O	46	0	FW	der
35	O	47	0	FW	deutschen
35	PERSON	48	0	NNP	Intelligenz
35	O	49	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
35	O	50	0	CD	1919
35	O	51	0	,	,
35	O	52	0	NN	Critique
35	O	53	0	IN	of
35	O	54	0	DT	the
35	ORGANIZATION	55	0	NNP	German/Intelligentsia
35	O	56	0	,	,
35	O	57	0	CD	1993
35	O	58	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
35	O	59	0	VBP	Die
35	O	60	0	NNP	Flucht
35	O	61	0	NN	aus
35	O	62	0	FW	der
35	O	63	0	FW	Zeit
35	O	64	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
35	O	65	0	CD	1927
35	O	66	0	,	,
35	O	67	0	NNP	Flight
35	O	68	0	IN	out
35	O	69	0	IN	of
35	O	70	0	NNP	Time
35	O	71	0	:	:
35	O	72	0	NNP	A
35	ORGANIZATION	73	0	NNP	Dada/Diary
35	O	74	0	,	,
35	O	75	0	CD	1996
35	O	76	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
35	ORGANIZATION	77	0	NNP	Smtliche/Werke
35	O	78	0	VBD	und
35	PERSON	79	0	NNP	Briefe
35	O	80	0	,	,
35	O	81	0	CD	2003
35	O	82	0	:	-
35	O	83	0	.	.

36	O	0	0	CD	Ten
36	O	1	0	NNS	volumes
36	O	2	0	VBN	planned
36	O	3	0	.	.

0	ORGANIZATION	0	0	NNS	Ballets/Russes
0	O	1	0	-LRB-	-LSB-
0	O	2	0	VB	Enter
0	O	3	0	DT	any
0	O	4	0	JJ	variant
0	O	5	0	NNS	forms
0	O	6	0	IN	of
0	O	7	0	PRP$	your
0	O	8	0	NN	headword
0	O	9	0	:	--
0	O	10	0	NN	OPTIONAL
0	O	11	0	-RRB-	-RSB-
0	O	12	0	VBN	Founded
0	O	13	0	IN	by
0	O	14	0	DT	the
0	MISC	15	0	JJ	Russian
0	O	16	0	NN	impressario
0	PERSON	17	0	NNP	Sergei/Diaghilev
0	O	18	0	IN	in
0	O	19	0	CD	1909
0	O	20	0	,	,
0	O	21	0	DT	the
0	PERSON	22	0	NNPS	Ballets/Russes
0	O	23	0	VBD	played
0	O	24	0	DT	a
0	O	25	0	NN	role
0	O	26	0	IN	of
0	O	27	0	JJ	fundamental
0	O	28	0	NN	importance
0	O	29	0	IN	in
0	O	30	0	DT	the
0	O	31	0	NN	development
0	O	32	0	IN	of
0	O	33	0	JJ	early
0	O	34	0	JJ	20th-century
0	O	35	0	NN	modernism
0	O	36	0	.	.

1	O	0	0	IN	In
1	O	1	0	DT	the
1	O	2	0	NN	course
1	O	3	0	IN	of
1	O	4	0	PRP$	its
1	O	5	0	CD	twenty
1	O	6	0	NN	year
1	O	7	0	NN	history
1	O	8	0	,	,
1	PERSON	9	0	NNP	Diaghilev
1	O	10	0	VBD	employed
1	O	11	0	DT	the
1	O	12	0	RBS	most
1	O	13	0	JJ	exciting
1	O	14	0	CC	and
1	O	15	0	RB	forward
1	O	16	0	VBG	thinking
1	O	17	0	NNS	artists
1	O	18	0	,	,
1	O	19	0	NNS	composers
1	O	20	0	CC	and
1	O	21	0	NNS	choregraphers
1	O	22	0	IN	of
1	O	23	0	DT	the
1	O	24	0	NN	time
1	O	25	0	TO	to
1	O	26	0	VB	create
1	O	27	0	IN	over
1	O	28	0	CD	100
1	O	29	0	NNS	ballets
1	O	30	0	WDT	which
1	O	31	0	RB	not
1	O	32	0	RB	only
1	O	33	0	VBD	revolutionized
1	O	34	0	DT	the
1	O	35	0	NN	language
1	O	36	0	IN	of
1	O	37	0	NN	dance
1	O	38	0	CC	and
1	O	39	0	VBD	reformulated
1	O	40	0	DT	the
1	O	41	0	NN	role
1	O	42	0	IN	of
1	O	43	0	DT	the
1	O	44	0	VBG	performing
1	O	45	0	NNS	arts
1	O	46	0	IN	by
1	O	47	0	VBP	bring
1	O	48	0	NN	modernism
1	O	49	0	IN	onto
1	O	50	0	DT	the
1	O	51	0	NN	stage
1	O	52	0	CC	but
1	O	53	0	RB	also
1	O	54	0	VBD	charted
1	O	55	0	DT	a
1	O	56	0	JJ	new
1	O	57	0	NN	step
1	O	58	0	RB	forward
1	O	59	0	IN	in
1	O	60	0	JJ	inter-disciplinary
1	O	61	0	NN	creation
1	O	62	0	,	,
1	O	63	0	VBG	using
1	O	64	0	DT	the
1	O	65	0	NN	medium
1	O	66	0	IN	of
1	O	67	0	JJ	ballet
1	O	68	0	TO	to
1	O	69	0	VB	bring
1	O	70	0	TO	to
1	O	71	0	NN	fruition
1	PERSON	72	0	NNP	Richard/Wagner
1	O	73	0	POS	's
1	O	74	0	NN	concept
1	O	75	0	IN	of
1	O	76	0	DT	the
1	O	77	0	NNP	Gesamtkunstwerk
1	O	78	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
1	O	79	0	``	`
1	O	80	0	JJ	total
1	O	81	0	NN	art
1	O	82	0	NN	work
1	O	83	0	''	'
1	O	84	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
1	O	85	0	.	.

2	O	0	0	VBN	Founded
2	O	1	0	IN	by
2	O	2	0	DT	the
2	MISC	3	0	JJ	Russian
2	O	4	0	NN	impressario
2	PERSON	5	0	NNP	Sergei/Diaghilev
2	O	6	0	IN	in
2	O	7	0	CD	1909
2	O	8	0	,	,
2	O	9	0	DT	the
2	MISC	10	0	NNPS	Ballets/Russes
2	O	11	0	VBD	played
2	O	12	0	DT	a
2	O	13	0	NN	role
2	O	14	0	IN	of
2	O	15	0	JJ	fundamental
2	O	16	0	NN	importance
2	O	17	0	IN	in
2	O	18	0	DT	the
2	O	19	0	NN	development
2	O	20	0	IN	of
2	O	21	0	JJ	early
2	O	22	0	JJ	20th-century
2	O	23	0	NN	modernism
2	O	24	0	.	.

3	O	0	0	IN	In
3	O	1	0	DT	the
3	O	2	0	NN	course
3	O	3	0	IN	of
3	O	4	0	PRP$	its
3	O	5	0	CD	twenty
3	O	6	0	NN	year
3	O	7	0	NN	history
3	O	8	0	,	,
3	PERSON	9	0	NNP	Diaghilev
3	O	10	0	VBD	employed
3	O	11	0	DT	the
3	O	12	0	RBS	most
3	O	13	0	JJ	exciting
3	O	14	0	CC	and
3	O	15	0	RB	forward
3	O	16	0	VBG	thinking
3	O	17	0	NNS	artists
3	O	18	0	,	,
3	O	19	0	NNS	composers
3	O	20	0	CC	and
3	O	21	0	NNS	choregraphers
3	O	22	0	IN	of
3	O	23	0	DT	the
3	O	24	0	NN	time
3	O	25	0	TO	to
3	O	26	0	VB	create
3	O	27	0	IN	over
3	O	28	0	CD	100
3	O	29	0	NNS	ballets
3	O	30	0	WDT	which
3	O	31	0	RB	not
3	O	32	0	RB	only
3	O	33	0	VBD	revolutionized
3	O	34	0	DT	the
3	O	35	0	NN	language
3	O	36	0	IN	of
3	O	37	0	NN	dance
3	O	38	0	CC	and
3	O	39	0	VBD	reformulated
3	O	40	0	DT	the
3	O	41	0	NN	role
3	O	42	0	IN	of
3	O	43	0	DT	the
3	O	44	0	VBG	performing
3	O	45	0	NNS	arts
3	O	46	0	IN	by
3	O	47	0	VBP	bring
3	O	48	0	NN	modernism
3	O	49	0	IN	onto
3	O	50	0	DT	the
3	O	51	0	NN	stage
3	O	52	0	CC	but
3	O	53	0	RB	also
3	O	54	0	VBD	charted
3	O	55	0	DT	a
3	O	56	0	JJ	new
3	O	57	0	NN	step
3	O	58	0	RB	forward
3	O	59	0	IN	in
3	O	60	0	JJ	inter-disciplinary
3	O	61	0	NN	creation
3	O	62	0	,	,
3	O	63	0	VBG	using
3	O	64	0	DT	the
3	O	65	0	NN	medium
3	O	66	0	IN	of
3	O	67	0	JJ	ballet
3	O	68	0	TO	to
3	O	69	0	VB	bring
3	O	70	0	TO	to
3	O	71	0	NN	fruition
3	PERSON	72	0	NNP	Richard/Wagner
3	O	73	0	POS	's
3	O	74	0	NN	concept
3	O	75	0	IN	of
3	O	76	0	DT	the
3	O	77	0	NNP	Gesamtkunstwerk
3	O	78	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
3	O	79	0	``	`
3	O	80	0	JJ	total
3	O	81	0	NN	art
3	O	82	0	NN	work
3	O	83	0	''	'
3	O	84	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
3	O	85	0	.	.

4	O	0	0	IN	Despite
4	O	1	0	DT	the
4	O	2	0	NN	emergence
4	O	3	0	IN	of
4	O	4	0	JJ	rival
4	O	5	0	NNS	enterprises
4	O	6	0	IN	in
4	O	7	0	DT	the
4	O	8	0	CD	1920s
4	O	9	0	,	,
4	O	10	0	JJ	such
4	O	11	0	IN	as
4	PERSON	12	0	NNP	Rolf/de/Mar
4	O	13	0	POS	's
4	PERSON	14	0	NNP	Ballets/Sudois
4	O	15	0	,	,
4	O	16	0	DT	the
4	MISC	17	0	NNPS	Ballets/Russes
4	O	18	0	VBD	remained
4	O	19	0	DT	the
4	O	20	0	JJ	pre-eminent
4	O	21	0	NN	exponent
4	O	22	0	IN	of
4	O	23	0	NN	stage
4	O	24	0	NN	modernism
4	O	25	0	IN	until
4	PERSON	26	0	NNP	Diaghilev
4	O	27	0	POS	's
4	O	28	0	NN	death
4	O	29	0	IN	in
4	LOCATION	30	0	NNP	Venice
4	O	31	0	IN	in
4	O	32	0	CD	1929
4	O	33	0	,	,
4	O	34	0	WRB	when
4	O	35	0	DT	the
4	O	36	0	NN	company
4	O	37	0	VBD	broke
4	O	38	0	RP	up
4	O	39	0	.	.

5	O	0	0	RB	Subsequently
5	O	1	0	,	,
5	O	2	0	IN	in
5	O	3	0	DT	the
5	O	4	0	JJ	early
5	O	5	0	NNS	1930s
5	O	6	0	,	,
5	O	7	0	DT	the
5	O	8	0	NN	company
5	O	9	0	VBD	was
5	O	10	0	,	,
5	O	11	0	TO	to
5	O	12	0	DT	some
5	O	13	0	NN	extent
5	O	14	0	,	,
5	O	15	0	VBN	reassembled
5	O	16	0	IN	under
5	O	17	0	DT	the
5	O	18	0	NN	aegis
5	O	19	0	IN	of
5	ORGANIZATION	20	0	NNP	Colonel/de/Basil
5	O	21	0	CC	but
5	O	22	0	DT	the
5	O	23	0	NNS	productions
5	O	24	0	IN	of
5	O	25	0	DT	this
5	O	26	0	NN	period
5	O	27	0	RB	never
5	O	28	0	RB	completely
5	O	29	0	VBD	matched
5	O	30	0	DT	the
5	O	31	0	JJ	artistic
5	O	32	0	NN	innovation
5	O	33	0	VBN	achieved
5	O	34	0	IN	by
5	PERSON	35	0	NNP	Diaghilev
5	O	36	0	CC	and
5	O	37	0	PRP$	his
5	O	38	0	NNS	collaborators
5	O	39	0	IN	in
5	O	40	0	JJ	former
5	PERSON	41	0	NNP	years.Sergei/Diaghilev
5	O	42	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
5	O	43	0	CD	1872-1929
5	O	44	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
5	O	45	0	VBD	was
5	O	46	0	RB	not
5	O	47	0	PRP	himself
5	O	48	0	DT	an
5	O	49	0	NN	artist
5	O	50	0	,	,
5	O	51	0	NN	choreographer
5	O	52	0	,	,
5	O	53	0	CC	or
5	O	54	0	NN	composer
5	O	55	0	CC	but
5	O	56	0	RB	rather
5	O	57	0	DT	an
5	O	58	0	NN	intellectual
5	O	59	0	WP	who
5	O	60	0	VBD	had
5	O	61	0	DT	a
5	O	62	0	NN	gift
5	O	63	0	IN	for
5	O	64	0	VBG	identifying
5	O	65	0	CC	and
5	O	66	0	VBG	promoting
5	O	67	0	DT	the
5	O	68	0	RB	very
5	O	69	0	JJS	latest
5	O	70	0	JJ	artistic
5	O	71	0	NN	talent
5	O	72	0	WRB	wherever
5	O	73	0	CC	and
5	O	74	0	IN	in
5	O	75	0	WDT	whatever
5	O	76	0	NN	form
5	O	77	0	PRP	he
5	O	78	0	VBD	found
5	O	79	0	PRP	it
5	O	80	0	.	.

6	O	0	0	PRP	He
6	O	1	0	VBD	came
6	O	2	0	TO	to
6	O	3	0	DT	the
6	O	4	0	NN	world
6	O	5	0	IN	of
6	O	6	0	JJ	ballet
6	O	7	0	IN	with
6	O	8	0	DT	an
6	O	9	0	JJ	established
6	O	10	0	NN	reputation
6	O	11	0	IN	as
6	O	12	0	CD	one
6	O	13	0	IN	of
6	O	14	0	DT	the
6	O	15	0	VBG	leading
6	O	16	0	NNS	members
6	O	17	0	IN	of
6	O	18	0	DT	the
6	LOCATION	19	0	NNP	St./Petersburg
6	O	20	0	NN	intelligentsia
6	O	21	0	.	.

7	O	0	0	IN	In
7	O	1	0	CD	1898
7	O	2	0	PRP	he
7	O	3	0	VBD	had
7	O	4	0	VBN	been
7	O	5	0	DT	the
7	O	6	0	NN	leader
7	O	7	0	IN	of
7	O	8	0	NNS	Mir
7	O	9	0	NN	iskusstva
7	O	10	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
7	O	11	0	DT	The
7	MISC	12	0	NNP	World/of/Art
7	O	13	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
7	O	14	0	,	,
7	O	15	0	DT	a
7	O	16	0	NN	group
7	O	17	0	IN	of
7	O	18	0	JJ	young
7	O	19	0	NNS	intellectuals
7	O	20	0	VBG	comprising
7	O	21	0	NNS	artists
7	O	22	0	,	,
7	O	23	0	NNS	writers
7	O	24	0	CC	and
7	O	25	0	NNS	philosophers
7	O	26	0	.	.

8	O	0	0	IN	For
8	O	1	0	CD	six
8	O	2	0	NN	year
8	O	3	0	PRP	he
8	O	4	0	VBD	had
8	O	5	0	VBN	published
8	O	6	0	DT	the
8	O	7	0	NN	journal
8	O	8	0	IN	of
8	O	9	0	DT	the
8	O	10	0	NN	group
8	O	11	0	CC	and
8	O	12	0	VBD	had
8	O	13	0	VBN	organised
8	O	14	0	NNS	exhibitions
8	O	15	0	IN	of
8	O	16	0	PRP$	its
8	O	17	0	NN	artist
8	O	18	0	NNS	members
8	O	19	0	.	.

9	O	0	0	IN	In
9	O	1	0	CD	1906
9	O	2	0	PRP	he
9	O	3	0	VBD	curated
9	O	4	0	DT	an
9	O	5	0	JJ	enormous
9	O	6	0	NN	exhibition
9	O	7	0	IN	of
9	MISC	8	0	JJ	Russian
9	O	9	0	NN	art
9	O	10	0	IN	in
9	O	11	0	DT	the
9	O	12	0	NN	context
9	O	13	0	IN	of
9	O	14	0	DT	the
9	LOCATION	15	0	NNP	Salon
9	O	16	0	NNP	dAutomne
9	O	17	0	IN	in
9	LOCATION	18	0	NNP	Paris
9	O	19	0	CC	and
9	O	20	0	IN	in
9	O	21	0	CD	1907
9	O	22	0	CC	and
9	O	23	0	CD	1908
9	O	24	0	VBD	tried
9	O	25	0	PRP$	his
9	O	26	0	NN	hand
9	O	27	0	IN	at
9	O	28	0	NN	staging
9	MISC	29	0	JJ	Russian
9	O	30	0	NN	opera
9	O	31	0	NN	season
9	O	32	0	IN	in
9	O	33	0	DT	the
9	MISC	34	0	JJ	French
9	O	35	0	NN	capital
9	O	36	0	.	.

10	O	0	0	DT	A
10	O	1	0	NN	year
10	O	2	0	RB	later
10	O	3	0	PRP	he
10	O	4	0	VBD	founded
10	O	5	0	DT	the
10	ORGANIZATION	6	0	NNPS	Ballets/Russes
10	O	7	0	IN	with
10	O	8	0	DT	the
10	O	9	0	NN	aim
10	O	10	0	IN	of
10	O	11	0	VBG	promoting
10	MISC	12	0	JJ	Russian
10	O	13	0	NN	art
10	O	14	0	CC	and
10	O	15	0	NN	culture
10	O	16	0	RB	abroad
10	O	17	0	,	,
10	O	18	0	RB	hence
10	O	19	0	DT	the
10	ORGANIZATION	20	0	NNPS	Ballets/Russes
10	O	21	0	RB	never
10	O	22	0	VBN	performed
10	O	23	0	IN	in
10	LOCATION	24	0	NNP	Russia
10	O	25	0	CC	but
10	O	26	0	RB	only
10	O	27	0	IN	in
10	LOCATION	28	0	NNP	Western/Europe
10	O	29	0	CC	and
10	O	30	0	DT	the
10	ORGANIZATION	31	0	NNPS	Americas
10	O	32	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
10	PERSON	33	0	NNP	De/Basil
10	O	34	0	POS	's
10	PERSON	35	0	NNPS	Ballets/Russes
10	O	36	0	VBD	toured
10	O	37	0	TO	to
10	LOCATION	38	0	NNP	Australia
10	O	39	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
10	O	40	0	.	.

11	O	0	0	NNP	Central
11	O	1	0	TO	to
11	PERSON	2	0	NNP	Diaghilev
11	O	3	0	POS	's
11	O	4	0	JJ	aesthetic
11	O	5	0	NN	ideology
11	O	6	0	VBD	was
11	O	7	0	DT	the
11	O	8	0	NN	idea
11	O	9	0	IN	of
11	O	10	0	VBG	using
11	O	11	0	DT	the
11	O	12	0	JJ	ballet
11	O	13	0	IN	as
11	O	14	0	DT	a
11	O	15	0	JJ	serious
11	O	16	0	NNS	means
11	O	17	0	IN	of
11	O	18	0	JJ	artistic
11	O	19	0	NN	expression
11	O	20	0	CC	and
11	O	21	0	IN	of
11	O	22	0	VBG	fusing
11	O	23	0	DT	the
11	O	24	0	NNS	arts
11	O	25	0	TO	to
11	O	26	0	VB	create
11	O	27	0	DT	a
11	ORGANIZATION	28	0	NNP	Gesamtkunstwerk
11	O	29	0	.	.

12	O	0	0	IN	For
12	O	1	0	DT	this
12	O	2	0	NN	reason
12	O	3	0	,	,
12	O	4	0	PRP	he
12	O	5	0	VBD	demanded
12	O	6	0	DT	the
12	O	7	0	JJS	closest
12	O	8	0	NN	cooperation
12	O	9	0	IN	between
12	O	10	0	PRP$	his
12	O	11	0	NNS	collaborators
12	O	12	0	,	,
12	O	13	0	IN	with
12	O	14	0	PRP	himself
12	O	15	0	IN	as
12	O	16	0	JJ	final
12	O	17	0	NN	arbiter
12	O	18	0	,	,
12	O	19	0	IN	in
12	O	20	0	NN	order
12	O	21	0	TO	to
12	O	22	0	VB	achieve
12	O	23	0	DT	the
12	O	24	0	RBS	most
12	O	25	0	JJ	powerful
12	O	26	0	,	,
12	O	27	0	JJ	multi-sensory
12	O	28	0	NN	expression
12	O	29	0	IN	of
12	O	30	0	DT	the
12	O	31	0	``	`
12	O	32	0	NN	idea
12	O	33	0	''	'
12	O	34	0	WDT	that
12	O	35	0	VBD	lay
12	O	36	0	IN	behind
12	O	37	0	DT	each
12	O	38	0	JJ	ballet
12	O	39	0	.	.

13	O	0	0	DT	The
13	O	1	0	NN	success
13	O	2	0	IN	of
13	O	3	0	PRP$	his
13	O	4	0	NN	enterprise
13	O	5	0	VBD	was
13	O	6	0	JJ	immediate
13	O	7	0	.	.

14	O	0	0	DT	The
14	MISC	1	0	NNPS	Ballets/Russes
14	O	2	0	VBD	charmed
14	O	3	0	PRP$	its
14	O	4	0	NNS	audiences
14	O	5	0	IN	from
14	O	6	0	DT	the
14	O	7	0	NN	start
14	O	8	0	CC	but
14	O	9	0	RB	also
14	O	10	0	,	,
14	O	11	0	IN	on
14	O	12	0	NN	occasion
14	O	13	0	,	,
14	O	14	0	VBD	scandalized
14	O	15	0	PRP	them
14	O	16	0	IN	with
14	O	17	0	PRP$	its
14	O	18	0	NN	novelty
14	O	19	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
14	O	20	0	DT	a
14	O	21	0	NN	riot
14	O	22	0	VBD	took
14	O	23	0	NN	place
14	O	24	0	IN	at
14	O	25	0	DT	the
14	O	26	0	JJ	first
14	O	27	0	NN	performance
14	O	28	0	IN	of
14	ORGANIZATION	29	0	NNP	Le
14	O	30	0	NNP	sacre
14	O	31	0	NNP	du
14	O	32	0	NNS	printemps
14	O	33	0	IN	in
14	O	34	0	CD	1913
14	O	35	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
14	O	36	0	.	.

15	O	0	0	DT	The
15	O	1	0	NN	development
15	O	2	0	IN	of
15	O	3	0	DT	the
15	ORGANIZATION	4	0	NNPS	Ballets/Russes
15	O	5	0	MD	may
15	O	6	0	VB	be
15	O	7	0	VBN	divided
15	O	8	0	IN	into
15	O	9	0	CD	three
15	O	10	0	JJ	distinct
15	O	11	0	NNS	phases
15	O	12	0	.	.

16	O	0	0	IN	In
16	O	1	0	DT	the
16	O	2	0	JJ	early
16	O	3	0	NN	period
16	O	4	0	IN	from
16	O	5	0	CD	1909-13
16	O	6	0	,	,
16	PERSON	7	0	NNP	Diaghilev
16	O	8	0	VBD	worked
16	O	9	0	RB	almost
16	O	10	0	RB	entirely
16	O	11	0	IN	with
16	MISC	12	0	JJ	Russian
16	O	13	0	NNS	collaborators
16	O	14	0	:	:
16	PERSON	15	0	NNP	Mikhail/Fokine
16	O	16	0	CC	and
16	LOCATION	17	0	NNP	Vaslav/Nijinsky
16	O	18	0	VBD	were
16	O	19	0	VBN	employed
16	O	20	0	IN	as
16	O	21	0	DT	the
16	O	22	0	NNS	choreographers
16	O	23	0	:	;
16	O	24	0	JJ	old
16	O	25	0	NNS	friends
16	O	26	0	IN	from
16	O	27	0	DT	the
16	MISC	28	0	NNS	Mir
16	O	29	0	NN	iskusstva
16	O	30	0	NN	group
16	O	31	0	,	,
16	O	32	0	JJ	such
16	O	33	0	IN	as
16	PERSON	34	0	NNP	Lev/Bakst
16	O	35	0	,	,
16	PERSON	36	0	NNP	Alexandre/Benois
16	O	37	0	,	,
16	PERSON	38	0	NNP	Alexander/Golovin
16	O	39	0	CC	and
16	PERSON	40	0	NNP	Nikolai/Riurikh
16	O	41	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
16	LOCATION	42	0	NNP	Roerich
16	O	43	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
16	O	44	0	,	,
16	O	45	0	VBD	were
16	O	46	0	VBN	commissioned
16	O	47	0	IN	as
16	O	48	0	NNS	designers
16	O	49	0	CC	and
16	O	50	0	,	,
16	O	51	0	JJ	other
16	O	52	0	IN	than
16	O	53	0	DT	the
16	O	54	0	NN	use
16	O	55	0	IN	of
16	PERSON	56	0	NNP	Claude/Debussy
16	O	57	0	POS	's
16	O	58	0	NN	score
16	O	59	0	IN	for
16	MISC	60	0	NN	Laprs-midi/dun
16	O	61	0	NN	faune
16	O	62	0	CC	and
16	PERSON	63	0	NNP	Ravel
16	O	64	0	POS	's
16	PERSON	65	0	NNP	Daphnis
16	O	66	0	FW	et
16	PERSON	67	0	NNP	Chloe
16	O	68	0	,	,
16	O	69	0	DT	the
16	O	70	0	NNS	ballets
16	O	71	0	VBD	were
16	O	72	0	VBN	set
16	O	73	0	TO	to
16	O	74	0	VBG	existing
16	O	75	0	JJ	musical
16	O	76	0	NNS	texts
16	O	77	0	IN	by
16	MISC	78	0	JJ	Russian
16	O	79	0	NNS	composers
16	O	80	0	JJ	such
16	O	81	0	IN	as
16	PERSON	82	0	NNP	Nikolai/Rimsky-Korsakov
16	O	83	0	,	,
16	PERSON	84	0	NNP	Alexander/Borodin
16	O	85	0	CC	and
16	PERSON	86	0	NNP	Petr/Tchaikovsky
16	O	87	0	.	.

17	O	0	0	IN	In
17	O	1	0	CD	1910
17	O	2	0	,	,
17	O	3	0	RB	however
17	O	4	0	,	,
17	PERSON	5	0	NNP	Diaghilev
17	O	6	0	VBD	began
17	O	7	0	TO	to
17	O	8	0	VB	work
17	O	9	0	RB	closely
17	O	10	0	IN	with
17	PERSON	11	0	NNP	Igor/Stravinsky
17	O	12	0	,	,
17	O	13	0	WP	who
17	O	14	0	VBD	became
17	O	15	0	DT	the
17	O	16	0	``	`
17	O	17	0	NN	house
17	O	18	0	NN	composer
17	O	19	0	''	'
17	O	20	0	CC	and
17	O	21	0	VBD	introduced
17	O	22	0	DT	a
17	O	23	0	JJ	new
17	O	24	0	NN	strain
17	O	25	0	IN	of
17	O	26	0	JJ	musical
17	O	27	0	NN	modernism
17	O	28	0	IN	into
17	O	29	0	DT	the
17	LOCATION	30	0	NNPS	Ballets/Russes
17	O	31	0	IN	with
17	O	32	0	PRP$	his
17	O	33	0	NNP	Loiseau
17	O	34	0	IN	de
17	O	35	0	FW	feu
17	O	36	0	.	.

18	O	0	0	DT	This
18	O	1	0	NN	period
18	O	2	0	VBD	marked
18	O	3	0	DT	a
18	O	4	0	NN	transition
18	O	5	0	IN	from
18	O	6	0	``	`
18	O	7	0	JJ	classical
18	O	8	0	''	'
18	O	9	0	VBZ	ballets
18	O	10	0	JJ	familiar
18	O	11	0	TO	to
18	O	12	0	DT	the
18	O	13	0	NN	audience
18	O	14	0	,	,
18	O	15	0	JJ	such
18	O	16	0	IN	as
18	ORGANIZATION	17	0	NNP	Les/Sylphides
18	O	18	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
18	O	19	0	CD	1909
18	O	20	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
18	O	21	0	CC	and
18	PERSON	22	0	NNP	Lac/des/Cygnes
18	O	23	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
18	O	24	0	CD	1911
18	O	25	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
18	O	26	0	,	,
18	O	27	0	TO	to
18	O	28	0	JJ	sumptuous
18	O	29	0	JJ	new
18	O	30	0	NNS	creations
18	O	31	0	,	,
18	O	32	0	JJ	such
18	O	33	0	IN	as
18	PERSON	34	0	NN	Schhrezade
18	O	35	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
18	O	36	0	CD	1910
18	O	37	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
18	O	38	0	CC	and
18	PERSON	39	0	NN	Laprs-midi/dun
18	O	40	0	NN	faune
18	O	41	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
18	O	42	0	CD	1911
18	O	43	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
18	O	44	0	,	,
18	O	45	0	DT	both
18	O	46	0	VBN	designed
18	O	47	0	IN	by
18	PERSON	48	0	NNP	Bakst
18	O	49	0	.	.

19	O	0	0	DT	These
19	O	1	0	NNS	ballets
19	O	2	0	VBD	gave
19	O	3	0	NN	way
19	O	4	0	TO	to
19	O	5	0	RBR	more
19	O	6	0	JJ	exploratory
19	O	7	0	NN	work
19	O	8	0	,	,
19	O	9	0	JJ	such
19	O	10	0	IN	as
19	ORGANIZATION	11	0	NNP	Le
19	O	12	0	NNP	sacre
19	O	13	0	NNP	du
19	O	14	0	NNS	printemps
19	O	15	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
19	O	16	0	CD	1913
19	O	17	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
19	O	18	0	,	,
19	O	19	0	WDT	which
19	O	20	0	VBD	shocked
19	O	21	0	DT	the
19	O	22	0	NN	audience
19	O	23	0	IN	through
19	O	24	0	DT	the
19	O	25	0	``	`
19	O	26	0	JJ	primitive
19	O	27	0	''	'
19	O	28	0	NN	modernism
19	O	29	0	IN	of
19	PERSON	30	0	NNP	Stravinsky
19	O	31	0	POS	's
19	O	32	0	NN	score
19	O	33	0	CC	and
19	O	34	0	DT	the
19	O	35	0	JJ	revolutionary
19	O	36	0	NN	choreography
19	O	37	0	VBN	designed
19	O	38	0	IN	by
19	O	39	0	NNP	Nijinsky.In
19	O	40	0	CD	1913
19	O	41	0	,	,
19	O	42	0	RB	however
19	O	43	0	,	,
19	PERSON	44	0	NNP	Diaghilev
19	O	45	0	VBD	undertook
19	O	46	0	DT	a
19	O	47	0	JJ	significant
19	O	48	0	NN	change
19	O	49	0	IN	in
19	O	50	0	NN	direction
19	O	51	0	WRB	when
19	O	52	0	PRP	he
19	O	53	0	VBD	employed
19	PERSON	54	0	NNP	Natalia/Goncharova
19	O	55	0	,	,
19	O	56	0	DT	a
19	MISC	57	0	JJ	Russian
19	O	58	0	JJ	modernist
19	O	59	0	NN	painter
19	O	60	0	,	,
19	O	61	0	TO	to
19	O	62	0	VB	make
19	O	63	0	DT	the
19	O	64	0	NNS	designs
19	O	65	0	IN	for
19	O	66	0	PRP$	his
19	O	67	0	NN	producion
19	O	68	0	IN	of
19	ORGANIZATION	69	0	NNP	Le
19	O	70	0	NN	coq
19	O	71	0	NN	dor
19	O	72	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
19	O	73	0	CD	1914
19	O	74	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
19	O	75	0	.	.

20	O	0	0	PRP$	Her
20	O	1	0	JJ	novel
20	O	2	0	CC	and
20	O	3	0	RB	brightly
20	O	4	0	VBN	coloured
20	O	5	0	NNS	designs
20	O	6	0	,	,
20	O	7	0	VBN	executed
20	O	8	0	IN	in
20	O	9	0	DT	the
20	O	10	0	NN	style
20	O	11	0	IN	of
20	LOCATION	12	0	NN	NEO-PRIMITIVISM
20	O	13	0	,	,
20	O	14	0	VBD	excited
20	O	15	0	DT	the
20	MISC	16	0	JJ	French
20	O	17	0	NN	audience
20	O	18	0	CC	and
20	O	19	0	JJ	convinced
20	PERSON	20	0	NNP	Diaghilev
20	O	21	0	IN	that
20	O	22	0	PRP	he
20	O	23	0	MD	should
20	O	24	0	RB	now
20	O	25	0	VB	priviledge
20	O	26	0	DT	the
20	O	27	0	NN	work
20	O	28	0	IN	of
20	O	29	0	JJ	modernist
20	O	30	0	NNS	painters
20	O	31	0	.	.

21	O	0	0	IN	During
21	O	1	0	DT	the
21	O	2	0	NN	war
21	O	3	0	NNS	years
21	O	4	0	CC	both
21	PERSON	5	0	NNP	Fokine
21	O	6	0	CC	and
21	LOCATION	7	0	NNP	Nijinsky
21	O	8	0	VBD	were
21	O	9	0	VBN	lost
21	O	10	0	TO	to
21	O	11	0	DT	the
21	O	12	0	NN	company
21	O	13	0	CC	and
21	O	14	0	DT	a
21	O	15	0	JJ	new
21	O	16	0	NN	choreographer
21	O	17	0	,	,
21	PERSON	18	0	NNP	Leonid/Massine
21	O	19	0	,	,
21	O	20	0	VBD	was
21	O	21	0	VBN	appointed
21	O	22	0	.	.

22	PERSON	0	0	NNP	Massine
22	O	1	0	VBD	worked
22	O	2	0	RB	closely
22	O	3	0	IN	with
22	O	4	0	DT	the
22	O	5	0	JJ	artistic
22	O	6	0	JJ	avant-garde
22	O	7	0	WP	whom
22	PERSON	8	0	NNP	Diaghilev
22	O	9	0	RB	now
22	O	10	0	RB	increasingly
22	O	11	0	VBN	employed
22	O	12	0	,	,
22	O	13	0	RB	so
22	O	14	0	RB	much
22	O	15	0	IN	so
22	O	16	0	IN	that
22	O	17	0	DT	the
22	O	18	0	NN	independence
22	O	19	0	IN	of
22	O	20	0	DT	the
22	O	21	0	NN	choreography
22	O	22	0	VBD	was
22	O	23	0	VBN	threatened
22	O	24	0	IN	by
22	O	25	0	DT	the
22	O	26	0	NN	novelty
22	O	27	0	IN	of
22	O	28	0	DT	the
22	O	29	0	NN	staging
22	O	30	0	IN	that
22	O	31	0	DT	the
22	O	32	0	NNS	artists
22	O	33	0	VBN	proposed
22	O	34	0	.	.

23	PERSON	0	0	NNP	Mikhail/Larionov
23	O	1	0	POS	's
23	O	2	0	JJ	cumbersome
23	O	3	0	NNS	costumes
23	O	4	0	IN	for
23	PERSON	5	0	NNP	Soleil
23	O	6	0	IN	de
23	O	7	0	NN	nuit
23	O	8	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	9	0	CD	1915
23	O	10	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	O	11	0	CC	and
23	PERSON	12	0	NNP	Picasso
23	O	13	0	POS	's
23	MISC	14	0	JJ	Cubist
23	O	15	0	NN	style
23	O	16	0	NNS	costumes
23	O	17	0	IN	for
23	O	18	0	NN	Parade
23	O	19	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
23	O	20	0	CD	1917
23	O	21	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
23	O	22	0	CC	both
23	O	23	0	RB	significantly
23	O	24	0	VBN	impacted
23	O	25	0	IN	upon
23	O	26	0	CC	and
23	O	27	0	JJ	restricted
23	O	28	0	DT	the
23	O	29	0	JJ	choreographic
23	O	30	0	NN	expression
23	O	31	0	IN	of
23	O	32	0	DT	the
23	O	33	0	NNS	ballets
23	O	34	0	.	.

24	O	0	0	JJS	Most
24	O	1	0	NN	radical
24	O	2	0	IN	of
24	O	3	0	DT	all
24	O	4	0	,	,
24	O	5	0	RB	however
24	O	6	0	,	,
24	O	7	0	VBD	was
24	PERSON	8	0	NNP	Giacomo/Balla
24	O	9	0	POS	's
24	O	10	0	NNS	designs
24	O	11	0	IN	for
24	PERSON	12	0	NNP	Stravinsky
24	O	13	0	POS	's
24	O	14	0	NNP	Feu
24	O	15	0	NNP	dArtifice
24	O	16	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
24	O	17	0	CD	1917
24	O	18	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
24	O	19	0	,	,
24	O	20	0	IN	in
24	O	21	0	WDT	which
24	O	22	0	DT	the
24	O	23	0	NN	dancer
24	O	24	0	VBD	was
24	O	25	0	VBN	banished
24	O	26	0	IN	from
24	O	27	0	DT	the
24	O	28	0	NN	stage
24	O	29	0	NN	alltogether
24	O	30	0	CC	and
24	O	31	0	DT	the
24	O	32	0	NN	action
24	O	33	0	VBD	was
24	O	34	0	VBN	interpreted
24	O	35	0	IN	by
24	O	36	0	DT	the
24	O	37	0	NN	play
24	O	38	0	IN	of
24	O	39	0	NN	light
24	O	40	0	IN	over
24	O	41	0	VBN	painted
24	O	42	0	NN	canvas
24	O	43	0	NNS	shapes
24	O	44	0	VBD	dispersed
24	O	45	0	IN	on
24	O	46	0	DT	the
24	O	47	0	NN	stage
24	O	48	0	.	.

25	O	0	0	DT	This
25	O	1	0	VBD	represented
25	O	2	0	DT	the
25	O	3	0	RBS	most
25	O	4	0	JJ	experimental
25	O	5	0	NN	period
25	O	6	0	IN	for
25	O	7	0	DT	the
25	ORGANIZATION	8	0	NNPS	Ballets/Russes
25	O	9	0	CC	and
25	O	10	0	RB	only
25	O	11	0	RB	really
25	O	12	0	VBD	came
25	O	13	0	TO	to
25	O	14	0	DT	an
25	O	15	0	NN	end
25	O	16	0	IN	in
25	O	17	0	CD	1921
25	O	18	0	IN	with
25	O	19	0	DT	the
25	O	20	0	NN	staging
25	O	21	0	IN	of
25	LOCATION	22	0	NNP	Chout
25	O	23	0	,	,
25	O	24	0	DT	a
25	O	25	0	JJ	ballet-pantomime
25	O	26	0	IN	with
25	O	27	0	JJ	outlandish
25	O	28	0	NNS	costumes
25	O	29	0	IN	by
25	PERSON	30	0	NNP	Larionov
25	O	31	0	CC	and
25	O	32	0	DT	a
25	O	33	0	JJ	cacophanous
25	O	34	0	NN	score
25	O	35	0	IN	by
25	PERSON	36	0	NNP	Prokofiev
25	O	37	0	,	,
25	O	38	0	WDT	which
25	O	39	0	VBD	proved
25	O	40	0	DT	a
25	O	41	0	JJ	critical
25	O	42	0	NN	disaster
25	O	43	0	CC	and
25	O	44	0	RB	nearly
25	O	45	0	VBD	ruined
25	O	46	0	DT	the
25	O	47	0	NN	company.The
25	O	48	0	NN	introduction
25	O	49	0	IN	of
25	LOCATION	50	0	NNP	Bronislava/Nijinska
25	O	51	0	IN	as
25	O	52	0	``	`
25	O	53	0	NN	house
25	O	54	0	NN	choreographer
25	O	55	0	''	'
25	O	56	0	,	,
25	O	57	0	WP	who
25	O	58	0	VBD	was
25	O	59	0	VBN	followed
25	O	60	0	IN	by
25	PERSON	61	0	NNP	George/Balanchine
25	O	62	0	CC	and
25	O	63	0	,	,
25	O	64	0	RB	finally
25	O	65	0	,	,
25	PERSON	66	0	NNP	Serge/Lifar
25	O	67	0	,	,
25	O	68	0	VBD	did
25	O	69	0	RB	much
25	O	70	0	TO	to
25	O	71	0	VB	restablish
25	O	72	0	DT	a
25	O	73	0	RBR	more
25	O	74	0	JJ	correct
25	O	75	0	NN	balance
25	O	76	0	IN	of
25	O	77	0	NNS	parts
25	O	78	0	CC	and
25	O	79	0	DT	the
25	O	80	0	CD	1920s
25	O	81	0	VBD	witnessed
25	O	82	0	DT	a
25	O	83	0	JJ	golden
25	O	84	0	NN	period
25	O	85	0	IN	for
25	O	86	0	DT	the
25	ORGANIZATION	87	0	NNPS	Ballets/Russes
25	O	88	0	.	.

26	O	0	0	DT	The
26	O	1	0	JJ	post-war
26	O	2	0	NN	trend
26	O	3	0	IN	for
26	MISC	4	0	NN	Neo-classicism
26	O	5	0	VBN	found
26	O	6	0	NN	expression
26	O	7	0	IN	in
26	PERSON	8	0	NNP	Picasso
26	O	9	0	POS	's
26	O	10	0	CC	and
26	PERSON	11	0	NNP	Stravinsky
26	O	12	0	POS	's
26	PERSON	13	0	NNP	Pulcinella
26	O	14	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
26	O	15	0	CD	1920
26	O	16	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
26	O	17	0	CC	and
26	O	18	0	IN	in
26	PERSON	19	0	NNP	Goncharova
26	O	20	0	POS	's
26	O	21	0	CC	and
26	PERSON	22	0	NNP	Stravinsky
26	O	23	0	POS	's
26	ORGANIZATION	24	0	NNP	Les
26	O	25	0	NNS	noces
26	O	26	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
26	O	27	0	CD	1923
26	O	28	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
26	O	29	0	IN	whilst
26	O	30	0	RB	even
26	MISC	31	0	NNP	Surrealism
26	O	32	0	VBD	was
26	O	33	0	VBN	given
26	O	34	0	DT	an
26	O	35	0	NN	airing
26	O	36	0	IN	in
26	LOCATION	37	0	NNP	Max/Ernst
26	O	38	0	POS	's
26	O	39	0	CC	and
26	PERSON	40	0	NNP	Joan/Mir
26	O	41	0	POS	's
26	O	42	0	NN	design
26	O	43	0	IN	for
26	PERSON	44	0	NNP	Romeo
26	O	45	0	CC	and
26	PERSON	46	0	NNP	Juliette
26	O	47	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
26	O	48	0	CD	1926
26	O	49	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
26	O	50	0	CC	and
26	PERSON	51	0	NNP	De/Chirico
26	O	52	0	POS	's
26	PERSON	53	0	NNP	Le
26	O	54	0	NN	bal
26	O	55	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
26	O	56	0	CD	1929
26	O	57	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
26	O	58	0	.	.

27	PERSON	0	0	NNP	Diaghilev
27	O	1	0	POS	's
27	O	2	0	NN	success
27	O	3	0	,	,
27	O	4	0	RB	however
27	O	5	0	,	,
27	O	6	0	VBD	was
27	O	7	0	TO	to
27	O	8	0	VB	maintain
27	O	9	0	DT	a
27	O	10	0	NN	balance
27	O	11	0	IN	between
27	O	12	0	DT	the
27	O	13	0	JJ	high-brow
27	O	14	0	CC	and
27	O	15	0	DT	the
27	O	16	0	JJ	popular
27	O	17	0	CC	and
27	O	18	0	JJ	many
27	O	19	0	DT	a
27	O	20	0	JJ	contemporary
27	O	21	0	NN	theme
27	O	22	0	CC	or
27	O	23	0	NN	issue
27	O	24	0	VBD	found
27	O	25	0	PRP	itself
27	O	26	0	VBD	addressed
27	O	27	0	,	,
27	O	28	0	VBD	celebrated
27	O	29	0	CC	or
27	O	30	0	VBD	mocked
27	O	31	0	IN	on
27	O	32	0	NN	stage
27	O	33	0	.	.

28	PERSON	0	0	NNP	Marie/Laurencin
28	O	1	0	POS	's
28	O	2	0	NNS	designs
28	O	3	0	IN	for
28	PERSON	4	0	NNP	Francis/Poulenc
28	O	5	0	POS	's
28	ORGANIZATION	6	0	NNP	Les
28	O	7	0	NNS	biches
28	O	8	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
28	O	9	0	CD	1924
28	O	10	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
28	O	11	0	,	,
28	O	12	0	DT	a
28	O	13	0	JJ	satyrical
28	O	14	0	JJ	ballet
28	O	15	0	IN	about
28	O	16	0	DT	a
28	O	17	0	``	`
28	O	18	0	NN	house-party
28	O	19	0	''	'
28	O	20	0	,	,
28	PERSON	21	0	NNP	Picasso
28	O	22	0	NNS	designs
28	O	23	0	CC	and
28	PERSON	24	0	NNP	Chanel
28	O	25	0	POS	's
28	O	26	0	NNS	costumes
28	O	27	0	IN	for
28	PERSON	28	0	NNP	Darius/Milhaud
28	O	29	0	POS	's
28	ORGANIZATION	30	0	NNP	Le
28	O	31	0	NN	train
28	O	32	0	NN	bleu
28	O	33	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
28	O	34	0	CD	1924
28	O	35	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
28	O	36	0	CC	and
28	PERSON	37	0	NNP	Yakulov
28	O	38	0	POS	's
28	O	39	0	NNS	designs
28	O	40	0	IN	for
28	PERSON	41	0	NNP	Prokofiev
28	O	42	0	POS	's
28	O	43	0	JJ	musical
28	O	44	0	NN	reflection
28	O	45	0	IN	on
28	O	46	0	DT	the
28	LOCATION	47	0	NNP	Soviet/Union/Le
28	O	48	0	VBZ	pas
28	O	49	0	JJR	dacier
28	O	50	0	-LRB-	-LRB-
28	O	51	0	CD	1927
28	O	52	0	-RRB-	-RRB-
28	O	53	0	VBP	are
28	O	54	0	NN	typical.On
28	O	55	0	PRP$	his
28	O	56	0	NN	death
28	O	57	0	IN	in
28	O	58	0	CD	1929
28	O	59	0	DT	the
28	MISC	60	0	NNP	Diaghilev/`/Revolution
28	O	61	0	''	'
28	O	62	0	VBD	was
28	O	63	0	JJ	complete
28	O	64	0	:	:
28	O	65	0	PRP	he
28	O	66	0	VBD	had
28	O	67	0	VBN	transformed
28	O	68	0	DT	the
28	O	69	0	NN	medium
28	O	70	0	IN	of
28	O	71	0	JJ	ballet
28	O	72	0	IN	into
28	O	73	0	DT	a
28	O	74	0	JJ	serious
28	O	75	0	NN	form
28	O	76	0	IN	of
28	O	77	0	JJ	artistic
28	O	78	0	NN	expression
28	O	79	0	CC	and
28	O	80	0	IN	in
28	O	81	0	RB	so
28	O	82	0	VBG	doing
28	O	83	0	VBD	had
28	O	84	0	VBN	demonstrated
28	O	85	0	DT	the
28	O	86	0	NN	viability
28	O	87	0	IN	of
28	O	88	0	NN	modernism
28	O	89	0	IN	as
28	O	90	0	DT	a
28	O	91	0	JJ	significant
28	O	92	0	NN	force
28	O	93	0	IN	in
28	O	94	0	DT	the
28	O	95	0	VBG	peforming
28	O	96	0	NNS	arts
28	O	97	0	.	.
